<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/community/</guid>
      <description>Ⅰ - Community #  When you think engineer, what traits come to mind? If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like most people, you probably thought &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;antisocial&amp;rdquo;. While I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to how truthful that stereotype may be, I can tell you for sure that in engineering, not knowing how to make friends, ask for help, and talk with others will make you all but useless.
The only way to be successful in this journey is to make friends along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Culture Problem in Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/wtfarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/wtfarch/</guid>
      <description>The Background #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to jump straight to the point, after my last post, somebody saw the Arch install guide on OpGuides and decided they didn&amp;rsquo;t like it, and so opened a PR deleting the file:
Now, this story could have ended here. I could have closed the issue and moved on with my life, but as a real &amp;ldquo;I use Arch BTW&amp;rdquo; user since 2014 I&amp;rsquo;m just not okay with this attitude in the community, so&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meta-er-verse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/metaverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/metaverse/</guid>
      <description>.me{background-color: #333!important; }Plots of land &amp;amp; Euclidean space #  One of the bigger points of the metaverse is the idea of owning a slice of digital property. This is a weird mix of the scarcity and value from real life property and the domain name (like myfancyname.com) market. It also makes no god damn sense in this context, and is really just artificially putting limitations into a system for the sake of making yet another crypto currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offline</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/offline/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion &amp; Doublethink</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/religiondoublethink/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/religiondoublethink/</guid>
      <description>From time to time, I get asked about my religion. Sometimes, &amp;ldquo;asked&amp;rdquo; is putting it lightly, like when my SO&amp;rsquo;s father asked if I believe in a God, but made it very clear there was only one right answer if I wanted to date my SO. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m asked with honest curiosity, as when people find out I grew up in a mixture of Wicca and Christianity, people wonder how that works, and what I came out believing in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/someconsumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/someconsumerism/</guid>
      <description>I bitch about consumerism a lot, yet, I like things. So that&amp;rsquo;s what this post is about. Things. Things I&amp;rsquo;ve bought over the last few years and what things fall into &amp;ldquo;OhMyGod This is Life Changing&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A Bit of a Mixed Bag&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How Did You Fuck This Up?&amp;rdquo;. Because I know not everyone cares about all these products, I&amp;rsquo;m going to skip right to the juicy bit- the thinking about what lessons come from this thinking:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Bandwidth Images</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lowbandwidthimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lowbandwidthimages/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a website that you want to make use less bandwidth. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re paying by the byte for content delivery, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re worried about the environment, either way, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you want to make your images as small as possible. The obvious place to start is just shrinking your images. Here, this is a 4032x2268 .jpg shrunk down to a 1008x567 .jpg - 25% of the original quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I pay to go to college?</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/whydidipay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/whydidipay/</guid>
      <description>Post originally published March 22 of 2021, date above represents most recent edit The Nebraska Union at UNL, photo by ensign_beedrill, CC BY-SA 2.0, via Wikimedia Commons I am currently a student at the University of Nebraska - Lincoln, where I study Computer and Electrical Engineering as a dual major. I have a serious passion for both of these subjects, which is why I am so incredibly frustrated at how negative my experience at UNL has been, especially in the classes that directly relate to my major.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not a Digital Native, and Neither Are You</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/digital-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/digital-native/</guid>
      <description>The term digital native describes a young person who has grown up in the digital age, in close contact with computers, the Internet, and video game consoles, and later mobile phones, social media, and tablets. The term is often used to refer to millennials, Generation Z, and Generation Alpha; the latter two are sometimes described as distinct &amp;ldquo;neo-digital natives&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; digital natives, or &amp;ldquo;digital integrators&amp;rdquo;.  &amp;lsquo;Digital Native&amp;rsquo; on Wikipedia You know how every headline about Millennials or Gen Z is &amp;ldquo;Gen ___ has killed ___&amp;rdquo; and it makes everyone from those generations want collectively bang their heads into a desk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nebraksa LR107 - Stupdity Abound</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</guid>
      <description>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT RESOLVED BY THE MEMBERS OF THE ONE HUNDRED SEVENTH LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA, FIRST SESSION:
 That we hereby reaffirm our solemn oaths of office by expressing a firm resolution to maintain and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Nebraska against every act of aggression whether foreign or domestic, including every act of unconstitutional abuse of power arising from the state or federal government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ternary Logic</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</guid>
      <description>This paper was written for CSCE-430, Computer Architecture at University Of Nebraska - Lincoln in Spring of 2021.
This in-page view isn&amp;rsquo;t all that great, so feel free to download the pdf directly.
If you would like to read the refrenced papers, I reccomend using Sci-Hub with a VPN on, as the academic publishers putting up paywalls as barriers to science can go fuck themselves.
  #the-canvas { border: 1px solid black; direction: ltr; width: 100%; height: auto; } #paginator{ text-align: center; margin-bottom: 10px; }  Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page:  /     window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Products I Wish Existed</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</guid>
      <description>Most of these things probably exist. For many, it&amp;rsquo;s just that they don&amp;rsquo;t exist at a practical price point.  Without further ado, In no particular order
  A not garbage, not phone based, IR camera that doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost a bajillion dollars
Yes. I know the FLIR and SEEK Thermal cameras are a thing, but both have their share of software problems or hardware incompatibilities. Most of all, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to hope that their app keeps working with my phone at risk of a $250 paper weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chains</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/chains/</guid>
      <description>My name is Vega. I have to tell myself that a lot, reminding myself of who I am.
I know that may sound weird, but, if it wen&amp;rsquo;t already obvious, it isn&amp;rsquo;t my legal name. (yet.)
Despite my best efforts, my parents still call me by my &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; name. I&amp;rsquo;m hesitant to call it a dead name, as I&amp;rsquo;m not trans. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s the same or that it&amp;rsquo;s fair to claim that it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirrors of Opal</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/mirrorsofopal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/mirrorsofopal/</guid>
      <description>When I looked into the mirror this morning, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure who I was looking at. Is that me? Is that really what I look like now? Has this years long separation from reality caused me to not recognize my own face, or would it have happened anyway- a side effect of growing older.
 If you saw me, would you even recognize me? Or am I the ship of Theseus, digested by the carnivore that we call time, now fertilizer for someone you&amp;rsquo;ve never met?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Make OpGuides</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/howimakeopguides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/howimakeopguides/</guid>
      <description>History #  Before I can get into how OpGuides works now, I need to provide some history so that you can learn from my mistakes.
The first iteration of OpGuides was OpinionatedEngineering.md. A single markdown file so long that the scroll bar was hard to grab. It was meant to be viewed and distributed not as a website, but as a file to be opened with https://typora.io (so that the html and everything rendered- though in theory any markdown editor would do)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time lapse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</guid>
      <description>Super brief post about one of the more fun projects I setup recently: a lil&#39; time lapse script
#!/bin/bash CAM=$(v4l2-ctl --list-devices | grep C920 -A 1 | grep /dev | awk &#39;{$1=$1};1&#39;) #Uncomment the next line to verify it&#39;s using the correct device #echo $CAM ffmpeg -f video4linux2 -s 1920x1080 -i $CAM -ss 0:0:2 -frames 1 &amp;quot;/mnt/data/lapse/tl$(date +&amp;quot;%Y-%m-%d_%H-%M-%S&amp;quot;).jpg&amp;quot; I have multiple cameras on my system, but only wanted output from the better one, the C920.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Down!</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</guid>
      <description>I use VCV Rack a lot. I normally use it on Windows as running VSTs in Linux is still a bit of a PITA and If I&amp;rsquo;m going to make music I want to have access to all of my tools. However, I still want to be able to use VCV on Linux for processing guitar when taking breaks from working on other things without having to reboot over to Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xx80</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</guid>
      <description>The year is 198x. #  I stare at my amber terminal. Hexadecimal fills my screen and my mind has become lost in the flow of 6502 assembly, as I hand optimize the code flow.
I&amp;rsquo;m interupted when I recieve a message from my friend, _Maverik, he&amp;rsquo;s excited about the ground breaking CGI in Tron.
 Nostalgia is a weird feeling. We can forget when things happened, and misttribute things to entirely different decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti Consumer</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</guid>
      <description>As I walked to my car after class I could smell the ashes of a cigarette and hear the echos of a train scraping on its tracks. The cool foggy air held still beams of light. It looked like a scene from Blade runner, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like the Android&amp;rsquo;s of it&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, lusting after something to make me feel alive.
The drive home was mentally taxing. The fog so dense that cars ahead seemed to be balls of light floating in the distance and keeping sight of the lines to stay in my lane took a constant effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</guid>
      <description>3D Modeling, Sculpting, Painting, Shading, and Rendering #  Art by TalonCreations This chapter will be using various programs, not all of which are free. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to recommend things that are open source if I can, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep the cost down as much as possible. You definitely can do everything in this chapter for free, just be aware that without some of the paid tools it may be substantially harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/analog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/analog/</guid>
      <description>Analog Art #  What makes it &amp;lsquo;analog&amp;rsquo; #  So, for OpGuides I&amp;rsquo;m going to refer to any non-digital art as analog. Traditionally, this art is called, well, traditional. I don&amp;rsquo;t like this term as it implies that there&amp;rsquo;s a right &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; way to do things, and that&amp;rsquo;s a load of shit. So, whenever I say analog, don&amp;rsquo;t think about it to much. I just mean not using software and a computer, or, if a computer is used, it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary for the end product, like 3D printing and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/dacadc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/dacadc/</guid>
      <description>Analog Art to Digital Art #  Scanning in your Analog Art #  [TODO] Scanner DPI, etc.
Background Removal #  Via vector art tools #  Before doing this, you should really know what vector art is and how it differs from the raster art you&amp;rsquo;re probably used to. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about this a bit in the previous chapter, Digital Art  .This process requires combining the two, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit odd if you haven&amp;rsquo;t use vector art tools before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/digital/</guid>
      <description>Digital Art #  Photo by cece kun The primary tool of the digital artist &amp;hellip; The pen? #  I want to give you a heads up that making digital art without a pen tablet or pen display of some sort is pretty awful. You can get a cheap pen tablet - they&amp;rsquo;re basically like a mousepad that you use a pen on - for ~$30. Or you can get a fancy pen display, where you draw directly on the screen, for about ~$300 (similar to the one in the picture above; however, one that large is probably much more expensive)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</guid>
      <description>Photography #  [TODO]
This Guy Flipped an Element in an Old Lens and Got ‘Magic’ Bokeh (PetaPixel)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/access/</guid>
      <description>Accessibility #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/content/</guid>
      <description>Content is King #  At the end of the day, you can make a cool looking fancy website, but you still have to have something to say, a story to tell, a tutorial, videos, something to play. something. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a print book, you can come back and edit it later. The important thing is to just make something.
It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be good at first, it just has to exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/cost/</guid>
      <description>Cost #  So, a pretty big question you should ask right away is &amp;ldquo;How much does this cost?&amp;rdquo;, and you probably already know the answer.
It depends.
First thing you should worry about is the cost of hosting, but, uhh, what is hosting?
Hosting? #  So, if you really want to you can run a web server off of your home internet connection. This has a few problem though:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/garden/</guid>
      <description>Your Own Garden #  So, I just said you&amp;rsquo;d need to learn a bunch to do this, so, why bother?
  Platforms like Facebook, Tumblr, etc. - Social Media - don&amp;rsquo;t let you really customize the look of your page
&amp;hellip; and they track you
&amp;hellip; and they make the experience bad for those without accounts
&amp;hellip; and they can limit your speech, ban your account, etc.
  Site builders (Squarespace, Wix, Wordpress, etc) tend to lead to cookie-cutter websites</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/jack/</guid>
      <description>Jack of All Trades #  You probably noticed the mildly ugly gradient heading this section, that was my warning to you that you&amp;rsquo;re about to walk into something that requires an interesting mixture of design and engineering skills. Making a good website requires a fair understanding of computers, some basic programming skills, and a willingness to dive into some technical topics. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason most blogging now happens on Medium or Tumblr and that social media has boomed: The barrier to entry is significantly lower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/</guid>
      <description>HTML, (S)CSS, JS&amp;hellip; WUT? #   document.getElementById(&#34;webMenu&#34;).open = true; The rise of WASM #  PHP needs to die. #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css/</guid>
      <description>CSS #   document.getElementById(&#34;webMenu&#34;).open = true;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/html/</guid>
      <description>HTML #   document.getElementById(&#34;webMenu&#34;).open = true; Alright, so HyperText Markup Language is the one thing on this list I suspect everyone has at least a smidgen of familiarity with, and it&amp;rsquo;s really very easy to work with, so let&amp;rsquo;s just dive in.
In general, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a bunch of html tags, tags are these point-bracketed enclosed words that mean something special to the browser, let&amp;rsquo;s actually make an html file right now to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/js/</guid>
      <description>JS #   document.getElementById(&#34;webMenu&#34;).open = true;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/resources/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources #  Blog Posts #  Only 90s Web Developers Remember This</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/setup/</guid>
      <description>Setting up everything you need to make a website #  [TODO] - include instructions for Github pages, a VPS, and self hosted but assume a Hugo site for all three. There&amp;rsquo;s gotta be limits in the complexity somewhere, and I draw the line at setting up everything for decent JS web app dev / PHP shit, cloud/AWS, etc. though I still want to link to external resources for those things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/static/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/static/</guid>
      <description>Static or Dynamic? #  The &amp;lsquo;Weight&amp;rsquo; of your website #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/thinkingweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/thinkingweb/</guid>
      <description>Thinking Web #  [TODO] Content can be presented in novel ways. Text as a last resort
[TODO] Because of browser differences, screen size, Fonts, JS support, etc you should check in other resolutions and browsers periodicaly
FAQs: why we don’t have them (gds.blog.gov.uk)
Every pricing page should have GIFs (Tony Dinh)
NoScript fallback
 Some Beautiful Websites For Inspiration: #   https://oxide.computer  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/tools/</guid>
      <description>Web Development Tools #  Code generation, libraries, etc.
HTML Helpers #  HTML Table Generator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/24-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/24-/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24 - #  This chapter has been merged with another, leaving the space open for now, I&amp;rsquo;ll put something else here&amp;hellip;
Maybe reverse engineering? This would seem a bit out of place though. I might need to do some rearranging of chapters 26-34 anyway https://github.com/mytechnotalent/Reverse-Engineering
If you&#39;re reading this, you have JavaScript off.
 document.querySelector(&#34;body  main  div  article  div  p&#34;).innerText = &#34;If you can read this you have JavaScript on&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/a3-bom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/a3-bom/</guid>
      <description>Appendix C - BOM #  As the guide isn&amp;rsquo;t anywhere near a usable state yet, this page should be ignored for the most part. OpGuides is free. Unfortunately all the tools and programs you&amp;rsquo;ll need to follow along aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily. While you probably could do everything in this guide without getting the things in this Bill OF Materials (BOM) it will massively help to have it.
I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to keep the cost as low as possible though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 22 - Intro to Angry Pixies #  A simple guide to electronic components (YouTube)
The Tools of the Trade #  Building, fixing, and analyzing circuitry requires the use of a few tools and appliances. While there are many more than those listed here, these tare the most important ones and should be all you need for most even very advanced applications.
The Multimeter #   note, the above video uses U=IR instead of V=IR like &amp;lsquo;normal&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits2/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 23 - Circuits &amp;amp; Semiconductors #  When I was a kid I thought about circuits as being alive, like Cells at Work!, only little electrons going around busily keeping the heart of my toy working instead of anthropomorphic red blood cells working in the human body.
Now, as an adult - and a computer and electrical engineer at that - I still find this thought endearing. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve now come to see the physics and art of electronics to be even more beautiful when their true nature is really understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/digitallogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/digitallogic/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24 - Digital Logic #     Binary (0b) Hex (0x) Decimal     0000 0 0   0001 1 1   0010 2 2   0011 3 3   0100 4 4   0101 5 5   0110 6 6   0111 6 7   1000 8 8   1001 9 9   1010 A 10   1011 B 11   1100 C 12   1101 D 13   1110 E 14   1111 F 15     lineart by https://merveilles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/embedded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/embedded/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 25 - Embedded Systems #   By Make It With Me What is an Embedded System? #  [TODO] need source  These little devices are Pocket Operators made by Teenage Engineering, they&amp;rsquo;re realatively inexpensive synths that can be chained together, and I think they&amp;rsquo;re a great example of what an embedded system is, but for the sake of clarity, here&amp;rsquo;s how wikipedia defines it:
 An embedded system is a computer system—a combination of a computer processor, computer memory, and input/output peripheral devices—that has a dedicated function within a larger mechanical or electronic system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/parts/</guid>
      <description>23½ - Parts #  When thinking about electronics, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to focus on the bits that electricity actually flows though. This chapter is for everything else
Knobs, Key-Caps #      Enclosures #  Adhesives #  Adapters #  + PCB footprint adapters, like SOP to DIP</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/pcb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/pcb/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 26 - Let&amp;rsquo;s make our own PCB #  [TODO]
 Make it work Make it not emit a ton of RF or go to shit when around it (everything is an antenna) Make it pretty  ref that weird russian autorouter as limits on this   Make it repairable Know when to do a PCB or a Perma-Proto Assuming parts will only be available for so long  First things first, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be using Kicad, so you&amp;rsquo;ll want to go grab that from the repos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/comparch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/comparch/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 36 - Let&amp;rsquo;s make our own CPU #  How To Make A CPU - A Simple Picture Based Explanation (RobertElder)
This Chapter will be split into three parts:Part 1, understanding the interval workings of a CPU. This is effectively just a computer architecture class, and will be by far the largest section.Part 2, making that CPU on an FPGA.Part 3, making that CPU do something. [TODO] http://www.lighterra.com/papers/modernmicroprocessors/
[TODO] A Density Metric for Semiconductor Technology - past nm for sizing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/compileassemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/compileassemble/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 33 - Compilers and Assemblers #  https://lee.earth/til/compiling-c-code-a-step-by-step-guide/
[TODO] Better Firmware with LLVM/Clang
[TODO] Zig cc: a Powerful Drop-In Replacement for GCC/Clang
Common Flags and When to Use them #   These flags are not universal, instead they&amp;rsquo;re from GCC. GCC and Clang are the big two compilers you&amp;rsquo;ll see a lot and these flags should be mostly the same between the two. Of course, there are many, many other compilers, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with the common stuff</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/fpga1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/fpga1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 35 - Let&amp;rsquo;s try out programmable logic #  Before we get started, please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve read Chapter 24 - Digital Logic  Simulation of an Intel 4004 in TICS (The Integrated Circuit Simulator) a (abandoned?) WIP by Oni, Download the interpreter here, the repo has pleanty of examples.
Something a bit less cool but similar is https://github.com/martinkirsche/wired-logic
 [TODO]
Finite State Machines, VHDL, Verilog, FPGA &amp;amp; CPLD internals</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/reverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/reverse/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 34 - Reverse Engineering #  Software #   Anyone know of good resources for learning binary reversing? Not particular tools necessarily, but like theory and how to think   @XMPPwocky on Twitter An Opinionated Guide on How To Reverse Engineer Software is decent.
for me personally:
know some assembly, and in particular make sure you know the calling conventions for your platform.
when starting out, do it on binaries you can actually run in a debugger and see what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening at runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/howtolearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/howtolearn/</guid>
      <description>Ⅱ - Learn how to learn #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep this short and sweet: Nobody learns (effectively) by being shown what to do. You can watch hundreds of hours of people playing guitar, even explaining how they do it, but you wont be able to randomly pick one up and play if you never have before. Furthermore, as much as you can learn from direct reading and instruction, it has it&amp;rsquo;s place and limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/arch/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 - Installing Arch Linux #  I am working on a new install guide located at
archnew  , though it is still a work in progress. The new guide is based on the offical install guide, among other pages from the wiki, and adds running commentry and advice in an attempt to help new users while still sticking to some of the Arch ethos.   Some Background #  Unlike Windows or Mac which are primarily differentiated by versions (Windows XP, Vista, 7, 10&amp;hellip;), Linux has two important things to look out for:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/archnew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/archnew/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 - Installing Arch Linux #   Some Background #  ⬤◯◯◯◯◯◯◯◯◯
Unlike Windows or Mac which are primarily differentiated by versions (Windows XP, Vista, 7, 10&amp;hellip;), Linux has two important things to look out for:
 The distribution name (Arch, Ubuntu, Mint, Debian, etc.) Kernel version number (5.15 last time this page was updated)  So, what do each of these mean?
Well, Linux is actually just the name of the underlying &amp;lsquo;core&amp;rsquo; of the system, known as the kernel, as such, there are literally thousands of Linux variations or &amp;lsquo;distributions&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/firstgoal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/firstgoal/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 - The first goal #  Art by @monoxromatik Every journey needs a place to start, and while many may like to start slow I think a head first approach is best. So that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we&amp;rsquo;re gonna do. The very first thing we&amp;rsquo;re going to do is install a new Operating System (OS)(1) on your computer. This is a pretty involved process. It will require you to Repartition(2) your drive, change settings in your BIOS or UEFI(3), and install a new Bootloader(4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/git/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5½ - Git. #   &amp;hellip; Despite the chapter name, git isn&amp;rsquo;t just a Linux thing - it&amp;rsquo;s actually more of a programming thing, but you&amp;rsquo;ll still probably want to use it for storing your configuration files for Linux, which is why it&amp;rsquo;s here.
 ./missing-semester - Version Control  The above link does a better job of covering the vast majority of what I&amp;rsquo;d say than I could hope to put here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3 - Into The Hardware #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  One of the nifty things about Linux is you don&amp;rsquo;t need to install extra software to check out the deeper parts of your hardware. While on windows you might need a tool like CPU-Z to look at information about the CPU on Linux you can do it out of the box. Even better, linux makes changing values and tweaking performance easier too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/architectures/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3½ - Architectures #  Instruction Set Architectures #  Today, there are two main computer architectures you&amp;rsquo;ll use x86_64 and ARM. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard this in passing, but you may not know what they are. These are Instruction Set Architectures (ISA), and they define the list of insturctions your computer can understand and the basics about how those insturctions are laid out.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a fictional computer, really old, that&amp;rsquo;s only 8-bit (most modern systems are 32 or 64bit) this would mean we get eight 1&amp;rsquo;s and 0&amp;rsquo;s to define our instruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/biggerpicture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/biggerpicture/</guid>
      <description>The Bigger Picture #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  The Storage Hierarchy: #  Registers→Cache→Memory→Disk &amp;amp; The role of interrupts #  Moving Data Vs Operating on Data #  mov is the majority of instructions
Generic = Slow #  Accelerators make modern systems useful
Abstractions are only usually good #  Useful for getting work done, a massive pain in the ass when the issue is down the stack</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/buying/</guid>
      <description>10 - How to Know What to Buy #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  I&amp;rsquo;ve tried writing this like 5 times, trying to work around the fucked up GPU market, I just can&amp;rsquo;t even show the process of finding parts when things are this messed up. I can&amp;rsquo;t reccomend a pre-built system either, since DELL is awful but so is everyone else. Fuck this. Unless you litterally don&amp;rsquo;t have a computer just don&amp;rsquo;t buy anything for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cooling/</guid>
      <description>8 - Cooling #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  Blower, air flow vs static pressure, fan size liquid, heat pipes, pwm vs DC control</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cpu/</guid>
      <description>1 - The CPU #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  Note, there&amp;rsquo;s more the a CPU on some of these boards. On the big one, only the square thing in the middle is the CPU, on the pi-0 (the board with the HDMI and USB Ports) the CPU is under the metal heatsink - and in truth the CPU is actually an SOC (System On a Chip) - more on that in a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/gpu/</guid>
      <description>4 - Graphics &amp;amp; Acceleration #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  Photo by Thomas Foster, depicting an Nvidia RTX 3070  Hi Gamers!
This page will obviously appeal to you, those that drive the sales of these chonky, expensive cards; however, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that this page is about all graphics &amp;amp; acceleration- from the iGPU in low power systems to the compute cards used for AI research and wasteful crypto mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/legacy/</guid>
      <description>#   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;   Legacy Hardware? There&amp;rsquo;s some old hardware almost everyone is familiar with: Floppy disks and big ol&#39; CRT monitors became a big part of what defined a computer, and became recognizeable enough that the shape of a floppy disk is still the standard save icon today. But still, why care?
In history classes the line “Those who don&amp;rsquo;t know history are destined to repeat it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/motherboard/</guid>
      <description>3 - The Motherboard #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  This is an older motherboard, but still new enough to have modern parts. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by looking at the the most obvious physical features and move to smaller things from there.
The most obvious thing to point out is the size of the motherboard. This is a mATX motherboard, which is considered the normal size for most systems. Most gaming or DIY computers will use full size ATX motherboards, which look very similar but are a bit longer vertically, allowing for more expansion slots - those horizontal black bars - among other features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/network/</guid>
      <description>6 - Network Interfaces #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;   Pictured here are three Network Interface Cards (NICs). The three on the left are for WiFi (though some of this form factor may include bluetooth as well) while the one on the right has an ethernet port for wired access. Most computer&amp;rsquo;s will not have a separate card for the wired interface though, as most motherboard&amp;rsquo;s have a wired network interface built in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/peripherals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/peripherals/</guid>
      <description>9 - Peripherals #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  USB #    BUT WAIT! THERE&amp;rsquo;S MORE! USB 4.0 is a thing now, butttt it&amp;rsquo;s actually based on Thunderbolt 3 and is only on USB-C. But what is Thunderbolt then? Let&amp;rsquo;s move on
&amp;hellip; but for the really nerdy that want more, see USB3: why it&amp;rsquo;s a bit harder than USB2, How Does A USB Keyboard Work? (Ben Eater, YouTube), and How does USB device discovery work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/power/</guid>
      <description>7 - Power Supply #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  The Power Supply Unit or PSU does what you think. It takes power from the wall and turns it into power for the computer. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the chapter on voltage and current, so I&amp;rsquo;ll spare some of the details, but effectively you want a power supply that can deliver plenty of power and that has clean power. A given power supply usually has a rating like &amp;lsquo;500w&amp;rsquo; for 500 watts, but this is usually a bad indicator, as they could be referring to multiple things- you see a desktop power supply usually outputs multiple voltages (-12, +12, +5, +3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/ram/</guid>
      <description>2 - RAM #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  Note, that some RAM sticks, espically the full size ones, have metal heat spreaders on top of them. In gaming computer espically it&amp;rsquo;s common for these to have RGB lights as well.  This is RAM or Random Access Memory. The above two sticks are the normal sized used in desktop PCs, this form factor is called a DIMM (Dual In-Line Memory Module) while the bottom two are from laptops and are called SO-DIMMS, the placement of the notch is an indicator of the generation of RAM, with nearly all modern ram being a consecutive generation of the DDR standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/storage/</guid>
      <description>5 - Storage #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  Pictured here are 3 hard drives, 2 of which are &amp;lsquo;full size&amp;rsquo; at 3.5&amp;quot; and the the other a &amp;lsquo;laptop drive&amp;rsquo; at 2.5&amp;quot;, the right most hard drive has been opened up, which has certainly ruined it as dust has gotten in. Below the smaller Hard drive is an NVMe ssd on a carrier card. Under the CD is a micro sd card and a flash drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/howwework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/howwework/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5 - Working on how we work #  The Terminal #  In the world of programming, embedded development, and electrical debugging you will inevitably need to understand how to use a terminal/command line at some point. While the text only interface can look intimidating, it has some clear advantages. Namely it&amp;rsquo;s significantly faster to use the cli or &amp;lsquo;command line interface&amp;rsquo; version of many tools. Because of the nature of this guide you will be using the terminal frequently, so for convince sake information on using it effectively has been moved to Appendix A, I highly recommend you read though it after you finish this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxdirtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxdirtree/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4 - Getting Rooted In Linux #  We&amp;rsquo;ve been using file in /proc and /dev throughout this, but we never really looked to see what else is in there. Let&amp;rsquo;s do that.
go ahead and open up a terminal and run
1 2 3 4 5  ╭─vega@lyrae ~ ╰─➤ cd /dev ╭─vega@lyrae /dev ╰─➤ ls [Very, Very Long Output here]   Alright, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxshell/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 1 - Using the Linux Shell #  ./missing-semester - The Shell
./missing-semester - Shell Tools and Scripting
./missing-semester - Data Wrangling
Linux Productivity Tools Presentation PDF (Ketan M.)
 :root { --body-background: linear-gradient(90deg, #121, #030, #121); --text-color: #f5f5f5cc; --link-color: #090; } body,p { color: var(--text-color); } code{ font-family: &#39;VT323&#39;, monospace; font-size: 22px !important; color: var(--text-color); } body{ background: var(--body-background); color: var(--text-color); } h1,h2,h3,h4,h5,h6,nav{ font-family: &#39;Press Start 2P&#39;, cursive !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/3dprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/3dprint/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 41 - 3D printing, CNC, and making things #  31.1 - Basic making #  Wood working #  Safety #  Cool projects #  Lichtenberg Figure Table (imgur)
Epoxy Inlay and Rustic Compass Butcher Block Countertops (imgur) (YouTube)
Wood Tables Embedded with Photoluminescent Resin (Mike Warren)
Metal Working #  Safety #  41.2 - CNC, 3D, Lasers, &amp;amp; Plotting #  Plotting #  Lasters #  3D Printing #  From personal experiance, I can tell you the really cheap, like sub $200 printers, are mostly shit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/hamradio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/hamradio/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 42 - Ham Radio #  TODO: https://github.com/jopohl/urh
&amp;lsquo;137Mhz&amp;rsquo; by u/CashewHut LORA
2.4Ghz patch antenna
electronically tunable filters
National Radio Quiet Zone (Wikipedia)
https://newhams.info/2017/02/17/rf-connector-types/
question of the day:
Analog TV is shut down in the US, right? so all the over-the-air TV is digital. And existing analog OTA frequencies are getting repurposed to other uses... so what am I seeing on UHF channel 60? it&amp;#39;s got way more structure than the noise everywhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/history/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 43 - History #  BBS and Tildie Sites #  tilde.town: A social network over SSH
Tilde.club
Other Tilde Services?
 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mother_of_All_Demos
Adam Savage&amp;rsquo;s Computer History Collection! (Youtube)
Preserving data #  https://media.ccc.de/v/31c3_-_6373_-_en_-_saal_6_-_201412291600_-_the_only_thing_we_know_about_cyberspace_is_that_its_640x480_-_olia_lialina#t=3641
Preserving hardware #  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delay_line_memory
http://www.vcfed.org/forum/forum.php
https://skilldrick.github.io/easy6502/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/mechanical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/mechanical/</guid>
      <description>Mechancial Bits #  Through all of the Engineering pages I&amp;rsquo;ve foucused on electrical and programming solutions, because those are what I know, but they are not always the right answer. For example, in this reddit post the author asks &amp;ldquo;What kind of motor can I use for this? I need a lightweight pole to go from 0 to 90 degrees [as fast as possible]?&amp;quot; and the answer really stuck out to me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/algebra/</guid>
      <description>1 - Algebra #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  This section is a tad bit misnamed, as instead of covering just Algebra I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering most things you&amp;rsquo;d learn in a high school Algebra class along side it, plus probably a bit extra.  Number Systems #  To get started, let&amp;rsquo;s look at &amp;lsquo;Number Systems&amp;rsquo;. Essentially, there are a variety of &amp;lsquo;types&amp;rsquo; of numbers, rather than get all philosophical let&amp;rsquo;s just dive in and I think you&amp;rsquo;ll get the gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/calc/</guid>
      <description>4 - Calculus #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Introduction To Calculus With Derivatives (adit.io)
Calculus Made Easy  by Silvanus P. Thompson
[TODO] limits before video
Below is a 12 video series that totals about 3.25 hours.   [The Exponential Function is a Miracle (Mark Dominus)](</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/diffeq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/diffeq/</guid>
      <description>5 - Differential Equations #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Below is a 5 video series that totals about 1.5 hours.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/geometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/geometry/</guid>
      <description>3 - Geometry and Trigonometry #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Geometry #  Notation #  ∥, ⊥,
Trigonometry #   Learning Trig playlist on YouTube by &amp;lsquo;The Organic Chemistry Tutor&amp;rsquo;
Notation #  3½ - Topology #        But, this is supposed to be about engineering, so why do we need it?
[TODO] topology optimization and generative design
3¾ - Non-Euclidian Spaces #   Fractals #    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/linalg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/linalg/</guid>
      <description>6 - Matrix Theory / Linear Algebra #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Below is a 15 video series that totals a bit under 3 hours.   Interactive Linear Algebra, text book that actually uses the web  Matricies, Diagrammatically
Linear Algebra - Jim Hefferson
Linear Algebra and Applications: An Inquiry-Based Approach</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/logic/</guid>
      <description>2 - Discrete Math &amp;amp; Logic #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  http://discrete.openmathbooks.org/dmoi3/
Math For Programmers (pdf)  Notation #  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mathematic_operators
Logic #  Many Valued Logic #  Fuzzy Logic #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/math/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6 - Math #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  This section of OpGuides is devided into sub sections for easier reading! Just click the little arrow next to the heading to see the full list of chapters
As with all of OpGuides, please skip around as necessary. I suspect the start of this math chapter will be stuff many readers already know, especially those currently in college.
  Math 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/numanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/numanalysis/</guid>
      <description>7 - Numerical Analysis #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;   Bisection Method
Newton&amp;rsquo;s Method
Secant Method
Lagrange Polynomial
Divided Differences
Linear Interpolation, Bilinear Interpolation, Bicubic Interpolation, Spatial Interpolation
Cubic Spline
Numerical Differentiation
Trapezoidal Rule
Simpson&amp;rsquo;s Rule
Romberg Integration
Monte Carlo Method - Algorithm Archive
Condition Number
Least Squares
The Bernstein Basis (Mutual Information, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/probability/</guid>
      <description>10 - Probability/Stats #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Why, where are these used, etc.
bring up music things, part failure rates, tollerences, etc.
Basics #  For the following I&amp;rsquo;ll be using a dice roll example, where the events are the total of two die. The Sample Space of this is
  \(S = \{2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12\}\)  Note, that 1 isn&amp;rsquo;t possible as the lowest is both die being &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/settheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/settheory/</guid>
      <description>9 - Set Theory #  The, uh, study of sets. It&amp;rsquo;s not as boring as it sounds, I swear.  document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Set theory is pretty boring. Yes, it brings about ideas of infinity, Sets of numbers (integers, complex numbers, etc.) but frankly, unless you&amp;rsquo;re really into math&amp;rsquo;s nerdy bits and tyring to understand the nature of mathmatics and all that jazz, there&amp;rsquo;s really only a few bits you need to understand:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/units/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/units/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6½ - Units #     By 42CrMo4 and Christoph Päper English units of Length, CC BY-SA 4.0   Scaling, Logarithms and Scientific Notation #  Before we get into units, we need to get into scale. That is, the idea of how big or how small something is, usually relative to something else.
In elementary school, you were taught to write the powers of 10 like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 38½ - &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo; #  Some people will tell you the cloud is the future, that someday everybody will rent computational power from a handful of services like AWS.
These people are nuts.
The cloud is just someone eles&amp;rsquo;s computer. Unless your business is going though a period of extreme growth it makes no sense to use a cloud provider like AWS or Azure. It does make plenty of sense to buy a VPS (Virtual Private Server) for hosting a website or game server or a personal website like this one, but at scale?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/databases/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 39 - Databases #  [TODO] Start with comparison to spread sheet, explaining &amp;lsquo;NoSQL&amp;rsquo; Vs &amp;lsquo;SQL&amp;rsquo; and that this is Relational vs Non-Relational
[TODO] explain CRUD
CRUD #  Create, Read, Update, Delete
SQL #  This is Opinionated Guides, so let me be clear, I really, really hate SQL. I don&amp;rsquo;t like OOP in general, and SQL is sorta like object orientation taken further. Add onto this a mostly shit syntax, like, JOINs are objectively weird to read, write, and understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/networking/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 37 - Networking #  The Basics #  To get started, let&amp;rsquo;s just get some basic terminology down and take a look at the bigger picture:
Nodes #  These are all the points in the network. There are terminal nodes and intermediate nodes.
Terminal nodes are things like your phone, laptop, desktop, and other user-facing devices, as well as servers, like would be used for hosting games or websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 40½ - Your Guide to Privacy #   &#34; Arguing that you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the right to privacy because you have nothing to hide is no different than saying you don&amp;rsquo;t care about free speech because you have nothing to say. &#34;  - Edward Snowden, in his Reddit AMA   Privacy online is a joke. No matter what you do, you&amp;rsquo;re still going to be tracked so much that advertisers and the big tech companies (Facebook, Google, Microsoft, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/security/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 40 - Security &amp;amp; Exploitation #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume at least some prior knowledge here, if you want a quick intro, I recommend going through ./missing-semester-Security so that we can all be on the same page.  Often when we think about Exploitation, better known as hacking, we conjure images of a more-punk-than-cyber cyberpunk person clicking away wildly on a keyboard as code flies by, like the 1995 movie, Hackers, and to some extent this isn&amp;rsquo;t wrong, as one look around the floor at DefCon, will show you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/servers/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 38 - Servers! #  First of all, let&amp;rsquo;s demystify the servers, they are not something to be afraid of &amp;hellip; they are just normal computers that execute processes, the main difference is that these computers do not have a direct interface, that is: there is no need for them to have peripherals (most of the time) since they only SERVE resources for other needs.
A good example of a server is this one, in which you are reading this, the only function of the server where this content is hosted is to provide it, nothing more and nothing less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/chem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/chem/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 8 - Chemistry #  Super handy periodic table with visualization, atomic mass, melting/boiling points, specific heat, isotopes, etc. (ptable)
This chapter is more or less on hold while I prioritize adding the content I&amp;rsquo;m more familiar with, if you&amp;rsquo;d like, feel free to submit a PR to flesh this section out. Unfortunately my chemistry education was pretty &amp;lsquo;meh&amp;rsquo;, and I never actually made it to Organic Chem. I have CrashCourse&amp;rsquo;s Chemistry and Organic Chemistry videos on YouTube on my &amp;lsquo;To Watch&amp;rsquo; list though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/othersubjects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/othersubjects/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 9 - &amp;lsquo;The Rest&amp;rsquo; #  English #  I&amp;rsquo;m monolingual. I got just enough Spanish in high school to graduate and never looked back. Unfortunately for those that don&amp;rsquo;t speak English as a first language, the internet has developed in such a way that English is basically the go-to language online.
Okay, so, some context is necessary here. Historically, England sorta gave the whole &amp;ldquo;World Domination&amp;rdquo; thing a shot as colonialism and in the process spread English to, well, everywhere?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/physics/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7 - Physics #  This is still a dumping ground for things I want to write about later, nothing of substance is here yet, sorry about that ╮(─▽─)╭ [TODO] speed vs Velocity vs Acceleration, clasicall vs realative
Radiocarbon dating (Wikipedia)
Cosmic Microwave Background (Wikipedia)
Natural nuclear fission reactor (Wikipedia)
How Kodak Exposed The Atomic Bomb (YouTube, Veritasium)
Seeing the invisible: Event displays in particle physics
Building a Vortex Tube (This Old Tony, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 14 - Discrete Math, Algorithms, Data Structures, and Not Sucking at Programming ™* #  Brute Force Algorithms #  Backtracking #   [TODO] Directed Acyclic Graphs
[TODO] Finite State Machines
[TODO] e-graphs? https://egraphs-good.github.io
[TODO] http://courses.csail.mit.edu/6.851/
[TODO] &amp;lsquo;Tree Traversal&amp;rsquo; on Algorithm Archive
Divide and Conquer #  Master Theorm #  Decrease and Conquer #  Branch and Bound #  Kernelization #  Cacheing #  *With some complexity analysis too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/bigprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/bigprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 15 - Writing a larger program #  From https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/development.html
  Prototype before polishing. Get it working before optimizing it. Separate policy from mechanism, separate interfaces from engines. Write simple modular parts connected by clean interfaces. Design programs to be connected to other programs. Write programs to write programs when you can. Design for the future, because it will be here sooner than you think. In interface design, always do the least surprising thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codecont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codecont/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 12 - Finishing up the project #   Manifesto  Everything should be a tool. A tool transforms data without adding to its source limitations. It&amp;rsquo;s a function: returns an output for a given input. A great tool is ambient. It should disappear and flow through your actions. You should never need it because it&amp;rsquo;s always at your hands. You should never ignore it because it&amp;rsquo;s never in your way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codeintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codeintro/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10 - Let&amp;rsquo;s write some Code #  Starting Minimal #  Code is mostly math #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Code is mostly math. If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you probably just went ugggggghhhhhhh.
And I get it. But it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad for two reasons:
 The math isn&amp;rsquo;t like what you&amp;rsquo;re used to. The math is actually doing something. You&amp;rsquo;re not just getting a number to solve a problem, you&amp;rsquo;re making a tool that can solve many problems or watching the math cause something to happen on screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/consequences/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10½ - Consequences #  Programming is awesome. If you get into creative coding you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use it to make art. You&amp;rsquo;ll likely use it to automate tasks you find boring. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you might use it to make your own website or start to make products you intend to sell. That&amp;rsquo;s great. But there are a few things you need to consider as what you make becomes more professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/data/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 13½ - Data, Encodings, etc. #  When you write code, you&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably be working with input and output of some sort - even if it&amp;rsquo;s just text. This is always more complicated than it seems. For example, text processing is easy, right?
🚫, 🅘🆃 🄸🄣&#39;s 🇳ot.
Even text enocding is a massive pain, unless you can ensure you only need to (and do) process basic ASCII characters, that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/debugbuildtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/debugbuildtest/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 16 - Debugging, Building and Testing #  Building #  The C Build Process #   I&amp;rsquo;m going to jump right in here, so things are going to be a bit brutal to understand for a bit. I&amp;rsquo;ll break things down, but I need to give the high-level view first!  As we saw way back Hardware→CPU  , your computer doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand instructions like printf(), so ultimately the code you write has to get turned into something your computer understands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fixxingissuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fixxingissuses/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 12½ - It Was Working Just A Second Ago&amp;hellip; #  Alright, so your code/electronics/computer/life was working fine just a second ago, and now it&amp;rsquo;s just not working at all. Take a deep breath, and relax. Let&amp;rsquo;s work though this.
🦆 Grab a rubber duck #  This won&amp;rsquo;t always be applicable, but assuming it&amp;rsquo;s a system- code, or electronics, or a math problem, something that can be analyzed - explain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fosscopyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fosscopyright/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11½ - Open Source, Licenses, and Copyright #   Open source enables a development method for software that harnesses the power of distributed peer review and transparency of process. The promise of open source is higher quality, better reliability, greater flexibility, lower cost, and an end to predatory vendor lock-in.
 &amp;ndash; The Open Source Initiative Mission Statement
Disclaimer #  I am not a lawyer, and neither are any of my contributors to this section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/funcprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/funcprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 21 - (((())(()((()(())))))) #  What is Functional Programming? #   Most of the programming languages in this section up until now have been imperative programming languages. Programs are a series of instructions: do this, then do that, then do the other thing.
Functional programming languages are another type of language. Like math, they simply define sets, relationships, and then have a process for doing things based on &amp;ldquo;answering questions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;getting to a result&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/game/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 20 - Game Programming &amp;amp; Design #  https://www.gameuidatabase.com/index.php
https://www.riotgames.com/en/urf-academy/curriculum-guide
COMP4300 - Game Programming (David Churchill, YouTube)
Engines &amp;amp; Frameworks #  Both 2d and 3d #  Godot
Luxe
fine. I&amp;rsquo;ll mention Unity and Unreal, but, like, I hate that the two make up such a huge chunk of the market
Unreal Engine
Unity
2d #  LEd engine - &amp;ldquo;LEd is a modern and open-source 2D level editor, specifically designed for indie devs&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/guiprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/guiprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 18 - Graphical Programming #  [TODO] Graphics Programming on badd10de.dev
Let&amp;rsquo;s start in a way that&amp;rsquo;s incredibly simple, and abstract away all the hard stuff at first by using a tool kit called &amp;lsquo;Processing&amp;rsquo;, which is available under that name from the community repo in arch. The default IDE that comes with it is awful to work in though, so go ahead and open up VSCode and grab the Processing Language add on, then in VSCode open up a new workspace folder and make a file called processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/languages/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 13 - Programming Languages #  for (🥚 = 1; 🥚 &amp;lt; 🐔; 🥚++){ //whatever } [TODO] talk about to why there are so many, pros &amp;amp; cons per domain, etc
https://esoteric.codes
Why OO Sucks (Joe Armstrong)
0-based vs. 1-based indexing (Hisham Hm)
Low Level #  C, C++, C#, ???? #  [TODO] - a lot, talk about the varieties and differences of C and C++ and C# and why thery&amp;rsquo;re good and bad, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lowlvl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lowlvl/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11 - Low Level Programming #   Ashlyn Black&amp;rsquo;s C Cheat Sheet
&amp;lsquo;C Programming&amp;rsquo; on badd10de.dev
Why C? #  This chapter of OpGuides will be mostly C, but, why? Well, there&amp;rsquo;s only really a few options for learning low level programming that make sense to start with. C, C++, Rust are the &amp;lsquo;big three&amp;rsquo; that come to mind for me. C is awesome. It&amp;rsquo;s spec is small, it&amp;rsquo;s been kept minimal, and it&amp;rsquo;s got a ton of tools to help you learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/multithread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/multithread/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 17 - We&amp;rsquo;ve got cores, let&amp;rsquo;s use em&#39; #  [TDOO] Motivations from Moore&amp;rsquo;s law, Blocking I/O,
[TODO] start with process forking via syscall - show it
https://lemire.me/blog/2020/01/30/cost-of-a-thread-in-c-under-linux/
C++ coroutines
not really threading, but process children
SIMD, https://nullprogram.com/blog/2021/12/04/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/shaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/shaders/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 19 - Shaders #  The Book Of Shaders   I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume you read through The Book Of Shaders because, frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic and there&amp;rsquo;s no way I&amp;rsquo;m going to to be able to do better for now- that said, I do have some commentary, that maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful. Each of these tabs corolates to the respective page in The Book, and is really just what I stumbled into as I tried to fill in the gaps for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/aiml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/aiml/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 32 - Fine, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about AI #  This chapter is very much a work in progress, and is really more of just a list of topics despite how much content there appears to be. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to have code examples under each concept as well, as otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s like reading a fucking math textbook from hell.In the mean time, please see https://sebastianraschka.com/blog/2021/dl-course.html#l01-introduction-to-deep-learning for a good intro to Deep Learning [TODO] https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/commsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/commsys/</guid>
      <description>28 - Communication Systems #  This chapter is currently just a stub. I&amp;rsquo;m currently taking a comm systems class at Uni and will be putting the results of my notes as well as external resources into here at some point. What is a communication system? #  For the purposes of this page, we&amp;rsquo;re talking about systems that transmit signals over a medium- so that might be your voice over the air, a radio signal though the vaccuum of space, or ultrasonic waves under the water as sonar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/compvision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/compvision/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 31 - Computer Vision #  This page is still pretty empty, in the mean time, check out The Ancient Secrets of Computer Vision by Joseph Redmon and Ali Farhadi
 As an aside, Joseph Redmon is an absolute genius, and the main brain behind You Only Look Once: Unified, Real-Time Object Detection which sort of revolutionized the computer vision with AI space, yet, his resume looks like this</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/controlsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/controlsys/</guid>
      <description>30 - Control Systems #  What are control systems? Well, the easiest way to answer that is to list the things control systems typically do:
What Can Control Systems do? #  Amplify an input: #   ex: Pluck a tiny string on a guitar, get an earth shaking output from the speaker   Reduce the complexity of user input or change its location #   ex: Floor button on an elevator- you don&amp;rsquo;t need to input a height off the ground for what floor you want to be on, nor do you need to enter values to compensate for how quickly it should get to it&amp;rsquo;s max speed or how fast it should slow down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/dsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/dsp/</guid>
      <description>29 - Digital Signal Processing #   Spectral Audio Signal Processing by JULIUS O. SMITH III at the Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics (CCRMA)  The Scientist and Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Digital Signal Processing By Steven W. Smith, Ph.D.
Awesome MusicDSP (Github)
Tom Erbe, Design the Erbe Verb (YouTube)
https://zserge.com/posts/etude-in-c/ &amp;amp; https://zserge.com/posts/beep/
Diospyros - Search-based compiler for high-performance DSP programming
Think DSP - DSP in Python, Free book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/sigandsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/sigandsys/</guid>
      <description>27 - Signals &amp;amp; Systems #  When I took ECEN 304 Signals &amp;amp; Systems Ⅰ with the fantastic Dr. Sayood at UNL I remember how in awe I was at how he consisely he managed to describe the core idea of this class. While I can not hope to convey the same level of brilliance or inspiration, I do hope that my poor attempt at mimicing his introduction to the course may be of value:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/cheat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/cheat/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 2 - Cheat Sheets and quick info #  Electrical Part Tables #  [TODO]
  package types
  reading specs
  datasheets
  Nice Libraries &amp;amp; Resources #  Multi-Language #  Ultralight - &amp;ldquo;Next-generation HTML renderer for apps and games&amp;rdquo;
 Bit like Electron, but less shit. Supports C, C++, C#, Rust, Java, and Go
 C #  Awesome-C - &amp;ldquo;A curated list of awesome C frameworks, libraries, resources and other shiny things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/job/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 4 - Getting a Job in Engineering #   &#34;Recently, I was asked if I was going to fire an employee who made a mistake that cost the company $600,000. No, I replied, I just spent $600,000 training him. Why would I want somebody to hire his experience?&#34;  - Thomas John Watson Sr., IBM
  [TODO] literally this entire page is TODO. I&amp;rsquo;m just making it as a place to dump links for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/latex/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 5 -   \(\LaTeX\)  &amp;amp; Markdown #  Like the kink? #   \(\LaTeX\)  , pronounced Lay-Tech, is a document writing and formatting &amp;lsquo;language&amp;rsquo; that acts pretty different from MS Word. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily used for writing fancy math equations, academic, journal, or conference papers, as such, you might have to use it at some point to conform to one standard or another (like IEEE).
As an example of what  \(\LaTeX\)  formatting looks like, check this equation out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/resources/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 3 - Other Great Resources #  Conventions #  https://www.emfcamp.org
https://media.ccc.de/
    News Sites #  Serializer.io (Aggregate of Hacker News, Ars, Reddit, Macrumors, and Lobste.rs )
Hacker News
Hackaday
Slashdot
 Snopzu
https://n-o-d-e.news/
   Forums #  https://lobste.rs/
https://stackoverflow.com/
   http://textfiles.com/
https://glitch.com/
 Learning Linux #  https://linuxjourney.com
 Youtube #  ElectroBoom
CNLohr
N-O-D-E
LiveOverflow
Tom Scott
 bigclive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/wrappingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/wrappingup/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 44 - Where To Go From Here? #  Hey, so, you made it. I can&amp;rsquo;t give you a degree. But, I&amp;rsquo;m proud of you. Even if you skipped a chapter or two, you still put in work to improve yourself and learn something. That&amp;rsquo;s cool.
But, maybe you thinking &amp;ldquo;Okay, but now what?&amp;quot;
Integrating other interests #  There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to life than computers and code and electronics and making and hacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Cadey Ratio #   .conversation { display: flex; } .conversation-picture { flex: 1; min-width: 9rem; max-width: calc(((70rem - 2rem)/6)); }  3/10/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Cadey. Your blog at christine.website/blog shows that you really have a wide range of interests. So, to get started, what are you passionate about and why?
I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about making computers understandable. We work with these impossibly complex mechanical creations like they are nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/kell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/kell/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Kell Bengal #  7/27/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Kell. I know you work on robots, and teach others to do so as well, and are from the continent where everything wants to kill you, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know much else: How would you describe yourself? What are you passionate about and why?
I would describe myself as an engineer, first and foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Loial Otter #  9/23/2018
Introduction:
I&amp;rsquo;m Matthew or LoialOtter, a crazy person up in western Canada who likes to make stuff. I work at Kron Technology as an engineer mainly in FPGA, electronics design and hardware design.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have any credentials except a certificate in baking and pastry arts. I&amp;rsquo;m self-taught mostly due to not being ever able to afford going to school. I suggest others do when the have the opportunity but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolutely required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Soatok Dreamseeker #  12/3/2020
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Soatok. Your blog at https://soatok.blog shows that you&amp;rsquo;re a furry crypto nerd, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to hear how you&amp;rsquo;d put it, so, to get started, can you describe yourself?
Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m asked, I usually say something to the effect of, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a security engineer with a dhole fursona that sometimes writes about cryptography on my furry blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/spg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/spg/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Annie of Sex Positive Gaming #  01/07/2022
:root {--body-background: linear-gradient(90deg, #2a1a33, #1c1122, #1c1122);--text-color: #C0ADC9;--link-color: #814D9F;}strong {font-size: 18px;color: var(--text-color);}p {font-size: 20px;color: #d6d6d6;}code{font-family: &#39;VT323&#39;, monospace;font-size: 22px !important;color: var(--text-color);}body{background: var(--body-background);color: var(--text-color);}h1,h2,h3,h4,h5,h6,nav{font-family: &#39;Press Start 2P&#39;, cursive !important;font-size: 18px;}a{color: var(--link-color);font-family: &#39;Press Start 2P&#39;, cursive;}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/taxbadger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/taxbadger/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Laguna of Tax Badger, LLC #  08/26/2021
﻿﻿Laguna Crale is a bright pink Tax Badger that has made a name for himself with Tax Badger, LLC where he has made waves in the furry artist and NSFW content creator communities for being open and accepting of these professions. He&amp;rsquo;s freely given helpful pointers on his Twitter, @TaxBadgerLLC to help those questioning how to handle transitioning from making content as a hobby to making it a real, legal self-employment career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Distortion #   How Distortion Works in Music (Ben Sheron&amp;rsquo;s Blog)
Clipping (Soft &amp;amp; Hard) #  Clipping does exactly what it sounds like, it just chops off the wave. Usually on both the top and bottom.
Hard Clipping
 Soft Clipping
  The key take away from the two different kinds of clipping is that while both add harmonics, hard clipping adds significantly more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</guid>
      <description>Filters (LP, HP, BP, Notch) #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  https://www.perfectcircuit.com/signal/learning-synthesis-filters
Low Pass Filters #  Low Pass filters do what you think, they let the low frequencies pass and cut out the high frequencies. As with most filters, this will typically not be a sharp cutoff but instead be a gradual fading of the higher frequencies. Despite this, there is still a point called the cut off frequency, which is defined as the point where the signal is cut by 3db (what this means is discussed below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</guid>
      <description>Misc Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Auto-Tune #  Given it&amp;rsquo;s basically a meme now, I assume you know what Auto-Tune is. What you may not realize is that not all auto-tune is, well, auto. A lot of the time it&amp;rsquo;s done manually, painstakingly correcting the tuning. If the original sound is close enough, it&amp;rsquo;s usually pretty easy to get it to sound natural too.
Also keep in mind pitch correction isn&amp;rsquo;t just for vocals, you might want to pitch correct your guitar playing, change a note in an already recorded sequence when you change keys, or even just use it as a glitchy effect on pitch bends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</guid>
      <description>Time Based Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Delay #  Delay is basically echo. Take a sound in, and repeat it it it. Normally the main controls on a delay are &amp;lsquo;Time&amp;rsquo;, which controls how long of a delay there is before each repeat, &amp;lsquo;Feedback&amp;rsquo; which controls how much the level is reduced each time the delay repeats (and in turn, how many audible repetitions there are), and &amp;lsquo;Dry/Wet&amp;rsquo; which controls how the signal is blended, entirely dry will have no delay, entirely wet may even miss the initial sound adding a weird latency before you hear what you&amp;rsquo;re playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</guid>
      <description>Trivial Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Tremolo #  This is probably the easiest to understand audio effect. Put simply, fade the volume in and out automatically. This can be done at different speeds (really fast for a &amp;lsquo;deep&amp;rsquo; effect or slow for something pad-like) and with a bias so that the volume never completely cuts. It can also refer to a playing style where the same note is struck rapidly, leading to a similar effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</guid>
      <description>The Esoteric #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  feedback only, no input. i love this instrument. pic.twitter.com/IR6lmxZGHJ
&amp;mdash; 𝒆𝒎𝒎𝒂 (@HECKSCAPER) July 31, 2020  𝐡𝐨𝐰 𝐢𝐭 𝐰𝐨𝐫𝐤𝐬: pedal rig rundown &amp;amp; building a sound (Emma Essex)
     A neat on-guitar effects board (Instagram, ian.costabile)
Why To Modular With Guitar (YouTube, Knobs)
Otamatone Metal - Rob Scallon
Theorbo - The enormous 14 string lute (YouTube)
Double-sided Guitar Jam (YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</guid>
      <description>Percussion #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  Theory #  Before I even dive into Percussion, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out how generic the term is. Just looking at the Wikipedia page for drum kit you&amp;rsquo;ll see this:
Drum Kit page on Wikipedia and clearly that&amp;rsquo;s still not an exhaustive list. Just off the top of my head I can see it lacks the Cajon or Taiko as acoustic instruments, let alone anything more specific than electronic drum, which can make for a class all its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</guid>
      <description>Strings #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  Picture of my character by Alex the Nerd Bird Guitars #  Acoustic, Electric, Acoustic-Electric? #  Hollow Body, Solid Body? #  Pickups? #  Picks, Slides, fingers, or&amp;hellip; chopsticks? #       Classical Guitars? #     6-String #  Bass #  12-String #  Extended Range #  Fretless #  Baritone #  Lap Steel &amp;amp; Pedal Steel #  Pianos #  Clavinet #  Dulcimers #  Hammered #      Harp #  [TODO] + Pedals on harp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</guid>
      <description>Synths #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  [TODO] I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about FM, additive, subtractive, etc. in Sound Sources. Here I want to go into how they fit into a song, the idea of pads, leads, bass. As well as how a lot of famous sounds have been done and what some of the most famous synths are. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to cover some of why some newer synths are exciting, like the Hydrasynth, Continumm, Norand Mono, Subharmonicon, Polygogo,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</guid>
      <description>Wind #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  What is a Wind Instrument? #   A wind instrument is a musical instrument that contains some type of resonator (usually a tube) in which a column of air is set into vibration by the player blowing into (or over) a mouthpiece set at or near the end of the resonator. The pitch of the vibration is determined by the length of the tube and by manual modifications of the effective length of the vibrating column of air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</guid>
      <description>MIDI in Detail #  Musical Instrument Digital Interface, or MIDI is what it sounds like, the primary way to get data between devices digitally. Want to tell a hardware synth to play a sequence you arranged on your computer? MIDI. Want to play notes into your computer using a keyboard? MIDI. Want to sequence drums, with varying &amp;lsquo;velocity&amp;rsquo; on each hit? MIDI.
Sounds Great?
For the most part, yeah. Everything works together and you can make all your hardware speak the same language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</guid>
      <description>Piracy? #  Plugins++ #  Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not the police. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care what you do on your system. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to outright condone you find pirated versions of music software though- in part for liability, but mostly because you absolutely will get a virus. That said, some sites are more reputable than others, and if you&amp;rsquo;re careful, you can probably yoink at least a few things. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</guid>
      <description>Psychoacoustics and Cultural Associations #   When we here music, we don&amp;rsquo;t hear individual sine waves and sum them up. We don&amp;rsquo;t hear instruments devoid of context either- a ukulele carries a different cultral meaning than a mandolin. We also don&amp;rsquo;t just hear what comes out the speakers as planly as basic frequencies. Our ears process what we here. Our ears take in the reverb of the room, ignore sounds before and after drum hits, find speech in sounds that weren&amp;rsquo;t meant to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</guid>
      <description>Digital Audio Workstations+ #   document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true; A Digital Audio Workstations is software that allows you to record and edit audio, host and play digital instruments, arrange the parts in a time line, and mix the audio together. The most common DAWs you&amp;rsquo;ll see are Ableton Live (Often called just &amp;ldquo;Ableton&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Live&amp;rdquo;) and FL Studio, but there are plenty of other options as well, many of which are listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</guid>
      <description>Live Coding Tools #   document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true;    Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot / Demo     SonicPi     ORCΑ  Learn Orca Extra Tools for ORCA:  Cassetter for ORCA Aioi - UDP to complex OSC for ORCA  Pilot - 16 voice synth for ORCA    Noton A minimal logic gates playground, written in ANSI C. Made by the same developers as ORCΑ    Chuck &amp;ldquo;Chuck is a programming language for real-time sound synthesis and music creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</guid>
      <description>Plugins #  This page is a massive work in progress  document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true; This is probably where the most bias of any of the lists on this page will show as I obviously can&amp;rsquo;t list every possible plugin. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll list those that I think are particularly good both in terms of value and function. While the list below does have ranking (copper, silver, gold) everything I&amp;rsquo;m listing I think is good, even the &amp;lsquo;copper&amp;rsquo; ones!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</guid>
      <description>VCV Rack Tips &amp;amp; Tricks #  I am not affiliated with VCV or the Rack software in any way. Despite the mess in the VCV community, I&amp;rsquo;ve still put in a lot of time in the software and run a pretty large group chat on Telegram where it (along side hardware Eurorack) is the main focus. In that chat, there&amp;rsquo;s been a feel recurring questions, this page is just some of those questions and answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/coolhardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/coolhardware/</guid>
      <description>Cool Hardware #    LTP-305G/HR 5x7 LED Matrix displays &amp;amp; Driver, article on (Hackaday)
also see the redot project for a modern clone
  Core Memory Shield for Arduino by Jussi Kilpelainen on Tindie
  A somewhat ridiculous precision voltage source
turns out placing 900 resistors does not get you banned from SMD assembly service after all 😇 pic.twitter.com/3iu3zL5TLi
&amp;mdash; Marco Reps (@MarcoReps) December 31, 2020    List of nixie tube types: https://justanotherelectronicsblog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/funlinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/funlinks/</guid>
      <description>Other cool things that I want to promote but don&amp;rsquo;t fit elsewhere so I&amp;rsquo;m making this list here: #    Brimestone Valley Mall
 The year is 1999. Lurking somewhere between Hot Topic and the food court, five misfit demons from Hell kill time inciting sin in a suburban shopping mall. When the lead singer of their band goes mysteriously missing, the demons only have two weeks to find him before they play the biggest gig of the millennium - or face the wrath of Satan herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/contradictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/contradictions/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4: What points contradict? #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true; Having Low Level Access and High Level Usability. #  Yeah, this is always a problem. It&amp;rsquo;s always been the dream to be able to describe in &amp;lsquo;natural language&amp;rsquo; what you want and to have the computer parse what you want, inferring intent, and do whatever you want for you, but naturally, this will never be totally possible. This point is only conflicting in the sense that it can be overwhelming- if a user has access to work in something as high as natural language and can manipulate those instructions all the way down an the assembly level, that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of open space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/digital/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2: The Digital #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true; Alright, now onto the fun stuff, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve established that the physical side of how we use a computer is sub optimal, but what about how we actually do the things we do day to day? I think, for the most part, these things can be put into a few categories:
 Finding and Accessing shit Looking at shit Storing Shit Transferring Shit Making Shit  I&amp;rsquo;m not the first to think on this subject by any means, Programs are a prison: Rethinking the fundamental building blocks of computing interfaces by Robert Lechte is a particularly good example of other thoughts on this same subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/intro/</guid>
      <description>The Way We Interact With Computers Sucks. #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true;  ASCII art morphing by Tim Holman   pre.morph-section { background-color: #2220 !important; font-family: monospace; color: #fff; font-size: .6em; }   /** * Ascii Morph * @author: Tim Holman (http://tholman.com) */ var AsciiMorph = (function() { &#39;use strict&#39;; var element = null; var canvasDimensions = {}; var renderedData = []; var framesToAnimate = []; var myTimeout = null; /** * Utils */ function extend(target, source) { for (var key in source) { if (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/physical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/physical/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1: The Physical #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true; Computers aren&amp;rsquo;t just about software, websites, and programs. As the most powerful tool that most people have access to and often one that we spend many hours a day looking at, it makes sense that we make working with that tool comfortable, straight forward, and healthy. In general, we&amp;rsquo;ve mostly sucked at this, and while some things are getting better (monitor resolution) some things have gotten significantly worse (keyboards).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/radicallychanging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/radicallychanging/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5: What Might Radically Change Things? #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true; ML Assisted Creation #  [TODO] https://cleanvoice.ai / https://www.descript.com, https://magenta.tensorflow.org, https://runwayml.com, https://auphonic.com/landing, etc.
Body Modification and Bio-Engineering #  Another point is the idea of biohacking and body augmentation. The most common biohacks include implanted RFID tags (which I actually have) and magnets for sensing electromagnetic fields, but these are still pretty mundane. This Ted Talk I think shows what might be possible a bit better:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/whatelse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/whatelse/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3: What&amp;rsquo;s Else Is Needed? #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true; Script all the things! But Not Like That™ #  [TODO]
Visual Programming but still supporting text based programming, natural language scripting
everything is a file/folder (inc. full programs)
Optional Security #  TempleOS is a really weird operating system. From Wikipedia
 TempleOS is a biblical-themed lightweight operating system designed to be the Third Temple prophesied in the Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/wrappingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/wrappingup/</guid>
      <description>Wrapping up #   document.getElementById(&#34;hciMenu&#34;).open = true; In all honestly I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure what everything I just wrote is about. Mostly it&amp;rsquo;s just a lot of ranting, but hopefully it has been interesting. To round things off with a bit of a closing note though, I don&amp;rsquo;t actually foresee many of the things I mentioned becoming common place or many even being possible, if not simply because they&amp;rsquo;re require so many people to agree on standards, but there is one glimmer of hope, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of proof of uniformity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/personal/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/personal/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>Wishlist #  $50 and Under #    Name &amp; Link Description Picture Category Price in USD (approx)     Geiger Counter Detects Radiation  Electronics ~$40   Musical Tesla Coil Makes music with big sparks in the air Music / Electronics ~$30   Magic Eye Tube Music Display using a tube  Music / Electronics ~$25   Small Electric Screwdriver(Arturia) Saves my hands hurting when tearing apart big things  Electronics ~$32   Toki Pona: The Language of Good Book about how to speak and write in a neat fantasy language  Book ~$16   Morse Code Straight Key I&#39;d actually be using this as part of a DIY guitar pedal  Electronics ~$25   Nerdy Shirt Either a medium or large should fit  Clothes ~$23   Safety Valve Eurorack Module PCB Distortion Effect  Music ~$50    $50 to $100 #    Name &amp; Link Description Picture Category Price in USD (approx)     ZLOB Diode Chaos Makes nice random signals for music stuff  Electronics ~$90IF YOU CAN GET IT USED, DO    $100+ #    Name &amp; Link Description Picture Category Price in USD (approx)     Stero MICROPHONE THESE ARE NOT HEADPHONES Allows for recording in stereo  Music ~$150   MIDI HUb  Allows complex routing of my other equipment in really fun ways  Music ~$180    Data Bender  Glitchy, broken super fun sounding audio effect  Music ~$350IF YOU CAN GET IT USED, DO   Cursus Iteritas  Audio sound source, probably the best sounding out there for what it does  Music ~$360IF YOU CAN GET IT USED, DO   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</guid>
      <description>Economic Systems #   Cryptocurrency &amp;amp; NFTs #  Why NFTs are bad: the long version (Antsstyle)
Hacker News comments on &amp;ldquo;PayPal raises fees for most domestic transaction types to 3.49% + $0.49&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</guid>
      <description>Environmental Protection #  Legacy [OC] from r/funny  Carbon Tax?
Percentage of all fossil fuel emissions that have occurred in my lifetime [OC] from r/dataisbeautiful 
Geoengineering: A Horrible Idea We Might Have to Do (YouTube, Kurzgesagt)
A Strange New Blend of Rock and Plastic Is Forming on a Portuguese Island (Gizmodo)
A Plateful of Plastic - Visualising the amount of microplastic we eat (Reuters)
The poison found in everyone, even unborn babies – and who is responsible for it (The Guardian)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/armament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/armament/</guid>
      <description>Personal Armament #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true;  Before we talk about this at all, I want to get one thing out of the way:
The 2nd amendment does not make gun ownership right or wrong. Laws - including the constitution - do not dictate morality and ethics. We all know there are unjust laws and many choose to break them because of it. So, if you use the argument &amp;ldquo;But Muh Constitution!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/body/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Body #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; What should you be able to do with your body? The immediate reaction may be &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s my body, so whatever I want!&amp;rdquo; but think about it really, should everyone have the right to do anything they want with their body? What about suicide and self harm? What about when information about you is shared- if you take a DNA test, that impacts everyone related to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/environmentalconcern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/environmentalconcern/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of environmental concern #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; Vaccination #  Local Polution #  PFAS #  Air Quality #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/fairtrial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/fairtrial/</guid>
      <description>Fair Trial #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; Jury of your peers - how do we define peers? #  Court of Public Opinion #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/freedoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/freedoms/</guid>
      <description>Freedoms and Rights #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; Before we go into some actual philosophy and current issues, let&amp;rsquo;s establish a baseline by looking at some of how freedooms and rights are laid out around the world
UN Declaration of Human Rights #  The Universal Declaration of Human Rights from the United Nations lays out quite a few protections that are mostly ignored and unenforcable, but fundamentally agreeable. The actual text isn&amp;rsquo;t very long, but here&amp;rsquo;s the quick version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/ownership/</guid>
      <description>Promise of Ownership #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; DRM, Right to Repair #  See the DRM  , Right To Repair  , and Ads in content you&#39;ve already paid for  sections from Chapter 9: Consumerism  https://goel.io/drm-ownership
General Purpose Computation #  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HUEvRyemKSg
First Sale Doctrine #  Trademark #  https://www.ipwatchdog.com/2021/04/13/satan-shoes-trademark-blasphemy-free-speech/id=132184/
Reverse Engineering #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/press/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Press #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; Everyone is press, https://www.eff.org/bloggers
The Trump Administration Is Trying To Force BuzzFeed News To Divulge Its Sources With A Subpoena
anti-SLAPP laws
Whistle Blower Protections #  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_whistleblowers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/recording/</guid>
      <description>Right to record, Right to know #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true;  if it is public, there&amp;rsquo;s reason to expect you may be if it is private, person to person, (not b2b or p2b) there&amp;rsquo;s an exception for if it only for personal or judical (to be used in trial) use.  I.E, can&amp;rsquo;t post it online if it&amp;rsquo;s unreasonable to expect being recorded    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/search/</guid>
      <description>Search and Seizure #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true;   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/speech/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Speech #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; xkcd №1357  The freedom of speech is weird, because it&amp;rsquo;s one that most of us recognize is that it should have limits because speech is powerful. The problem comes in what those limits are, which is why there are so many topics under debate:
 Government Secrets Whistleblowing Hate Speech Political/Religious Opinion Copyright Parody Public Health Advertising of Sugar/Drugs Public Saftey Creating Panic Encryption Self Incrimination Flag Burning National Pride Gag Orders National Security Porn/Cursing Public Decency (and the FCC) Advertising Spam Satire Defamation    There&amp;rsquo;s also a question of where things go to far- at what point is speech a legitimate threat, and where is the line for actions that constitute harassment vs just being an asshole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/travel/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Travel #  document.getElementById(&#34;freedomMenu&#34;).open = true; Immigration, Citizenship testing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</guid>
      <description>History #  Something to consider before going forward is that, assuming you&amp;rsquo;re from the US, the education you&amp;rsquo;ve received is likely very skewed both in what content is presented in the first place and how it&amp;rsquo;s presented. Unlike what most US education will tell you MLK did not magically end racism, not every US war has been just, and - no - our three branches of government are not working as intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/todo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/kids/</guid>
      <description> Ask HN: How can I make a “kid&amp;rsquo;s computer” today as good as an Apple II? The Bad Way To Teach Music to Babies  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</guid>
      <description>List of Ideas #   Post about sympy in math chapter, espically with sum and product increasingly online spaces that are custom-built are both spreading new ideas and preventing mono-cultures AND causing people to live in completely different realities and echo chambers Fuck consumerism, fuck hoarding, fuck status symbols, fuck plastic wrapped single use internationally shiped good, fuck single use electronics, fuck shitty electronics that are instant-ewaste Dangerous sounds - high voltage arc clicks, hard drive clicks, loud 60hz hum, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/p5test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/p5test/</guid>
      <description>P5 test #    function setup() { pixelDensity(1); frameRate(5); var canvas = createCanvas(document.getElementById(&#34;canvasContainer&#34;).offsetWidth, windowHeight/4); canvas.parent(&#39;canvasContainer&#39;); } function draw() { loadPixels(); let d = pixelDensity(); let fullImage = 4 * (width * d) * (height * d); for (let i = 0; i  canvas { position:relative; width: 100%; }  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/tokipona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/tokipona/</guid>
      <description>Toki Pona? #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/vr/</guid>
      <description>VR #  FBT #  https://www.crowdsupply.com/slimevr/slimevr-full-body-tracker
Vive trackers
April Tag
Kinect
Hand tracking &amp;amp; Haptics #  Walking around #  I created a Udon world to visualize infinite walking. The white lines are the limits of my play space.
The orange trail shows my movement in play space, and the blue trail shows my movement in world space.
(When I&amp;#39;m wireless I walk in circles, otherwise I walk in a ∞ shape) pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/webdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/webdev/</guid>
      <description>How to make OpGuides Better #  From 3b1b:
 Restructure things to go from Concrete to Abstract, not the other way around; Show patterns &amp;amp; examples, before going to the symbolic and abstract Go really esoteric and specific - it builds a loyal audience Do not start with definitions - let people think they could have come to those definitions themselves Start with motivating problems  source
  Don&amp;rsquo;t force the user to remember things if you can help it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</guid>
      <description>Philosophical Arguments #  [TODO]how to construct a phil argument
Not simply accepting &amp;ldquo;Because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is&amp;rdquo; #  I&amp;rsquo;m writing this at @292.78 on Day 132 of 12,020. I&amp;rsquo;m typing on a Dvorak, split, ortholinear keyboard in a markdown document using Arch Linux instead of M$ Word on Windows, and if you&amp;rsquo;d like you could view this document using DAT or IPFS or LBRY. I find music off the 12 tone scale interesting, and while I know 432 vs 440hz, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to open my 3rd eye, listening to microtonal or music made with just intonation is still something interesting to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Phil</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</guid>
      <description>OPINION          Before anything else, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out this is opinionated guides. Philosophy involves looking at the world around us and asking ourselves &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, then making arguments for how things should be different and what moral frameworks work best to come to conclusions that optimize for something like happiness or &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; in the world. Given that both morals and &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; are not absolutes, the best way for me to write this guide and actually be of service to you as a reader is to provide my opinion and talk about why I believe what believe both from a researched &amp;lsquo;here are the facts&amp;rsquo; sense and from a &amp;lsquo;here is the moral framework that, with these facts, brought me to this conclusion&amp;rsquo; sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Art and Design #  When you&amp;rsquo;re first learning art, every art class will beat a few core ideas into your head:
  Lines - The &amp;lsquo;structure&amp;rsquo; bits of the works, when you start making art, you&amp;rsquo;ll often start with the Line Art
  Shape - Structures that form out of lines, might appear 3D. These might be mathy, like squares, or organic, like an eye</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</guid>
      <description>Community #  Hopefully this isn&amp;rsquo;t a shock to anyone reading this, but I&amp;rsquo;m a furry.
owo uwu nuzzles rawr tehe So, I think I can share a little bit about why I joined the fandom, what being in a subculture community is like, and how some of those experiences have made me a better person and helped me be a part of or run successful online communities.
I hope that though this I can talk about what makes a community good or bad, what brings division, and what good rules for a healthy community look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>Consumerism #  Vega&amp;rsquo;s Maw, made for me by @NewtWolfdeer  Look, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of falling for the tricks used to get people to consume. To buy and buy more. A good sale, even on something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I previously wanted, still has a way of making my dumb lil&#39; human brain go &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;
The problem is that consumers can easily fall into traps that lead them to buy things for a stupid reasons, these include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/cooking/cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/cooking/cooking/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
My name is Vega, and I can&amp;rsquo;t cook, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be letting my friends take this one over.
Why you should take the time to be a functional adult: #  !&amp;gt; I had a few friends interested in fleshing this page out, but they got busy, lmk if you want to take it over or just sumbit a pull request ^-^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Letting Society Advance Though Art and Innovation #  This video from Tom Scott on YouTube is a very good intro to everything I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about on this page, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you&amp;rsquo;ve watched it so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat everything that he says here.
 What is Copyright? #  [TODO]
What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong With that? #  Watch a police officer admit to playing Taylor Swift to keep a video off YouTube (The Verge)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Apps for Art &amp;amp; Design #     Name &amp;amp; Link Description Demo/Screenshot          Pixlr phone version of https://pixlr.com    Fragment Add some neat geometric reflections into your art    Mirror Lab ^         Spiro, Tilemaker Makes some interesting tiled patterns    Easyposer, plenty of other alternatives Decent app for poseable character models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duties</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</guid>
      <description>Personal Duties #  Maintaining health #  Physical #  Working out #  Air quality #  Mental #  Socialized healthcare #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</guid>
      <description>Education #  Freedom of Information #  Curriculum Changes #    Basic Aid #  Sex Education #  Individualized, shared, and student led #  [TODO] Faster, lower standards #  Better testing #   Fuck Respondus And Proctorio #   The following is a (slightly edited) excerpt from an email I felt necessary to send to my professors at the start of the spring semester, 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  This chapter is broken up into sub sections, check the menu and it should have expanded!  Please Read This, for real   Automation Lanes Are Your Friend #  A lot of audio effects boil down to automating some simple parameter. Some times you may not actually need a dedicated effect and can instead get by with using Automation Lanes (YouTube, once upon a synth) in you Digital Audio Workstation (DAW)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/engineering/</guid>
      <description>Hey There! My name is Vega, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad you&amp;rsquo;re here!   #canvasContainer { display:absolute; position: fixed; height: 100%; z-index: -1; } #canvas { height: 100% width: 100% position:fixed; display: block; top: 0; left: 0; }     var canvas = document.querySelector(&#39;#backcanvas&#39;); fitToContainer(canvas); function fitToContainer(canvas){ // Make it visually fill the positioned parent canvas.style.width =&#39;100%&#39;; canvas.style.height=&#39;100%&#39;; // ...then set the internal size to match canvas.width = canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</guid>
      <description>Logical Fallacies (and a bit more) #  If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet for more than about a quarter of a second, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely been accused of a whole host of logical fallacies. Unfortunately, most people really don&amp;rsquo;t understand what they&amp;rsquo;re saying and often use a lot of these incorrectly. On the other hand, you also likely encounter politicians people using these fallacies on a regular basis as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to call them out on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foriegn</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</guid>
      <description>Foreign Involvement #   &#34; The Ministry of Peace concerns itself with war, the Ministry of Truth with lies, the Ministry of Love with torture and the Ministry of Plenty with starvation &#34;  - George Orwell, 1984   In the US, we have the Department of Defense - the DOD. Whenever I think about that name I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about that quote from 1984. The Department of Defense is primarily concerned with war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/generative-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/generative-art/</guid>
      <description>Generative Art #  This page is almost completely devoid of actual educational content. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to make the most complete list of generative art tools and libraries on the internet. Of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t actually make an exhaustive list and may be missing some of the newest tools and ideals, so please check out these other communities for more:  r/proceduralgeneration
r/generative
r/PlotterArt
  If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in generative music and sounds as well, you may want to check out The OpGuides page on Music Software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Labs</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</guid>
      <description>Idea Labs #  This page is heavily inspired by Idea Labs and Echo Chambers, which is Part 8 of The Story Of Us. It&amp;rsquo;s a long read, but worth the time- you could read just the one part; however, I think it will be harder to understand without the previous 7 parts as context. Rather than try to repeat here what is put so well there, I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend you read at least that section and come back here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure #  College Campuses Are Designed at Human-Scale. Our Cities Can Be Too. (StrongTowns.org)
Power #  Gravity-based batteries try to beat their chemical cousins with winches, weights, and mine shafts
Light Pollution #  International Dark Sky Association
Air Quality #  A paradigm shift to combat indoor respiratory infection
Networking (Mesh) #  Housing and Land #  Car-Free Neibhborhoods in the US
The People the Suburbs Were Built for Are Gone (Vice)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspirational Artists</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</guid>
      <description>Inspirational Artists #  Added a lot of minor improvements, like camera limits, subtle lighting, dust particles and more #gamedev #pixelart #screenshotsaturday pic.twitter.com/KmSYW3iHml
&amp;mdash; Luis Moreno Jimenez (@more8bit) September 2, 2017  Teenage Engineering&amp;#39;s OP-1 Synthesizer modules: pic.twitter.com/Jx5FEkiGK9
&amp;mdash; Shadow Drop - R&amp;amp;D (@ShadowDropDev) August 18, 2017  Some really cool pixel art gifs by Mark Ferrari
/// Caution some are NSFW /// https://twitter.com/halphelt (NSFW) https://twitter.com/Hushabye_Valley (NSFW-ish) https://twitter.com/koidrake (Like kinda lood I guess?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Instruments #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  If you&amp;rsquo;re going to be playing an instrument though a computer - and I mean either an instrument which makes it&amp;rsquo;s own noise like a guitar or a controller like a MIDI keyboard - you&amp;rsquo;ll want to adjust your audio buffer size as best you can. See Optimizing The Latency Of Your PC Audio Interface from Sound on Sound for more info about this, but generally just set your buffer size as low as you can until it starts to sound like it&amp;rsquo;s horribly broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</guid>
      <description>Published Interviews: #   Loial Otter Soatok Dreamseeker Cadey Ratio Kell Bengal Tax Badger Sex Positive Gaming  If you would like to be interviewed #  Well, first of all I&amp;rsquo;d like to know what makes you interesting - so shoot me a message or open an issue on GitHub, twitter, or where ever you can find me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</guid>
      <description>Labor and Compensation #  The Case For Banning Non-Competes (slowboring.com)
EU pushes for &amp;lsquo;right to disconnect&amp;rsquo; from work at home (dw.com)
Please Consider My Application to Give You Labor So I Can Stay Alive
Workplace Wellbeing Is a Scam (Tribune)
 Economic Inequality #   Source code (GPL v3), by Matt Korostoff Wage Theft is a Much Bigger Problem Than Other Forms of Theft—But Workers Remain Mostly Unprotected</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law And Order</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</guid>
      <description>Law Enforcment and Judgment #  Trial of educated peers
Criminal Rehabilitation #  end mandatory sentencing end bail no debters prision
 Divorce, Child Support #  Jury Duty #   Prosecutors &amp;amp; Public Defenders #    Police #  Illinois First State to Tell Police They Can&amp;rsquo;t Lie to Minors in Interrogations (NPR)
 Prisions #   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare Costs #  Why is life expectancy in the US lower than in other rich countries?
White House wins ruling on disclosing health care prices (AP)
Drugs #  Most drugs and prostitution should be legal at the age of 18. However, trafficking obviously not, and drugs must be sold by an individual with a licence to deal and said licence may be revoked if the product is sold with a false label or is tainted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixing &amp;amp; Mastering #  Mixers #  mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring #  https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and spotify
Mixing #  eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Mastering #  Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)
 Studio Monitors, Headphones, and Amps #  @Tirrelous on Twitter  Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of all the specs you might want to understad if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to buy headphones or studio monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the part where I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to explain how to read music or something boring like that. Really though, that&amp;rsquo;s not why you&amp;rsquo;re here. So let me start by giving you a bit of motivation. In a bit I&amp;rsquo;ll be going though how to use VCV Rack, a free (with paid addons, but those aren&amp;rsquo;t necessary) program for making music. But as we go though each bit is going to look so -basic- that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see the bigger picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware #  While you could make all of your music with just computer, you’ll probably want some tools that make your life as a musician easier and let you explore ideas faster. Like I said back in the Audio Effects Chapter  , in my experience, making music depends on a really quick brain to input device feedback loop. Being able to turn a physical knob and mash physical keys will often lead to better results if only because you’re able to try things both faster and by physically interacting with something that you may not have thought of otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software #   document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true; Audio Sources #     Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot          Various from SugarBytes I really like Consequence - Chord GroveboxFactory - Mod Matrix PolysynthGuitarist - Guitar Emulation, easy to programDrum Computer - Drum SynthObscurium - I don&amp;rsquo;t even know, but it&amp;rsquo;s cool.Cyclop - Neat Synth, good for bassEgoist - Weird audio stem re-groover?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpPhil Old</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</guid>
      <description>Old Version, needs migrated: #  Because you&amp;rsquo;re now somebody in the know about topics relating to technology and have a deeper understanding about issues that may effect the public, such as The FBI V Apple encryption case, Issues regrading internet speed and infrastructure, or The Government/NSA spying on people. There are plenty of issues that weather you like it or not you&amp;rsquo;re one of the few with enough information to truly understand and inform your peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources #  PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (Github) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses
Sample Packs &amp;amp; Wavetables #  Echo Sound Works Coda (~$30) - Wavetables &amp;amp; Serum presets. These wavetables are truly amazing.
Cool People #  https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/thePatchBay  - some shameless self promo, as this is my chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil and The Internet</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>The fight for the Internet is never ending. At the time of writing, Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell tried to tie anti §230 legislation to the $2000 stimulus checks, and my own Congress Critter, Ben Sasse (R,Nebraska), along with Jeff Merkley (D,Oregon) are trying to push though SISEA - the Stop Internet Sexual Exploitation Act, which on paper sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s doing good to stop the possibility of revenge porn. Unfortunately, they want to do this by requiring that all people in porn expressly give the site written consent with identity verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</guid>
      <description>Thank you #  If you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far I just want to say thank you. We need more people to really consider how ethics, politics, and copyright shape the world around us with technology and art as we design it and proceed with it. DeepFakes, Automated driving, and even more mass online censorship are issues we&amp;rsquo;re only going to face more with time and it&amp;rsquo;s people like you who are going to help make sure we take the best path we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil, Misc</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</guid>
      <description>Animal Rights (Industrial Scale Slaughter) #  Organ donation #  Tech can&amp;rsquo;t solve all your problems #  Human problems need human solutions
Guns #                  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion #  [TODO] [TODO] America Without God: As Religious Faith Has Declined, Ideological Intensity Has Risen 
The engineering community is strangely divided, the &amp;lsquo;old guard&amp;rsquo; is actually relatively conservative and professional, but as time has moved forward it&amp;rsquo;s quite the opposite. Unsurprisingly, this correlates with religion as well. The main way this plays into politics is a general hard stance for the separation of church and state. This is in part due to a past of religiously motivated legislation negatively impacting copyright law, but also just generally an understood ideal that is beneficial to democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequencing and MIDI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing &amp;amp; Midi #  This chapter only goes over the basics of MIDI. Because MIDI is so important to music production I&amp;rsquo;ll dive much deeper into the details of MIDI in Chapter 6½ - MIDI in Detail Sequencing #  The definition of a sequence is pretty obvious, but don&amp;rsquo;t be misled by the name- a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; is not always just a list of notes to be played one after the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</guid>
      <description>Sex #  In an ideal world human kind would be driven forward by more than the initiate desire to reproduce and bone. But, we don&amp;rsquo;t live in an ideal world and people like to have fun and feel good. (consensual) Sex is fun and feels good- so it should not be looked down on. Flirting, hooking up, being horny: They&amp;rsquo;re all natural and good. Unfortunately, today it seems Everyone is Beautiful and No One is Horny</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise #  Samples #  A snippet of a .wav file open in audacity  A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. The easiest to explain is what is usually meant by sample: a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: #   Don&amp;rsquo;t undervalue just sitting down and listening to music, trying to figure out what parts you enjoy and thinking about how it compares to what you&amp;rsquo;ve made, what you think you should change to sound better.
Theory #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest. I can&amp;rsquo;t read music and I don&amp;rsquo;t know scales. Why, then, would I in any way think I&amp;rsquo;m qualified to write anything about music?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</guid>
      <description>UI and UX #  Principals of UI, A Thread (zensaiyuki@mastodon.social)
Gallery of Fantasy UI design from Movies and TV shows
Responsiveness #  Source Power Users #  User power, not power users: htop and its design philosophy
Typography #  Practical Typography Textbook
Datalegeya Font
Data Visualization #  https://bids.github.io/colormap/
Website Design #  Learn CSS by Google Developers
Butalist Web Design, by David Copeland
motherfuckingwebsite.com, bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com, thebestmotherfuckingwebsite.website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/video/</guid>
      <description>Video &amp;amp; Streaming #   Before anythinge else, I need to crush some hopes and dreams:
You absolutely should not expect your YouTube or Twitch channel to make it big. Even if you put in the work, invest in good eqipment, and make cool content regularly, and promote the shit out of yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s still a game of luck on if you can go viral and if you can retain any viewership whatsoever after doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</guid>
      <description>Elections &amp;amp; Voting #  I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;lsquo;murican, so this will be US centric, that said, the arguments here could likely be applied universally Issue 1: FPTP Voting Sucks #  lower standards of removal, ranked, transparency Budget voting
  Issue 2: Voters are really, really stupid #  voting based on if they like the person, how he/she looks, single issue voting
Issue 3: Two is the unfriendliest number #  Issue 4: Gerrymandering, Fraud, and Astroturfing #      [TODO] Comment on Citizen&amp;rsquo;s United</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
