<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/community/</guid>
      <description>Ⅰ - Community #  The only way to be successful in this journey is to make friends along the way. Some of this gets really, really difficult. You will get stuck. Having friends to help makes it possible. Find group chats on telegram, join IRC channels, get on some forums, and ask questions on Reddit. Working with people is a lot more fun and you&amp;rsquo;ll learn so much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I pay to go to college?</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/whydidipay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/whydidipay/</guid>
      <description>Post originally published March 22 of 2021, date above represents most recent edit The Nebraska Union at UNL, photo by ensign_beedrill, CC BY-SA 2.0, via Wikimedia Commons I am currently a student at the University of Nebraska - Lincoln, where I study Computer and Electrical Engineering as a dual major. I have a serious passion for both of these subjects, which is why I am so incredibly frustrated at how negative my experience at UNL has been, especially in the classes that directly relate to my major.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not a Digital Native, and Neither Are You</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/digital-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/digital-native/</guid>
      <description>The term digital native describes a young person who has grown up in the digital age, in close contact with computers, the Internet, and video game consoles, and later mobile phones, social media, and tablets. The term is often used to refer to millennials, Generation Z, and Generation Alpha; the latter two are sometimes described as distinct &amp;ldquo;neo-digital natives&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; digital natives, or &amp;ldquo;digital integrators&amp;rdquo;.  &amp;lsquo;Digital Native&amp;rsquo; on Wikipedia You know how every headline about Millennials or Gen Z is &amp;ldquo;Gen ___ has killed ___&amp;rdquo; and it makes everyone from those generations want collectively bang their heads into a desk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nebraksa LR107 - Stupdity Abound</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</guid>
      <description>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT RESOLVED BY THE MEMBERS OF THE ONE HUNDRED SEVENTH LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA, FIRST SESSION:
 That we hereby reaffirm our solemn oaths of office by expressing a firm resolution to maintain and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Nebraska against every act of aggression whether foreign or domestic, including every act of unconstitutional abuse of power arising from the state or federal government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ternary Logic</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</guid>
      <description>This paper was written for CSCE-430, Computer Architecture at University Of Nebraska - Lincoln in Spring of 2021.
This in-page view isn&amp;rsquo;t all that great, so feel free to download the pdf directly.
If you would like to read the refrenced papers, I reccomend using Sci-Hub with a VPN on, as the academic publishers putting up paywalls as barriers to science can go fuck themselves.
  #the-canvas { border: 1px solid black; direction: ltr; width: 100%; height: auto; } #paginator{ text-align: center; margin-bottom: 10px; }  Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page:  /     window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Products I Wish Existed</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</guid>
      <description>Most of these things probably exist. For many, it&amp;rsquo;s just that they don&amp;rsquo;t exist at a practical price point.  Without further ado, In no particular order
  A not garbage, not phone based, IR camera that doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost a bajillion dollars
Yes. I know the FLIR and SEEK Thermal cameras are a thing, but both have their share of software problems or hardware incompatibilities. Most of all, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to hope that their app keeps working with my phone at risk of a $250 paper weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chains</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/chains/</guid>
      <description>My name is Vega. I have to tell myself that a lot, reminding myself of who I am.
I know that may sound weird, but, if it wen&amp;rsquo;t already obvious, it isn&amp;rsquo;t my legal name. (yet.)
Despite my best efforts, my parents still call me by my &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; name. I&amp;rsquo;m hesitant to call it a dead name, as I&amp;rsquo;m not trans. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s the same or that it&amp;rsquo;s fair to claim that it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirrors of Opal</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/mirrorsofopal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/mirrorsofopal/</guid>
      <description>When I looked into the mirror this morning, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure who I was looking at. Is that me? Is that really what I look like now? Has this years long separation from reality caused me to not recognize my own face, or would it have happened anyway- a side effect of growing older.
 If you saw me, would you even recognize me? Or am I the ship of Theseus, digested by the carnivore that we call time, now fertilizer for someone you&amp;rsquo;ve never met?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Make OpGuides</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/howimakeopguides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/howimakeopguides/</guid>
      <description>History #  Before I can get into how OpGuides works now, I need to provide some history so that you can learn from my mistakes.
The first iteration of OpGuides was OpinionatedEngineering.md. A single markdown file so long that the scroll bar was hard to grab. It was meant to be viewed and distributed not as a website, but as a file to be opened with https://typora.io (so that the html and everything rendered- though in theory any markdown editor would do)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time lapse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</guid>
      <description>Super brief post about one of the more fun projects I setup recently: a lil&#39; time lapse script
#!/bin/bash CAM=$(v4l2-ctl --list-devices | grep C920 -A 1 | grep /dev | awk &#39;{$1=$1};1&#39;) #Uncomment the next line to verify it&#39;s using the correct device #echo $CAM ffmpeg -f video4linux2 -s 1920x1080 -i $CAM -ss 0:0:2 -frames 1 &amp;quot;/mnt/data/lapse/tl$(date +&amp;quot;%Y-%m-%d_%H-%M-%S&amp;quot;).jpg&amp;quot; I have multiple cameras on my system, but only wanted output from the better one, the C920.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Down!</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</guid>
      <description>I use VCV Rack a lot. I normally use it on Windows as running VSTs in Linux is still a bit of a PITA and If I&amp;rsquo;m going to make music I want to have access to all of my tools. However, I still want to be able to use VCV on Linux for processing guitar when taking breaks from working on other things without having to reboot over to Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soatok</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Soatok Dreamseeker #  12/3/2020
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Soatok. Your blog at https://soatok.blog shows that you&amp;rsquo;re a furry crypto nerd, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to hear how you&amp;rsquo;d put it, so, to get started, can you describe yourself?
Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m asked, I usually say something to the effect of, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a security engineer with a dhole fursona that sometimes writes about cryptography on my furry blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xx80</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</guid>
      <description>The year is 198x. #  I stare at my amber terminal. Hexadecimal fills my screen and my mind has become lost in the flow of 6502 assembly, as I hand optimize the code flow.
I&amp;rsquo;m interupted when I recieve a message from my friend, _Maverik, he&amp;rsquo;s excited about the ground breaking CGI in Tron.
 Nostalgia is a weird feeling. We can forget when things happened, and misttribute things to entirely different decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti Consumer</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</guid>
      <description>As I walked to my car after class I could smell the ashes of a cigarette and hear the echos of a train scraping on its tracks. The cool foggy air held still beams of light. It looked like a scene from Blade runner, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like the Android&amp;rsquo;s of it&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, lusting after something to make me feel alive.
The drive home was mentally taxing. The fog so dense that cars ahead seemed to be balls of light floating in the distance and keeping sight of the lines to stay in my lane took a constant effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loial</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Loial Otter #  9/23/2018
Introduction:
I&amp;rsquo;m Matthew or LoialOtter, a crazy person up in western Canada who likes to make stuff. I work at Kron Technology as an engineer mainly in FPGA, electronics design and hardware design.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have any credentials except a certificate in baking and pastry arts. I&amp;rsquo;m self-taught mostly due to not being ever able to afford going to school. I suggest others do when the have the opportunity but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolutely required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</guid>
      <description>3D Modeling, Sculpting, Painting, Shading, and Rendering #  This chapter will be using various programs, not all of which are free. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to recommend things that are open source if I can, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep the cost down as much as possible. You definitely can do everything in this chapter for free, just be aware that without some of the paid tools it may be substantially harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</guid>
      <description>Photography #  [TODO]
This Guy Flipped an Element in an Old Lens and Got ‘Magic’ Bokeh (PetaPixel)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/24-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/24-/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24 - #  This chapter has been merged with another, leaving the space open for now, I&amp;rsquo;ll put something else here&amp;hellip;
Maybe reverse engineering? This would seem a bit out of place though. I might need to do some rearranging of chapters 26-34 anyway https://github.com/mytechnotalent/Reverse-Engineering
If you&#39;re reading this, you have javascript off.
 document.querySelector(&#34;body  main  div  article  div  p&#34;).innerText = &#34;If you can read this you have JavaScript on&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/a3-bom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/a3-bom/</guid>
      <description>Appendix C - BOM #  As the guide isn&amp;rsquo;t anywhere near a usable state yet, this page should be ignored for the most part. OpGuides is free. Unfortunately all the tools and programs you&amp;rsquo;ll need to follow along aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily. While you probably could do everything in this guide without getting the things in this Bill OF Materials (BOM) it will massively help to have it.
I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to keep the cost as low as possible though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 22 - Intro to Angry Pixies #  A simple guide to electronic components (YouTube)
The Tools of the Trade #  Building, fixing, and analyzing circuitry requires the use of a few tools and appliances. While there are many more than those listed here, these are the most important ones and should be all you need for most even very advanced applications.
The Multimeter #   note, the above video uses U=IR instead of V=IR like &amp;lsquo;normal&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits2/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 23 - Circuits &amp;amp; Semiconductors #  When I was a kid I thought about circuits as being alive, like Cells at Work!, only little electrons going around busily keeping the heart of my toy working instead of anthropomorphic red blood cells working in the human body.
Now, as an adult - and a computer and electrical engineer at that - I still find this thought endearing. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve now come to see the physics and art of electronics to be even more beautiful when their true nature is really understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/digitallogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/digitallogic/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24 - Digital Logic #     Binary (0b) Hex (0x) Decimal     0000 0 0   0001 1 1   0010 2 2   0011 3 3   0100 4 4   0101 5 5   0110 6 6   0111 6 7   1000 8 8   1001 9 9   1010 A 10   1011 B 11   1100 C 12   1101 D 13   1110 E 14   1111 F 15      lineart by https://merveilles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/embedded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/embedded/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 25 - Embedded Systems #  [TODO]
What is an Embedded System? #  [TODO] need source PWM, SPI, I2C, What&amp;rsquo;s going on?! #  Driving a PAL TV over RF thanks to PWM harmonics (Hackaday)
Playing around - Hello World and blink #  Making an Embedded System project - 1 - Humidity Sensor #  Making an Embedded System project - 2 - MIDI Controller (with piezzo) #  Making an Embedded System project - 3 - Stepper Motor Music #  adapted from floppy drives, but less expensive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/pcb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/pcb/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 26 - Let&amp;rsquo;s make our own PCB #  [TODO]
 Make it work Make it not emit a ton of RF or go to shit when around it (everything is an antenna) Make it pretty  ref that weird russian autorouter as limits on this   Make it repairable Know when to do a PCB or a Perma-Proto Assuming parts will only be available for so long  First things first, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be using Kicad, so you&amp;rsquo;ll want to go grab that from the repos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/comparch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/comparch/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 29 - Let&amp;rsquo;s make our own CPU #  This Chapter will be split into three parts:Part 1, understanding the interval workings of a CPU. This is effectively just a computer architecture class, and will be by far the largest section.Part 2, making that CPU on an FPGA.Part 3, making that CPU do something. [TODO] http://www.lighterra.com/papers/modernmicroprocessors/
[TODO] A Density Metric for Semiconductor Technology - past nm for sizing
Part 1: Computer Architecture #  Motivation: #   Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/compileassemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/compileassemble/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 27 - Compilers and Assemblers #  https://lee.earth/til/compiling-c-code-a-step-by-step-guide/
[TODO] Better Firmware with LLVM/Clang
Common Flags and When to Use them #   These flags are not universal, instead they&amp;rsquo;re from GCC. GCC and Clang are the big two compilers you&amp;rsquo;ll see a lot and these flags should be mostly the same between the two. Of course, there are many, many other compilers, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with the common stuff</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/fpga1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/fpga1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 28 - Let&amp;rsquo;s try out programmable logic #  Before we get started, please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve read Chapter 24 - Digital Logic  Simulation of an Intel 4004 in TICS (The Integrated Circuit Simulator) a (abandoned?) WIP by Oni, Download the interpreter here, the repo has pleanty of examples.
Something a bit less cool but similar is https://github.com/martinkirsche/wired-logic
 [TODO]
Finite State Machines, VHDL, Verilog, FPGA &amp;amp; CPLD internals</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/engineering/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, #  My name is Vega. I know there are plenty of tutorials and ways to learn online be it on YouTube, SkillShare, or online classes provided for free by various universities. The difference here is there is no content you&amp;rsquo;ll never use, it&amp;rsquo;s more entertaining than a text book, and there&amp;rsquo;s lots of bias as a result of personal experience. My views of things like what programming languages are bad or what hardware you should buy to learn on will be expressed directly and bluntly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/howtolearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/howtolearn/</guid>
      <description>Ⅱ - Learn how to learn #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep this short and sweet: Nobody learns (effectively) by being shown what to do. You can watch hundreds of hours of people playing guitar, even explaining how they do it, but you wont be able to randomly pick one up and play if you never have before. Furthermore, as much as you can learn from direct reading and instruction, it has it&amp;rsquo;s place and limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/arch/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 - Installing Arch Linux #   Some Background #  Unlike Windows or Mac which are primarily differentiated by versions (Windows XP, Vista, 7, 10&amp;hellip;), Linux has two important things to look out for:
 The distribution name (Arch, Ubuntu, Mint, Debian, etc.) Kernel version number (5.12 last time this page was updated)  So, what do each of these mean?
Well, Linux is actually just the name of the underlying &amp;lsquo;core&amp;rsquo; of the system, known as the kernel, as such, there are literally thousands of Linux variations or &amp;lsquo;distributions&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/firstgoal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/firstgoal/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 - The first goal #  Art by @monoxromatik Every journey needs a place to start, and while many may like to start slow I think a head first approach is best. So that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we&amp;rsquo;re gonna do. The very first thing we&amp;rsquo;re going to do is install a new Operating System (OS)(1) on your computer. This is a pretty involved process. It will require you to Repartition(2) your drive, change settings in your BIOS or UEFI(3), and install a new Bootloader(4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/git/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5½ - Git. #  ./missing-semester - Version Control  The above link does a better job of covering the vast majority of what I&amp;rsquo;d say than I could hope to put here. Just check it out. But do come back here! Oh, hai! Welcome back.
So, a lot of people conflate Git and Github, the largest git cloud service on the internet. This isn&amp;rsquo;t totally without out reason: Github is actually super nice to use, and is often the only way a lot of people use git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3 - Into The Hardware #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  One of the nifty things about Linux is you don&amp;rsquo;t need to install extra software to check out the deeper parts of your hardware. While on windows you might need a tool like CPU-Z to look at information about the CPU on Linux you can do it out of the box.
Before we get started, let&amp;rsquo;s just look into abyss, hopefully when we&amp;rsquo;re done you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to recognize everything in this picture:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/architectures/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3½ - Architectures #  [TODO]
From the README.md file at https://github.com/radareorg/radare2
 Architectures #  i386, x86-64, ARM, MIPS, PowerPC, SPARC, RISC-V, SH, m68k, m680x, AVR, XAP, System Z, XCore, CR16, HPPA, ARC, Blackfin, Z80, H8/300, V810, V850, CRIS, XAP, PIC, LM32, 8051, 6502, i4004, i8080, Propeller, Tricore, CHIP-8, LH5801, T8200, GameBoy, SNES, SPC700, MSP430, Xtensa, NIOS II, Java, Dalvik, WebAssembly, MSIL, EBC, TMS320 (c54x, c55x, c55+, c66), Hexagon, Brainfuck, Malbolge, whitespace, DCPU16, LANAI, MCORE, mcs96, RSP, SuperH-4, VAX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/buying/</guid>
      <description>10 - How to Know What to Buy #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  [TODO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cooling/</guid>
      <description>8 - Cooling #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  Blower, air flow vs static pressure, fan size liquid, heat pipes, pwm vs DC control</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cpu/</guid>
      <description>1 - The CPU #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  These are CPUS or Central Processing Units. They&amp;rsquo;re the beating heart of your computer, doing the day-to-day number crunching. The rectangular one of one of the first CPU&amp;rsquo;s in the lineage leading up to CPU&amp;rsquo;s like the ones used in desktop&amp;rsquo;s today, with further successors shown in order from top left to the bottom right. The metal-capped one at the bottom right, while old, is visually quite representative of a modern desktop CPU, though the CPUs in a laptop or smart phone do look quite different still.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/gpu/</guid>
      <description>4 - Graphics Acceleration #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;   A wide array of graphics cards spanning multiple generations. The majority pictured are made by Nvidia
 Most &amp;lsquo;beefier&amp;rsquo; systems have a graphics card, but (almost) every computer that can output a video signal has dedicated graphics processing of some sort. For many lower end or low power systems (especially laptops) this graphics processing unit, or GPU, is built into the CPU and uses the systems same ram for video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/legacy/</guid>
      <description>11 - Legacy Hardware &amp;amp; e-waste #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  [TODO] Parallel, Serial, Tape, CD, gameport</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/motherboard/</guid>
      <description>3 - The Motherboard #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  This is an older motherboard, but still new enough to have modern parts. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by looking at the the most obvious physical features and move to smaller things from there.
The most obvious thing to point out is the size of the motherboard. This is a mATX motherboard, which is considered the normal size for most systems. Most gaming or DIY computers will use full size ATX motherboards, which look very similar but are a bit longer vertically, allowing for more expansion slots - those horizontal black bars - among other features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/network/</guid>
      <description>6 - Network Interfaces #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;   Pictured here are three Network Interface cards or NICs. The three on the left are for WiFi (though some of this form factor may include bluetooth as well) while the one on the right has an ethernet port for wired access. Most computer&amp;rsquo;s will not have a separate card for the wired interface though, as most motherboard&amp;rsquo;s have a wired network interface built in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/peripherals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/peripherals/</guid>
      <description>9 - Peripherals #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  USB #  [TODO] all the annoyences of USB standards
USB3: why it&amp;rsquo;s a bit harder than USB2
Thunderbolt, Firewire, PS-2? #  Keyboards #  HID or Human Interface Device, is the standard over which most mice, keyboards, and game controllers talk to the computer. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s also a pretty lame standard. You can&amp;rsquo;t just input arbitrary Unicode or send fancy data back to the keyboard to control fancy RGB lights, because of this it&amp;rsquo;s common to need extra drivers per device</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/power/</guid>
      <description>7 - Power Supply #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  The Power Supply Unit or PSU does what you think. It takes power from the wall and turns it into power for the computer. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the chapter on voltage and current, so I&amp;rsquo;ll spare some of the details, but effectively you want a power supply that can deliver plenty of power and that has clean power. A given power supply usually has a rating like &amp;lsquo;500w&amp;rsquo; for 500 watts, but this is usually a bad indicator, as they could be referring to multiple things- you see a desktop power supply usually outputs multiple voltages (-12, +12, +5, +3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/ram/</guid>
      <description>2 - RAM #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;  This is RAM or Random Access Memory. The above two sticks are the normal sized used in desktop PCs, this form factor is called a DIM while the bottom two are from laptops and are called SO-DIMS, the placement of the notch is an indicator of the generation of RAM, with nearly all modern ram being a consecutive generation of the DDR standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/storage/</guid>
      <description>5 - Storage #   document.getElementById(&#34;hardwareMenu&#34;).open = true;   Pictured here are 3 hard drives, 2 of which are &amp;lsquo;full size&amp;rsquo; at 3.5&amp;quot; and the the other a &amp;lsquo;laptop drive&amp;rsquo; at 2.5&amp;quot;, the left most hard drive has been opened up, which has certainly ruined it as dust has gotten in. Below the smaller Hard drive is an NVMe ssd, a micro sd card, and a flash drive. All of which are examples of solid state storage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/howwework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/howwework/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5 - Working on how we work #  The Terminal #  In the world of programming, embedded development, and electrical debugging you will inevitably need to understand how to use a terminal/command line at some point. While the text only interface can look intimidating, it has some clear advantages. Namely it&amp;rsquo;s significantly faster to use the cli or &amp;lsquo;command line interface&amp;rsquo; version of many tools. Because of the nature of this guide you will be using the terminal frequently, so for convince sake information on using it effectively has been moved to Appendix A, I highly recommend you read though it after you finish this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxdirtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxdirtree/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4 - Getting Rooted In Linux #  We&amp;rsquo;ve been using file in /proc and /dev throughout this, but we never really looked to see what else is in there. Let&amp;rsquo;s do that.
go ahead and open up a terminal and run
1 2 3 4 5  ╭─vega@lyrae ~ ╰─➤ cd /dev ╭─vega@lyrae /dev ╰─➤ ls [Very, Very Long Output here]   Alright, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxshell/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 1 - Using the Linux Shell #  ./missing-semester - The Shell
./missing-semester - Shell Tools and Scripting
./missing-semester - Data Wrangling
What The Shell? #  Okay, first question you probably have after I&amp;rsquo;ve been using them interchangebly &amp;lsquo;What is a Shell and is it different from a terminal?&amp;rsquo;
Yes, they&amp;rsquo;re different, but before I talk about the shell it&amp;rsquo;s easier to talk about the Terminal.
The Terminal is a piece of hardware, or, rather was a piece of hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/3dprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/3dprint/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 34 - 3D printing, CNC, and making things #  34.1 - Basic making #  Wood working #  Safety #  Cool projects #  Lichtenberg Figure Table (imgur)
Epoxy Inlay and Rustic Compass Butcher Block Countertops (imgur) (YouTube)
Wood Tables Embedded with Photoluminescent Resin (Mike Warren)
Metal Working #  Safety #  34.2 - CNC, 3D, Lasers, &amp;amp; Plotting #  Plotting #  Lasters #  3D Printing #  From personal experiance, I can tell you the really cheap, like sub $200 printers, are mostly shit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/hamradio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/hamradio/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 35 - Ham Radio #  TODO: https://github.com/jopohl/urh
&amp;lsquo;137Mhz&amp;rsquo; by u/CashewHut LORA
2.4Ghz patch antenna
electronically tunable filters
National Radio Quiet Zone (Wikipedia)
https://newhams.info/2017/02/17/rf-connector-types/
question of the day:
Analog TV is shut down in the US, right? so all the over-the-air TV is digital. And existing analog OTA frequencies are getting repurposed to other uses... so what am I seeing on UHF channel 60? it&amp;#39;s got way more structure than the noise everywhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/history/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 36 - History #  BBS and Tildie Sites #  tilde.town: A social network over SSH
Tilde.club
Other Tilde Services?
 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mother_of_All_Demos
Adam Savage&amp;rsquo;s Computer History Collection! (Youtube)
Preserving data #  https://media.ccc.de/v/31c3_-_6373_-_en_-_saal_6_-_201412291600_-_the_only_thing_we_know_about_cyberspace_is_that_its_640x480_-_olia_lialina#t=3641
Preserving hardware #  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delay_line_memory
http://www.vcfed.org/forum/forum.php
https://skilldrick.github.io/easy6502/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/algebra/</guid>
      <description>1 - Algebra #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  This section is a tad bit misnamed, as instead of covering just Algebra I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering most things you&amp;rsquo;d learn in a high school Algebra class along side it, plus probably a bit extra.  Number Systems #  To get started, let&amp;rsquo;s look at &amp;lsquo;Number Systems&amp;rsquo;. Essentially, there are a variety of &amp;lsquo;types&amp;rsquo; of numbers, rather than get all philosophical let&amp;rsquo;s just dive in and I think you&amp;rsquo;ll get the gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/calc/</guid>
      <description>4 - Calculus #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Introduction To Calculus With Derivatives (adit.io)
[] TODO limits before video
Below is a 12 video series that totals about 3.25 hours.   [The Exponential Function is a Miracle (Mark Dominus)](</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/diffeq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/diffeq/</guid>
      <description>5 - Differential Equations #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Below is a 5 video series that totals about 1.5 hours.   #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/geometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/geometry/</guid>
      <description>3 - Geometry and Trigonometry #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Geometry #  Notation #  ∥, ⊥,
Trigonometry #   Learning Trig playlist on YouTube by &amp;lsquo;The Organic Chemistry Tutor&amp;rsquo;
Notation #  3½ - Topology #        But, this is supposed to be about engineering, so why do we need it?
[TODO] topology optimization and generative design
3¾ - Non-Euclidian Spaces #   Fractals #    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/linalg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/linalg/</guid>
      <description>6 - Matrix Theory / Linear Algebra #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Below is a 15 video series that totals a bit under 3 hours.   Matricies, Diagrammatically
Linear Algebra - Jim Hefferson
Linear Algebra and Applications: An Inquiry-Based Approach</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/logic/</guid>
      <description>2 - Discrete Math &amp;amp; Logic #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  http://discrete.openmathbooks.org/dmoi3/
Math For Programmers (pdf)  Notation #  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mathematic_operators
Logic #  Many Valued Logic #  Fuzzy Logic #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/math/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6 - Math #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  This section of OpGuides is devided into sub sections for easier reading! Just click the little arrow next to the heading to see the full list of chapters
As with all of OpGuides, please skip around as necessary. I suspect the start of this math chapter will be stuff many readers already know, especially those currently in college.
     The next few chapters are, regrettably, necessary for developing your knack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/numanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/numanalysis/</guid>
      <description>7 - Numerical Analysis #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;   Bisection Method
Newton&amp;rsquo;s Method
Secant Method
Lagrange Polynomial
Divided Differences
Linear Interpolation, Bilinear Interpolation, Bicubic Interpolation, Spatial Interpolation
Cubic Spline
Numerical Differentiation
Trapezoidal Rule
Simpson&amp;rsquo;s Rule
Romberg Integration
Monte Carlo Method - Algorithm Archive
Condition Number
Least Squares
The Bernstein Basis (Mutual Information, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/probability/</guid>
      <description>10 - Probability/Stats #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Why, where are these used, etc.
bring up music things, part failure rates, tollerences, etc.
Basics #  For the following I&amp;rsquo;ll be using a dice roll example, where the events are the total of two die. The Sample Space of this is
$ S = {2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12}$
Note, that 1 isn&amp;rsquo;t possible as the lowest is both die being &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/settheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/settheory/</guid>
      <description>9 - Set Theory #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;   #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/sigandsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/sigandsys/</guid>
      <description>8 - Signals &amp;amp; Systems #   document.getElementById(&#34;mathMenu&#34;).open = true;  Below is a 54 video series that totals around 13 hours   MIT Signals and Systems Lectures (YouTube)
But, if you&amp;rsquo;d rather learn out of a textbook, if you go looking online you might just be able to stumble upon a 100% super-duper legal way to obtain Alan V. Oppenheim, Alan S. Willsky, with S. Hamid-Signals and Systems with ISBN 978-0138147570 published by Prentice Hall which is now a subsidiary of Pearson, a textbook publisher which can, and this is 100% true, go fuck themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/units/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/units/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6½ - Units #   [TODO] - weird units coming up: moles, ferads, light years, pascals, radians+, electron mass, big/small metric units, flops, decades, etc.
Should probably have a metric table too (nano = 10^-9 etc.)
  By 42CrMo4 and Christoph Päper English units of Length, CC BY-SA 4.0   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 31½ - &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo; #  Some people will tell you the cloud is the future, that someday everybody will rent computational power from a handful of services like AWS.
These people are nuts.
The cloud is just someone eles&amp;rsquo;s computer. Unless your business is going though a period of extreme growth it makes no sense to use a cloud provider like AWS or Azure. It does make plenty of sense to buy a VPS (Virtual Private Server) for hosting a website or game server or a personal website like this one, but at scale?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/databases/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 32 - Databases #  [TODO] Start with comparison to spread sheet, explaining &amp;lsquo;NoSQL&amp;rsquo; Vs &amp;lsquo;SQL&amp;rsquo; and that this is Relational vs Non-Relational
[TODO] explain CRUD
CRUD #  Create, Read, Update, Delete
SQL #  This is Opinionated Guides, so let me be clear, I really, really hate SQL. I don&amp;rsquo;t like OOP in general, and SQL is sorta like object orientation taken further. Add onto this a mostly shit syntax, like, JOINs are objectively weird to read, write, and understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/networking/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 30 - Networking #  [TODO] Add follow along making a network stack
[TODO] https://iximiuz.com/en/posts/computer-networking-101/
Basics #  Nodes
These are all the points in the network. There are terminal nodes and intermediate nodes.
Terminal nodes are things like your phone, laptop, desktop, and other user-facing devices, as well as servers, like would be used for hosting games or websites.
Intermediate nodes, are things that are internal to the network: Things like modems, hubs, switches, routers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 33½ - Your Guide to Privacy #   &#34; Arguing that you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the right to privacy because you have nothing to hide is no different than saying you don&amp;rsquo;t care about free speech because you have nothing to say. &#34;  - Edward Snowden, in his Reddit AMA   Privacy online is a joke. No matter what you do, you&amp;rsquo;re still going to be tracked so much that advertisers and the big tech companies (Facebook, Google, Microsoft, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/security/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 33 - Security &amp;amp; Exploitation #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume at least some prior knowledge here, if you want a quick intro, I recommend going through ./missing-semester-Security so that we can all be on the same page.  Often when we think about Exploitation, better known as hacking, we conjure images of a more-punk-than-cyber cyberpunk person clicking away wildly on a keyboard as code flies by, like the 1995 movie, Hackers, and to some extent this isn&amp;rsquo;t wrong, as one look around the floor at DefCon, will show you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/servers/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 31 - Servers! #  First of all, let&amp;rsquo;s demystify the servers, they are not something to be afraid of &amp;hellip; they are just normal computers that execute processes, the main difference is that these computers do not have a direct interface, that is: there is no need for them to have peripherals (most of the time) since they only SERVE resources for other needs.
A good example of a server is this one, in which you are reading this, the only function of the server where this content is hosted is to provide it, nothing more and nothing less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/chem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/chem/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 8 - Chemistry #  This chapter is more or less on hold while I prioritize adding the content I&amp;rsquo;m more familiar with, if you&amp;rsquo;d like, feel free to submit a PR to flesh this section out. Unfortunately my chemistry education was pretty &amp;lsquo;meh&amp;rsquo;, and I never actually made it to Organic Chem. I have CrashCourse&amp;rsquo;s Chemistry and Organic Chemistry videos on YouTube on my &amp;lsquo;To Watch&amp;rsquo; list though. Obviously I don&amp;rsquo;t know if they&amp;rsquo;re any good, but maybe they&amp;rsquo;d be a decent place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/othersubjects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/othersubjects/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 9 - &amp;lsquo;The Rest&amp;rsquo; #  English #  I&amp;rsquo;m monolingual. I got just enough Spanish in high school to graduate and never looked back. Unfortunately for those that don&amp;rsquo;t speak English as a first language, the internet has developed in such a way that English is basically the go-to language online.
Okay, so, some context is necessary here. Historically, England sorta gave the whole &amp;ldquo;World Domination&amp;rdquo; thing a shot as colonialism and in the process spread English to, well, everywhere?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/physics/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7 - Physics #  This is still a dumping ground for things I want to write about later, nothing of substance is here yet, sorry about that ╮(─▽─)╭ [TODO] speed vs Velocity vs Acceleration, clasicall vs realative
Radiocarbon dating (Wikipedia)
Cosmic Microwave Background (Wikipedia)
Natural nuclear fission reactor (Wikipedia)
How Kodak Exposed The Atomic Bomb (YouTube, Veritasium)
Seeing the invisible: Event displays in particle physics
Building a Vortex Tube (This Old Tony, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/aiml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/aiml/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 21 - Fine, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about AI #  This chapter is very much a work in progress, and is really more of just a list of topics despite how much content there appears to be. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to have code examples under each concept as well, as otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s like reading a fucking math textbook from hell. [TODO] https://www.asimovinstitute.org/author/fjodorvanveen/
Machine Learning? #  You&amp;rsquo;ve used it today. ML is used for search engines, social media feed order (the almighty Algorithm), and predictive text systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 14 - Discrete Math, Algorithms, Data Structures, and Not Sucking at Programming ™* #  [TODO] Directed Acyclic Graphs
[TODO] Finite State Machines
[TODO] e-graphs? https://egraphs-good.github.io
[TODO] http://courses.csail.mit.edu/6.851/
[TODO] &amp;lsquo;Tree Traversal&amp;rsquo; on Algorithm Archive
*With some complexity analysis too.
[TODO]
https://www.mattkeeter.com/blog/2021-03-01-happen/
[TODO] I also have discreete math in the chapter 11, math&amp;hellip; not sure what do do about this&amp;hellip;
Truth tables, binary, logical equlivencies, propositional logic,
Sets, functions, relations, recurrence, induction, combonation, graphs, isomorphsm,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/bigprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/bigprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 15 - Writing a larger program #  From https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/development.html
  Prototype before polishing. Get it working before optimizing it. Separate policy from mechanism, separate interfaces from engines. Write simple modular parts connected by clean interfaces. Design programs to be connected to other programs. Write programs to write programs when you can. Design for the future, because it will be here sooner than you think. In interface design, always do the least surprising thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codecont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codecont/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 12 - Finishing up the project #   Manifesto  Everything should be a tool. A tool transforms data without adding to its source limitations. It&amp;rsquo;s a function: returns an output for a given input. A great tool is ambient. It should disappear and flow through your actions. You should never need it because it&amp;rsquo;s always at your hands. You should never ignore it because it&amp;rsquo;s never in your way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codeintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codeintro/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10 - Let&amp;rsquo;s write some Code #  Starting Minimal #  Code is mostly math #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Code is mostly math. If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you probably just went ugggggghhhhhhh.
And I get it. But it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad for two reasons:
 The math isn&amp;rsquo;t like what you&amp;rsquo;re used to. The math is actually doing something. You&amp;rsquo;re not just getting a number to solve a problem, you&amp;rsquo;re making a tool that can solve many problems or watching the math cause something to happen on screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/consequences/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10½ - Consequences #  Programming is awesome. If you get into creative coding you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use it to make art. You&amp;rsquo;ll likely use it to automate tasks you find boring. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you might use it to make your own website or start to make products you intend to sell. That&amp;rsquo;s great. But there are a few things you need to consider as what you make becomes more professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/debugbuildtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/debugbuildtest/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 16 - Debugging, Automated Building and Testing #  Automated Building #  Debugging #  ./missing-semester - Debugging and Profiling
Software Debugging #  [TODO]
GDB with Gef, interpreted languages, embedded systems, non-code issues (boot problems, glitchy behavior), hardware failures, valgrind, various trace programs, print debugging extended
Debuggers #  GDB Frontend
GDB + GEF
The State of Linux Debuggers (Jamie Brandon&amp;rsquo;s Blog) ← This is a decent rant about why most debuggers sort of suck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fixxingissuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fixxingissuses/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 12½ - It Was Working Just A Second Ago&amp;hellip; #  Alright, so your code/electronics/computer/life was working fine just a second ago, and now it&amp;rsquo;s just not working at all. Take a deep breath, and relax. Let&amp;rsquo;s work though this.
🦆 Grab a rubber duck #  This won&amp;rsquo;t always be applicable, but assuming it&amp;rsquo;s a system- code, or electronics, or a math problem, something that can be analyzed - explain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fosscopyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fosscopyright/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11½ - Open Source, Licenses, and Copyright #  [TODO]
actually contribute on github, make an issue, submit a pull request, make a custom repo,
https://github.com/Marak/faker.js/issues/1046
How to break the Internet: Cory Doctorow at TEDxOxbridge (YouTube)
No, &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; does not mean &amp;ldquo;Includes Free Support&amp;rdquo; + The update to that post.
Chapter 11¾ - Things That Really Need to Exist #  Better than DuckDuckGo [Drew Devault&amp;rsquo;s Blog]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/funcprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/funcprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 20 - (((())(()((()(())))))) #  What is Functional Programming? #   [TODO] Functional Programming, and other paradigms: lisp, haskell, luna-lang.org, ronin
Lambda Calculus #   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/game/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 19 - Game Design #  https://www.gameuidatabase.com/index.php
https://www.riotgames.com/en/urf-academy/curriculum-guide
Engines &amp;amp; Frameworks #  Both 2d and 3d #  Godot
Luxe
fine. I&amp;rsquo;ll mention Unity and Unreal, but, like, I hate that the two make up such a huge chunk of the market
Unreal Engine
Unity
2d #  LEd engine - &amp;ldquo;LEd is a modern and open-source 2D level editor, specifically designed for indie devs&amp;rdquo;
OGMO Editor - &amp;ldquo;OGMO Editor is a free, open source 2D level editor built by indie game developers for indie game developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/guiprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/guiprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 18 - Graphical Programming #  [TODO] Graphics Programming on badd10de.dev
Let&amp;rsquo;s start in a way that&amp;rsquo;s incredibly simple, and abstract away all the hard stuff at first by using a tool kit called &amp;lsquo;Processing&amp;rsquo;, which is available under that name from the community repo in arch. The default IDE that comes with it is awful to work in though, so go ahead and open up VSCode and grab the Processing Language add on, then in VSCode open up a new workspace folder and make a file called processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/languages/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 13 - Programming Languages #  for (🥚 = 1; 🥚 &amp;lt; 🐔; 🥚++){ //whatever } [TODO] talk about to why there are so many, pros &amp;amp; cons per domain, etc
https://esoteric.codes
Why OO Sucks (Joe Armstrong)
0-based vs. 1-based indexing (Hisham Hm)
Low Level #  C, C++, C#, ???? #  [TODO] - a lot, talk about the varieties and differences of C and C++ and C# and why thery&amp;rsquo;re good and bad, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lowlvl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lowlvl/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11 - Low Level Programming #   Ashlyn Black&amp;rsquo;s C Cheat Sheet
&amp;lsquo;C Programming&amp;rsquo; on badd10de.dev
Why C? #  This chapter of OpGuides will be mostly C, but, why? Well, there&amp;rsquo;s only really a few options for learning low level programming that make sense to start with. C, C++, Rust are the &amp;lsquo;big three&amp;rsquo; that come to mind for me. C is awesome. It&amp;rsquo;s spec is small, it&amp;rsquo;s been kept minimal, and it&amp;rsquo;s got a ton of tools to help you learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/multithread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/multithread/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 17 - We&amp;rsquo;ve got cores, let&amp;rsquo;s use em&#39; #  [TODO]
https://lemire.me/blog/2020/01/30/cost-of-a-thread-in-c-under-linux/
C++ coroutines
not really threading, but process children</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/cheat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/cheat/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 2 - Cheat Sheets and quick info #  Electrical Part Tables #  [TODO]
  package types
  reading specs
  datasheets
  Nice Libraries &amp;amp; Resources #  Multi-Language #  Ultralight - &amp;ldquo;Next-generation HTML renderer for apps and games&amp;rdquo;
 Bit like Electron, but less shit. Supports C, C++, C#, Rust, Java, and Go
 C #  Awesome-C - &amp;ldquo;A curated list of awesome C frameworks, libraries, resources and other shiny things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/job/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 4 - Getting a Job in Engineering #   &#34;Recently, I was asked if I was going to fire an employee who made a mistake that cost the company $600,000. No, I replied, I just spent $600,000 training him. Why would I want somebody to hire his experience?&#34;  - Thomas John Watson Sr., IBM
  [TODO] literally this entire page is TODO. I&amp;rsquo;m just making it as a place to dump links for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/latex/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 5 -   \(\LaTeX\)  &amp;amp; Markdown #  Like the kink? #   \(\LaTeX\)  , pronounced Lay-Tech, is a document writing and formatting &amp;lsquo;language&amp;rsquo; that acts pretty different from MS Word. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily used for writing fancy math equations, academic, journal, or conference papers, as such, you might have to use it at some point to conform to one standard or another (like IEEE).
As an example of what  \(\LaTeX\)  formatting looks like, check this equation out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/resources/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 3 - Other Great Resources #  Conventions #  https://www.emfcamp.org
https://media.ccc.de/
    News Sites #  Serializer.io (Aggregate of Hacker News, Ars, Reddit, Macrumors, and Lobste.rs )
Hacker News
Hackaday
Slashdot
 Snopzu
https://n-o-d-e.news/
   Forums #  https://lobste.rs/
https://stackoverflow.com/
   http://textfiles.com/
https://glitch.com/
 Learning Linux #  https://linuxjourney.com
 Youtube #  ElectroBoom
CNLohr
N-O-D-E
LiveOverflow
Tom Scott
 bigclive</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/wrappingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/wrappingup/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 37 - Where To Go Frome Here? #  Hey, so, you made it. I can&amp;rsquo;t give you a degree. But, I&amp;rsquo;m proud of you. Even if you skipped a chapter or two, you still put in work to improve yourself and learn something. That&amp;rsquo;s cool.
But, maybe you thinking &amp;ldquo;Okay, but now what?&amp;quot;
Integrating other interests #  There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to life than computers and code and electronics and making and hacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Cadey Ratio #   .conversation { display: flex; } .conversation-picture { flex: 1; min-width: 9rem; max-width: calc(((70rem - 2rem)/6)); }  3/10/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Cadey. Your blog at christine.website/blog shows that you really have a wide range of interests. So, to get started, what are you passionate about and why?
I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about making computers understandable. We work with these impossibly complex mechanical creations like they are nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</guid>
      <description>MIDI in Detail #  Musical Instrument Digital Interface, or MIDI is what it sounds like, the primary way to get data between devices digitally. Want to tell a hardware synth to play a sequence you arranged on your computer? MIDI. Want to play notes into your computer using a keyboard? MIDI. Want to sequence drums, with varying &amp;lsquo;velocity&amp;rsquo; on each hit? MIDI.
Sounds Great?
For the most part, yeah. Everything works together and you can make all your hardware speak the same language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/coolhardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/coolhardware/</guid>
      <description>Cool Hardware #    LTP-305G/HR 5x7 LED Matrix displays &amp;amp; Driver, article on (Hackaday)
  https://hackaday.io/project/15102-redot    Core Memory Shield for Arduino by Jussi Kilpelainen on Tindie
    A somewhat ridiculous precision voltage source
  turns out placing 900 resistors does not get you banned from SMD assembly service after all 😇 pic.twitter.com/3iu3zL5TLi
&amp;mdash; Marco Reps (@MarcoReps) December 31, 2020      List of nixie tube types: https://justanotherelectronicsblog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/funlinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/funlinks/</guid>
      <description>Other cool things that I want to promote but don&amp;rsquo;t fit elsewhere so I&amp;rsquo;m making this list here: #    Brimestone Valley Mall
 The year is 1999. Lurking somewhere between Hot Topic and the food court, five misfit demons from Hell kill time inciting sin in a suburban shopping mall. When the lead singer of their band goes mysteriously missing, the demons only have two weeks to find him before they play the biggest gig of the millennium - or face the wrath of Satan herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/</guid>
      <description>The Way We Interact With Computers Sucks. #  What do you see when you sit down to work? My guess is a desk pressed against a wall, maybe a few shelves, one, maybe two monitors in front of you, and a keyboard and mouse dominating the work area of your desk. How do you access information? Do you simply Google something and if it&amp;rsquo;s not on the first page give up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</guid>
      <description>Economic Systems #   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</guid>
      <description>Environmental Protection #  Legacy [OC] from r/funny  Carbon Tax?
Percentage of all fossil fuel emissions that have occurred in my lifetime [OC] from r/dataisbeautiful 
Geoengineering: A Horrible Idea We Might Have to Do (YouTube, Kurzgesagt)
A Strange New Blend of Rock and Plastic Is Forming on a Portuguese Island (Gizmodo)
A Plateful of Plastic - Visualising the amount of microplastic we eat (Reuters)
The poison found in everyone, even unborn babies – and who is responsible for it (The Guardian)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</guid>
      <description>History #  Something to consider before going forward is that, assuming you&amp;rsquo;re from the US, the education you&amp;rsquo;ve received is likely very skewed both in what content is presented in the first place and how it&amp;rsquo;s presented. Unlike what most US education will tell you MLK did not magically end racism, not every US war has been just, and - no - our three branches of government are not working as intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</guid>
      <description>Post about sympy in math chapter, espically with sum and product
increasingly online spaces that are custom-built are both spreading new ideas and preventing mono-cultures AND causing people to live in completely different realities and echo chambers
Fuck consumerism, fuck hoarding, fuck status symbols, fuck plastic wrapped single use internationally shiped good, fuck single use electronics, fuck shitty electronics that are instant-ewaste</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/webdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/webdev/</guid>
      <description>h1 The Quick Brown Fox #  test
h2 The Quick Brown Fox #  test
h3 The Quick Brown Fox #  test
h4 The Quick Brown Fox #  test
h5 The Quick Brown Fox #  test
h6 #  test
https://excalidraw.com - for &amp;lsquo;hand drawn&amp;rsquo; svg diagrams
https://detexify.kirelabs.org/classify.html - for Latex symbol lookup
http://shapecatcher.com - for unicode symbol lookup
 note, youtube &amp;ldquo;copy embed code&amp;rdquo; depends on current size on screen of the embed, this can be fixed a bit by changing the start to &amp;lt;iframe width=&amp;ldquo;100%&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog Design</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/analog-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/analog-design/</guid>
      <description>[TODO]
What makes it &amp;lsquo;analog&amp;rsquo; #  Pen/Pencil and Paper #  Charcoal #  Paints #  https://www.reddit.com/r/PourPainting/
New Genesis, me, fluid acrylic, 2020 from r/Art  Sculpting #  Fabrics and Fashion #  This is my very long daughter, Calliope Crayon Cruncher from r/LongFurbies  LED Hackers Jacket for EMF Camp (lochsh)
Glass #  The biggest stained glass commision so far - feels great! from r/furry  Other #  Foil Art (Reddit)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</guid>
      <description>Philosophical Arguments #  [TODO]how to construct a phil argument
Not simply accepting &amp;ldquo;Because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is&amp;rdquo; #  I&amp;rsquo;m writing this at @292.78 on Day 132 of 12,020. I&amp;rsquo;m typing on a Dvorak, split, ortholinear keyboard in a markdown document using Arch Linux instead of M$ Word on Windows, and if you&amp;rsquo;d like you could view this document using DAT or IPFS or LBRY. I find music off the 12 tone scale interesting, and while I know 432 vs 440hz, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to open my 3rd eye, listening to microtonal or music made with just intonation is still something interesting to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Phil</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</guid>
      <description>OPINION          Before anything else, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out this is opinionated guides. Philosophy involves looking at the world around us and asking ourselves &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, then making arguments for how things should be different and what moral frameworks work best to come to conclusions that optimize for something like happiness or &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; in the world. Given that both morals and &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; are not absolutes, the best way for me to write this guide and actually be of service to you as a reader is to provide my opinion and talk about why I believe what believe both from a researched &amp;lsquo;here are the facts&amp;rsquo; sense and from a &amp;lsquo;here is the moral framework that, with these facts, brought me to this conclusion&amp;rsquo; sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Art and Design #  When you&amp;rsquo;re first learning art, every art class will beat a few core ideas into your head:
  Lines - The &amp;lsquo;structure&amp;rsquo; bits of the works, when you start making art, you&amp;rsquo;ll often start with the Line Art
  Shape - Structures that form out of lines, might appear 3D. These might be mathy, like squares, or organic, like an eye</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</guid>
      <description>Community #  Hopefully this isn&amp;rsquo;t a shock to anyone reading this, but I&amp;rsquo;m a furry.
owo uwu nuzzles rawr tehe So, I think I can share a little bit about why I joined the fandom, what being in a subculture community is like, and how some of those experiences have made me a better person and helped me be a part of or run successful online communities.
I hope that though this I can talk about what makes a community good or bad, what brings division, and what good rules for a healthy community look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>Consumerism #  Vega&amp;rsquo;s Maw, made for me by @NewtWolfdeer  Look, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of falling for the tricks used to get people to consume. To buy and buy more. A good sale, even on something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I previously wanted, still has a way of making my dumb lil&#39; human brain go &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;
The problem is that consumers can easily fall into traps that lead them to buy things for a stupid reasons, these include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/cooking/cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/cooking/cooking/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
My name is Vega, and I can&amp;rsquo;t cook, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be letting my friends take this one over.
Why you should take the time to be a functional adult: #  !&amp;gt; I had a few friends interested in fleshing this page out, but they got busy, lmk if you want to take it over or just sumbit a pull request ^-^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Letting Society Advance Though Art and Innovation #  This video from Tom Scott on YouTube is a very good intro to everything I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about on this page, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you&amp;rsquo;ve watched it so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat everything that he says here.
 What is Copyright? #  [TODO]
What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong With that? #  Watch a police officer admit to playing Taylor Swift to keep a video off YouTube (The Verge)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</guid>
      <description>Mobile Apps for Art &amp;amp; Design #     Name &amp;amp; Link Description Demo/Screenshot          Pixlr phone version of https://pixlr.com    Fragment Add some neat geometric reflections into your art    Mirror Lab ^         Spiro, Tilemaker Makes some interesting tiled patterns    Easyposer, plenty of other alternatives Decent app for poseable character models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Design</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/digital-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/digital-design/</guid>
      <description>Digital Art #  Raster, Vector, Pixel, Voxel, ASCII, Mesh, Fractal, Generative, #  Projection Mapping, Creative Code, &amp;hellip;
Raster Art #  PhotoGIMP is a patch for Gimp that makes it look more like Photoshop, adds fonts and some filters.
Unsplash is a good source for &amp;lsquo;Freely usable images&amp;rsquo; if you need some source material
Pixel Art #  Vector Art #  inkscape
dotgrid
SVGPathEditor (Github)
3D Art #  Meshes #  Meshlab</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duties</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</guid>
      <description>Personal Duties #  Maintaining health #  Physical #  Working out #  Air quality #  Mental #  Socialized healthcare #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</guid>
      <description>Education #  Freedom of Information #  Curriculum Changes #   Basic Aid #  Sex Education #  Individualized, shared, and student led #  [TODO] Faster, lower standards #  Better testing #   Fuck Respondus And Proctorio #   The following is a (slightly edited) excerpt from an email I felt necessary to send to my professors at the start of the spring semester, 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects #  A lot of audio effects boil down to automating some simple parameter. Some times you may not actually need a dedicated effect and can instead get by with using Automation Lanes (YouTube, once upon a synth) in you Digital Audio Workstation (DAW) Also don&amp;rsquo;t get to deep into gear envy. Effects are awesome and it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to either want to collect them and hoard them like a happy dragon on a pile of gold or feel like you can&amp;rsquo;t make music without that one perfect effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</guid>
      <description>Logical Fallacies (and a bit more) #  If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet for more than about a quarter of a second, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely been accused of a whole host of logical fallacies. Unfortunately, most people really don&amp;rsquo;t understand what they&amp;rsquo;re saying and often use a lot of these incorrectly. On the other hand, you also likely encounter politicians people using these fallacies on a regular basis as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to call them out on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foriegn</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</guid>
      <description>War and Foreign Involvement #  [TODO] DoD or Department of War?
Denuclearization #  Localization #   Falsehoods Programmers Believe About Name The Problem with Time &amp;amp; Timezones (YouTube) Google Maps is Different in Other Countries (YouTube)  US Tampering in Foregin Affairs #   This embedable version of this video is a re-upload. The orginal, from &amp;lsquo;Second Thought&amp;rsquo; on YouTube is here but has been age restricted and has been shadow-banned by YouTube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedoms</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/</guid>
      <description>Freedoms and Rights #  Freedom of Speech #  xkcd №1357 Freedom of Press #  Everyone is press, https://www.eff.org/bloggers
The Trump Administration Is Trying To Force BuzzFeed News To Divulge Its Sources With A Subpoena
anti-SLAPP laws
Whistle Blower Protections #  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_whistleblowers
Search and Seizure #    Fair Trial #  Court of Public Opinion #  Freedom of Body #  Marital Rape, Euthanasia, Abortion, AI recognition and usage, gene ownership</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/generative-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/generative-art/</guid>
      <description>Generative Art #  This page is almost completely devoid of actual educational content. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to make the most complete list of generative art tools and libraries on the internet. Of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t actually make an exhaustive list and may be missing some of the newest tools and ideals, so please check out these other communities for more:  r/proceduralgeneration
r/generative
r/PlotterArt
  If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in generative music and sounds as well, you may want to check out The OpGuides page on Music Software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Labs</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</guid>
      <description>Communal Efforts #  [TODO] Shared Spaces #  Hacker Spaces Community Garden
Open Source hardware and software #  Different Ideas are better #   P-hacking, Fake Science, and Academia&amp;rsquo;s Bullshit #   Scientific Studies (Last Week Tonight, YouTube)    Academic journal publishing reform (Wikipedia)
List of scholarly publishing stings (Wikipedia)
Predatory Publishing (Wikipedia)
           I&amp;rsquo;d also like to touch on paid-for research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure #  College Campuses Are Designed at Human-Scale. Our Cities Can Be Too. (StrongTowns.org)
Power #  Gravity-based batteries try to beat their chemical cousins with winches, weights, and mine shafts
Light Pollution #  International Dark Sky Association
Air Quality #  A paradigm shift to combat indoor respiratory infection
Networking (Mesh) #  Housing and Land #  The People the Suburbs Were Built for Are Gone (Vice)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspirational Artists</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</guid>
      <description>Inspirational Artists #  Added a lot of minor improvements, like camera limits, subtle lighting, dust particles and more #gamedev #pixelart #screenshotsaturday pic.twitter.com/KmSYW3iHml
&amp;mdash; Luis Moreno Jimenez (@more8bit) September 2, 2017  Teenage Engineering&amp;#39;s OP-1 Synthesizer modules: pic.twitter.com/Jx5FEkiGK9
&amp;mdash; Shadow Drop - R&amp;amp;D (@ShadowDropDev) August 18, 2017  Some really cool pixel art gifs by Mark Ferrari
/// Caution some are NSFW /// https://twitter.com/halphelt (NSFW) https://twitter.com/Hushabye_Valley (NSFW-ish) https://twitter.com/koidrake (Like kinda lood I guess?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Instruments #  What is an Instrument? #  Okay, yeah, that sounds like a stupid question, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to think about. Wikipedia has it defined like this:
 A musical instrument is a device created or adapted to make musical sounds. In principle, any object that produces sound can be considered a musical instrument—it is through purpose that the object becomes a musical instrument. - Wikipedia   which, okay, that&amp;rsquo;s fair enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</guid>
      <description>If you would like to be interviewed #  Well, first of all I&amp;rsquo;d like to know what makes you interesting - so shoot me a message or open an issue on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</guid>
      <description>Labor and Compensation #  EU pushes for &amp;lsquo;right to disconnect&amp;rsquo; from work at home (dw.com)
Please Consider My Application to Give You Labor So I Can Stay Alive
Workplace Wellbeing Is a Scam (Tribune)
 Economic Inequality #   Source code (GPL v3), by Matt Korostoff Wage Theft is a Much Bigger Problem Than Other Forms of Theft—But Workers Remain Mostly Unprotected
Ex-Google Employee Exposes Unequal Pay With Spreadsheet (Wall Street Journal)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law And Order</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</guid>
      <description>Law Enforcment and Judgment #  Trial of educated peers
Criminal Rehabilitation #  end mandatory sentencing end bail no debters prision
 Divorce, Child Support #  Jury Duty #   Prosecutors &amp;amp; Public Defenders #    Police #   Prisions #   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare Costs #  Why is life expectancy in the US lower than in other rich countries?
White House wins ruling on disclosing health care prices (AP)
Drugs #  Most drugs and prostitution should be legal at the age of 18. However, trafficking obviously not, and drugs must be sold by an individual with a licence to deal and said licence may be revoked if the product is sold with a false label or is tainted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixing &amp;amp; Mastering #  Mixers #  mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring #  https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and spotify
Mixing #  eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Mastering #  Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)
 Studio Monitors, Headphones, and Amps #  @Tirrelous on Twitter  Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of all the specs you might want to understad if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to buy headphones or studio monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the part where I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to explain how to read music or something boring like that. Really though, that&amp;rsquo;s not why you&amp;rsquo;re here. So let me start by giving you a bit of motivation. In a bit I&amp;rsquo;ll be going though how to use VCV Rack, a free (with paid addons, but those aren&amp;rsquo;t necessary) program for making music. But as we go though each bit is going to look so -basic- that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see the bigger picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware #  While you could make all of your music with just computer, you’ll probably want some tools that make your life as a musician easier and let you explore ideas faster. Like I said back in the Audio Effects Chapter, in my experience, making music depends on a really quick brain to input device feedback loop. Being able to turn a physical knob and mash physical keys will often lead to better results if only because you’re able to try things both faster and by physically interacting with something that you may not have thought of otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software #  Some tools on this page are not-free. As such, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to list prices as best I can. Music software usually goes on sale pretty significantly around Black Friday or Christmas, so when I can, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to list &amp;lsquo;street&amp;rsquo; prices. Regardless, I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with any of these projects in any way and I don&amp;rsquo;t make any money from these links- so don&amp;rsquo;t complain to me if the prices are wrong ╮(─▽─)╭ NOTE: this list is far from exhaustive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpPhil Old</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</guid>
      <description>Old Version, needs migrated: #  Because you&amp;rsquo;re now somebody in the know about topics relating to technology and have a deeper understanding about issues that may effect the public, such as The FBI V Apple encryption case, Issues regrading internet speed and infrastructure, or The Government/NSA spying on people. There are plenty of issues that weather you like it or not you&amp;rsquo;re one of the few with enough information to truly understand and inform your peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources #  PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (Github) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses
Cool People #  https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/thePatchBay - some shameless self promo, as this is my chat.  Neurotypique https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4oBI5piGMznFMZdtEC0FhA
Omri Cohen, a Rack Master&amp;rsquo;s YouTube Channel
Loopop RedMeansRecording AdamNeely AndrewHuang Rob Scallon Pipe Organ Video (YouTube), Theorbo Video (YouTube),</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil and The Internet</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>The fight for the Internet is never ending. At the time of writing, Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell tried to tie anti §230 legislation to the $2000 stimulus checks, and my own Congress Critter, Ben Sasse (R,Nebraska), along with Jeff Merkley (D,Oregon) are trying to push though SISEA - the Stop Internet Sexual Exploitation Act, which on paper sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s doing good to stop the possibility of revenge porn. Unfortunately, they want to do this by requiring that all people in porn expressly give the site written consent with identity verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</guid>
      <description>Thank you #  If you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far I just want to say thank you. We need more people to really consider how ethics, politics, and copyright shape the world around us with technology and art as we design it and proceed with it. DeepFakes, Automated driving, and even more mass online censorship are issues we&amp;rsquo;re only going to face more with time and it&amp;rsquo;s people like you who are going to help make sure we take the best path we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil, Misc</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</guid>
      <description>Animal Rights (Industrial Scale Slaughter) #  Organ donation #  Tech can&amp;rsquo;t solve all your problems #  Human problems need human solutions
Guns #                  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion #  [TODO] The engineering community is strangely divided, the &amp;lsquo;old guard&amp;rsquo; is actually relatively conservative and professional, but as time has moved forward it&amp;rsquo;s quite the opposite. Unsurprisingly, this correlates with religion as well. The main way this plays into politics is a general hard stance for the separation of church and state. This is in part due to a past of religiously motivated legislation negatively impacting copyright law, but also just generally an understood ideal that is beneficial to democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequencing and MIDI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing &amp;amp; Midi #  This chapter only goes over the basics of MIDI. Because MIDI is so important to music production I&amp;rsquo;ll dive much deeper into the details of MIDI in Chapter 6½ - MIDI in Detail Sequencing #  The definition of a sequence is pretty obvious, but don&amp;rsquo;t be misled by the name- a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; is not always just a list of notes to be played one after the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</guid>
      <description>Sex #  In an ideal world human kind would be driven forward by more than the initiate desire to reproduce and bone. But, we don&amp;rsquo;t live in an ideal world and people like to have fun and feel good. (consensual) Sex is fun and feels good- so it should not be looked down on. Flirting, hooking up, being horny: They&amp;rsquo;re all natural and good. Unfortunately, today it seems Everyone is Beautiful and No One is Horny</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise #  Samples #   a snippet of a .wav file open in audacity
 A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. The easiest to explain is what is usually meant by sample: a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: #   Theory #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest. I can&amp;rsquo;t read music and I don&amp;rsquo;t know scales. Why, then, would I in any way think I&amp;rsquo;m qualified to write anything about music? Well, let me stop you right there, I&amp;rsquo;m not. I make music for fun. However, I like to think that people enjoy my music and I enjoy listening to it myself as I make it, and though my experience I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a little here and there to make sure things don&amp;rsquo;t sound awful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</guid>
      <description>UI and UX #  Principals of UI, A Thread (zensaiyuki@mastodon.social)
Gallery of Fantasy UI design from Movies and TV shows
Responsiveness #   Source
 Power Users #  User power, not power users: htop and its design philosophy
Typography #  Practical Typography Textbook
Datalegeya Font
Website Design #  Learn CSS by Google Developers
Butalist Web Design, by David Copeland
motherfuckingwebsite.com, bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com, thebestmotherfuckingwebsite.website
Scrollbar Blindness (Sven Kadak&amp;rsquo;s Blog)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/video/</guid>
      <description>Video &amp;amp; Streaming #  [TODO, basically the entire page]
Cameras #  If you&amp;rsquo;re like most people, the best camera you own is probably you&amp;rsquo;re phone camera.
Lighting #  I found hanging up some of those string light LED edison bulbs (like you&amp;rsquo;d see at a wedding) on the ceiling works well as an alternative to a softbox. It&amp;rsquo;s so many point lights that it adds up to a similar effect- albeit with the downside that you can&amp;rsquo;t move them around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</guid>
      <description>Elections &amp;amp; Voting #  I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;lsquo;murican, so this will be US centric, that said, the arguments here could likely be applied universally Issue 1: FPTP Voting Sucks #  lower standards of removal, ranked, transparency Budget voting
  Issue 2: Voters are really, really stupid #  voting based on if they like the person, how he/she looks, single issue voting
Issue 3: Two is the unfriendliest number #  Issue 4: Gerrymandering and Fraud and Astroturfing #     [TODO] Comment on Citizen&amp;rsquo;s United</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
