<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/community/</guid>
      <description>Art by Talon Creations. Characters from Left to Right: Soatok, Cadey, Loial, Vega, Cendyne, Mimir, Vordex Ⅰ - Community # When you think engineer, what traits come to mind? If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like most people, you probably thought &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;antisocial&amp;rdquo;. While I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to how truthful that stereotype may be, I can tell you for sure that in engineering, not knowing how to make friends, ask for help, and talk with others will make you all but useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exodus</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/exodus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/exodus/</guid>
      <description>The year is 2022. In the world of social media, Twitter has long been the platform of choice for politicians, celebrities, and everyday users alike. But as the years have passed, the once-mighty site has struggled to keep up with the rapidly changing landscape of the internet.
As the lines between the virtual and the physical world blur, Twitter becomes a battleground for hackers, activists, and corporate interests. Despite the best efforts of its engineers and executives, the site is plagued by outages and security breaches, causing frustration and anger among its remaining user base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Art Panic</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/aiartpanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/aiartpanic/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet at all lately, you&amp;rsquo;ve seen AI generated art and discussion of the impact of the tools. You&amp;rsquo;ve also probably seen a lot of hate for AI generated art. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of drama going on, as art focused communities across the internet decide how to handle this. Does AI generated/assisted art need tagged as such? Should it be allowed at all? There&amp;rsquo;s the whole Deviant Art situation (ArsTechnica).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Video Synthesis Journey</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/video-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/video-synth/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not being paid to say any of this, I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken to any of the companies listed here except for
Noisedeck, which while is made by two really awesome people, also gets a pretty nasty review here because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for this use case. Sleepy Circuits, which I&amp;rsquo;ve only talked to. I don&amp;rsquo;t even own their hardware. Furthermore, I have paid my own money for Visual Synthesizer, Cathodemer, and KodeLife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did I pay to go to college?</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/whydidipay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/whydidipay/</guid>
      <description>Post originally published March 22 of 2021, date above represents most recent edit The Nebraska Union at UNL, photo by ensign_beedrill, CC BY-SA 2.0, via Wikimedia Commons At the time of writing, I am currently a student at the University of Nebraska - Lincoln, where I study Computer and Electrical Engineering as a dual major. I have a serious passion for both of these subjects, which is why I am so incredibly frustrated at how negative my experience at UNL has been, especially in the classes that directly relate to my major.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantization, Polarization, &amp; Indoctrination</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/quantized/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/quantized/</guid>
      <description>Quantization is the process of constraining an input from a continuous or otherwise large set of values (such as the real numbers) to a discrete set (such as the integers). - wikipedia I&amp;rsquo;m less than two months from graduating with degrees in both Electrical Engineering and Computer Engineering. One subject that comes up a lot in both fields is Quantization. Reading audio in to a micocontroller from a DAC? That continuous signal, represented physically by infinite values, now may only have 12 bits of resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Culture Problem in Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/wtfarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/wtfarch/</guid>
      <description>The Background # I&amp;rsquo;m going to jump straight to the point, after my last post, somebody saw the Arch install guide on OpGuides and decided they didn&amp;rsquo;t like it, and so opened a PR deleting the file:
Now, this story could have ended here. I could have closed the issue and moved on with my life, but as a real &amp;ldquo;I use Arch BTW&amp;rdquo; user since 2014 I&amp;rsquo;m just not okay with this attitude in the community, so&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Meta-er-verse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/metaverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/metaverse/</guid>
      <description>Plots of land &amp;amp; Euclidean space # One of the bigger points of the metaverse is the idea of owning a slice of digital property. This is a weird mix of the scarcity and value from real life property and the domain name (like myfancyname.com) market. It also makes no god damn sense in this context, and is really just artificially putting limitations into a system for the sake of making yet another crypto currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offline</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/offline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/offline/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion &amp; Doublethink</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/religiondoublethink/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/religiondoublethink/</guid>
      <description>From time to time, I get asked about my religion. Sometimes, &amp;ldquo;asked&amp;rdquo; is putting it lightly, like when my SO&amp;rsquo;s father asked if I believe in a God, but made it very clear there was only one right answer if I wanted to date my SO. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m asked with honest curiosity, as when people find out I grew up in a mixture of Wicca and Christianity, people wonder how that works, and what I came out believing in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/someconsumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/someconsumerism/</guid>
      <description>I bitch about consumerism a lot, yet, I like things. So that&amp;rsquo;s what this post is about. Things. Things I&amp;rsquo;ve bought over the last few years and what things fall into &amp;ldquo;OhMyGod This is Life Changing&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;A Bit of a Mixed Bag&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;How Did You Fuck This Up?&amp;rdquo;. Because I know not everyone cares about all these products, I&amp;rsquo;m going to skip right to the juicy bit- the thinking about what lessons come from this thinking:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Bandwidth Images</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lowbandwidthimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lowbandwidthimages/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a website that you want to make use less bandwidth. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re paying by the byte for content delivery, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re worried about the environment, either way, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you want to make your images as small as possible. The obvious place to start is just shrinking your images. Here, this is a 4032x2268 .jpg shrunk down to a 1008x567 .jpg - 25% of the original quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Not a Digital Native, and Neither Are You</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/digital-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/digital-native/</guid>
      <description>The term digital native describes a young person who has grown up in the digital age, in close contact with computers, the Internet, and video game consoles, and later mobile phones, social media, and tablets. The term is often used to refer to millennials, Generation Z, and Generation Alpha; the latter two are sometimes described as distinct &amp;ldquo;neo-digital natives&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; digital natives, or &amp;ldquo;digital integrators&amp;rdquo;. &amp;lsquo;Digital Native&amp;rsquo; on Wikipedia You know how every headline about Millennials or Gen Z is &amp;ldquo;Gen ___ has killed ___&amp;rdquo; and it makes everyone from those generations want collectively bang their heads into a desk?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nebraksa LR107 - Stupdity Abound</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</guid>
      <description>NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT RESOLVED BY THE MEMBERS OF THE ONE HUNDRED SEVENTH LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA, FIRST SESSION:
That we hereby reaffirm our solemn oaths of office by expressing a firm resolution to maintain and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Nebraska against every act of aggression whether foreign or domestic, including every act of unconstitutional abuse of power arising from the state or federal government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ternary Logic</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</guid>
      <description>This paper was written for CSCE-430, Computer Architecture at University Of Nebraska - Lincoln in Spring of 2021.
This in-page view isn&amp;rsquo;t all that great, so feel free to download the pdf directly.
If you would like to read the refrenced papers, I reccomend using Sci-Hub with a VPN on, as the academic publishers putting up paywalls as barriers to science can go fuck themselves.
Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: / </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Products I Wish Existed</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</guid>
      <description>Most of these things probably exist. For many, it&amp;rsquo;s just that they don&amp;rsquo;t exist at a practical price point. Without further ado, In no particular order
A not garbage, not phone based, IR camera that doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost a bajillion dollars
Yes. I know the FLIR and SEEK Thermal cameras are a thing, but both have their share of software problems or hardware incompatibilities. Most of all, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to hope that their app keeps working with my phone at risk of a $250 paper weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chains</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/chains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/chains/</guid>
      <description>My name is Vega. I have to tell myself that a lot, reminding myself of who I am.
I know that may sound weird, but, if it wen&amp;rsquo;t already obvious, it isn&amp;rsquo;t my legal name. (yet.)
Despite my best efforts, my parents still call me by my &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; name. I&amp;rsquo;m hesitant to call it a dead name, as I&amp;rsquo;m not trans. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s the same or that it&amp;rsquo;s fair to claim that it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirrors of Opal</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/mirrorsofopal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/mirrorsofopal/</guid>
      <description>When I looked into the mirror this morning, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure who I was looking at. Is that me? Is that really what I look like now? Has this years long separation from reality caused me to not recognize my own face, or would it have happened anyway- a side effect of growing older.
If you saw me, would you even recognize me? Or am I the ship of Theseus, digested by the carnivore that we call time, now fertilizer for someone you&amp;rsquo;ve never met?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Make OpGuides</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/howimakeopguides/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/howimakeopguides/</guid>
      <description>History # Before I can get into how OpGuides works now, I need to provide some history so that you can learn from my mistakes.
The first iteration of OpGuides was OpinionatedEngineering.md. A single markdown file so long that the scroll bar was hard to grab. It was meant to be viewed and distributed not as a website, but as a file to be opened with https://typora.io (so that the html and everything rendered- though in theory any markdown editor would do)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time lapse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</guid>
      <description>Super brief post about one of the more fun projects I setup recently: a lil&amp;rsquo; time lapse script
#!/bin/bash CAM=$(v4l2-ctl --list-devices | grep C920 -A 1 | grep /dev | awk &amp;#39;{$1=$1};1&amp;#39;) #Uncomment the next line to verify it&amp;#39;s using the correct device #echo $CAM ffmpeg -f video4linux2 -s 1920x1080 -i $CAM -ss 0:0:2 -frames 1 &amp;#34;/mnt/data/lapse/tl$(date +&amp;#34;%Y-%m-%d_%H-%M-%S&amp;#34;).jpg&amp;#34; I have multiple cameras on my system, but only wanted output from the better one, the C920.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Down!</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</guid>
      <description>I use VCV Rack a lot. I normally use it on Windows as running VSTs in Linux is still a bit of a PITA and If I&amp;rsquo;m going to make music I want to have access to all of my tools. However, I still want to be able to use VCV on Linux for processing guitar when taking breaks from working on other things without having to reboot over to Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xx80</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</guid>
      <description>The year is 198x. # I stare at my amber terminal. Hexadecimal fills my screen and my mind has become lost in the flow of 6502 assembly, as I hand optimize the code flow.
I&amp;rsquo;m interupted when I recieve a message from my friend, _Maverik, he&amp;rsquo;s excited about the ground breaking CGI in Tron.
Nostalgia is a weird feeling. We can forget when things happened, and misttribute things to entirely different decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti Consumer</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</guid>
      <description>As I walked to my car after class I could smell the ashes of a cigarette and hear the echos of a train scraping on its tracks. The cool foggy air held still beams of light. It looked like a scene from Blade runner, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like the Android&amp;rsquo;s of it&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, lusting after something to make me feel alive.
The drive home was mentally taxing. The fog so dense that cars ahead seemed to be balls of light floating in the distance and keeping sight of the lines to stay in my lane took a constant effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/daily/day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/daily/day1/</guid>
      <description>Day x # Writing Prompt # After months of endless false accusations of being a witch, a perfectly fine young woman is determined to become a witch. u/MostlyMades &amp;ldquo;Witch! Witch! What just because I wear fucking dark clothes, like growing herbs, have had pre-marital sex, and don&amp;rsquo;t like their silly little Sunday sing along hour doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m a God damned witch&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Mm,&amp;rdquo; Abbey tried to speak, as sala dripped off her tortilla chip onto the table &amp;ldquo;I dunno Bree, I think you had to have done something magical when you made this,&amp;rdquo; she held up her chip, making even more sala drip off &amp;ldquo;devine tomato based dip&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/daily/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/daily/template/</guid>
      <description> Day x # Writing Prompt # After months of endless false accusations of being a witch, a perfectly fine young woman is determined to become a witch. u/MostlyMades Art # Featured Artwork # My Work # Photography # Music # What I&amp;rsquo;m listening to # What I&amp;rsquo;m making # Gaming # Code &amp;amp; Software # Featured Project # What I&amp;rsquo;m working on # Watching # Reading # test2
Today&amp;rsquo;s Poem # Today&amp;rsquo;s Thoughts # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</guid>
      <description>3D Modeling, Sculpting, Painting, Shading, and Rendering # Art by TalonCreations This chapter will be using various programs, not all of which are free. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to recommend things that are open source if I can, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep the cost down as much as possible. You definitely can do everything in this chapter for free, just be aware that without some of the paid tools it may be substantially harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/analog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/analog/</guid>
      <description>Analog Art # What makes it &amp;lsquo;analog&amp;rsquo; # So, for OpGuides I&amp;rsquo;m going to refer to any non-digital art as analog. Traditionally, this art is called, well, traditional. I don&amp;rsquo;t like this term as it implies that there&amp;rsquo;s a right &amp;rsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; way to do things, and that&amp;rsquo;s a load of shit. So, whenever I say analog, don&amp;rsquo;t think about it too much. I just mean not using software and a computer, or, if a computer is used, it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary for the end product, like 3D printing and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/dacadc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/dacadc/</guid>
      <description>Analog Art to Digital Art # Scanning in your Analog Art # [TODO] Scanner DPI, etc.
Background Removal # Via vector art tools # Before doing this, you should really know what vector art is and how it differs from the raster art you&amp;rsquo;re probably used to. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about this a bit in the previous chapter, Digital Art . This process requires combining the two, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit odd if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used vector art tools before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/digital/</guid>
      <description>Digital Art # Photo by cece kun The primary tool of the digital artist &amp;hellip; The pen? # I want to give you a heads-up that making digital art without a pen tablet or pen display of some sort is pretty awful. You can get a cheap pen tablet - they&amp;rsquo;re basically like a mouse pad that you use a pen on - for ~$30. Or you can get a fancy pen display, where you draw directly on the screen, for about ~$300 (similar to the one in the picture above; however, one that large is probably much more expensive)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/gen/</guid>
      <description>Generative Art # This page is almost completely devoid of actual educational content. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to make the most complete list of generative art tools and libraries on the internet. Of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t actually make an exhaustive list and may be missing some of the newest tools and ideals, so please check out these other communities for more: r/proceduralgeneration
r/generative
r/PlotterArt
Most will notice this page lacks AI generative art tools such as DALL·E 2, Midjourney, &amp;amp; Stable Diffusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</guid>
      <description>Photography # [TODO]
This Guy Flipped an Element in an Old Lens and Got ‘Magic’ Bokeh (PetaPixel)
https://hackaday.com/2022/10/12/enjoy-the-beauty-of-corona-discharge-with-this-kirlian-photography-setup/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/vbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/vbasics/</guid>
      <description>Vega&amp;rsquo;s Not-As-Basics of Art and Design # So, we have the basics that any art program will focus on - Lines, Shape, Form, Color, Space, Texture, Value - and these are the standard starting topics for good reason. They&amp;rsquo;re tried and tested to make people better at art, and they apply to any piece. This is great, but I think there are a few things left out of this for the purpose of making it broadly applicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/access/</guid>
      <description>Accessibility # Constrast. # ░▒▓ Accessability doesn&#39;t mean ugly. ▓▒░ ♚ High constrast colors can look good. ♛ 🙟Like this, nice nature-y theme.🙝 → Or this in-your-face purple ← 🗹🗹🗹 All of these boxes are high constrast. !!! And it&#39;s not like this is hard to do. &amp;nbsp&amp;nbsp Hell, it&#39;s easier! All of these palettes were made with https://randoma11y.com Though it&#39;s not hard to make your own. You just have to give a shit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/content/</guid>
      <description>Content is King # At the end of the day, you can make a cool looking fancy website, but you still have to have something to say, a story to tell, a tutorial, videos, something to play. something. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a print book, you can come back and edit it later. The important thing is to just make something.
It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be good at first, it just has to exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/cost/</guid>
      <description>Cost # So, a pretty big question you should ask right away is &amp;ldquo;How much does this cost?&amp;rdquo;, and you probably already know the answer.
It depends.
First thing you should worry about is the cost of hosting, but, uhh, what is hosting?
Hosting? # So, if you really want to, you can run a web server off of your home internet connection. This has a few problems though:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/garden/</guid>
      <description>Your Own Garden # So, I just said you&amp;rsquo;d need to learn a bunch to do this, so, why bother?
Platforms like Facebook, Tumblr, etc. - Social Media - don&amp;rsquo;t let you really customize the look of your page
&amp;hellip; and they track you
&amp;hellip; and they make the experience bad for those without accounts
&amp;hellip; and they can limit your speech, ban your account, etc.
Site builders (Squarespace, Wix, WordPress, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/jack/</guid>
      <description>Jack of All Trades # You probably noticed the mildly ugly gradient heading this section, that was my warning to you that you&amp;rsquo;re about to walk into something that requires an interesting mixture of design and engineering skills. Making a good website requires a fair understanding of computers, some basic programming skills, and a willingness to dive into some technical topics. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason most blogging now happens on Medium or Tumblr and that social media has boomed: The barrier to entry is significantly lower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/</guid>
      <description> HTML, (S)CSS, JS&amp;hellip; WUT? # The rise of WASM # PHP needs to die. # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css/</guid>
      <description>CSS # Let me start by saying that Cascading Style Sheets - CSS - is not a hard language to write. The problem is not the language(1), but with how humans don&amp;rsquo;t think about style and art in a linear way and dealing with the complexities of different devices.
How we think about style # Look around this website, there are things that have been made stylistically cohesive - the color theme, the way I indicate that something is a local link by putting it in a button with a color that matches where it goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/html/</guid>
      <description>HTML # Alright, so HyperText Markup Language is the one thing on this list I suspect everyone reading this page has at least a smidgen of familiarity with, and it&amp;rsquo;s really very easy to work with, so let&amp;rsquo;s just dive in.
In general, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a bunch of HTML tags, tags are these point-bracketed enclosed words that mean something special to the browser, let&amp;rsquo;s actually make a HTML file right now to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/js/</guid>
      <description>JS # Javascript is hard to talk about. Fundamentally, it&amp;rsquo;s a language for adding interactive content to the web.
Want to make a button that increments a counter?
Click me
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 // Set the initial value of the counter to 0 let counter = 0; // Get a reference to the button element const button = document.getElementById(&amp;#39;countButton&amp;#39;); // Add a click event listener to the button button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/resources/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources # Blog Posts # Only 90s Web Developers Remember This
https://www.learnui.design/tools/gradient-generator.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/setup/</guid>
      <description>Setting up everything you need to make a website # [TODO] - include instructions for GitHub pages, a VPS, and self-hosted but assume a Hugo site for all three. There&amp;rsquo;s gotta be limits in the complexity somewhere, and I draw the line at setting up everything for decent JS web app dev / PHP shit, cloud/AWS, etc. though I still want to link to external resources for those things. Also, this probably needs to be written for win/mac/lin, which means there will have to be a ton of permutations of getting things setup depending on hosting solution and OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/static/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/static/</guid>
      <description> Static or Dynamic? # The &amp;lsquo;Weight&amp;rsquo; of your website # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/thinkingweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/thinkingweb/</guid>
      <description> Thinking Web # [TODO] Content can be presented in novel ways. Text as a last resort
[TODO] Because of browser differences, screen size, Fonts, JS support, etc. you should check in other resolutions and browsers periodically
FAQs: why we don’t have them (gds.blog.gov.uk)
Every pricing page should have GIFs (Tony Dinh)
NoScript fallback
Some Beautiful Websites For Inspiration: # https://oxide.computer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/tools/</guid>
      <description>Web Development Tools # Code generation, libraries, etc.
HTML Helpers # HTML Table Generator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/a3-bom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/a3-bom/</guid>
      <description>Appendix C - BOM # As the guide isn&amp;rsquo;t anywhere near a usable state yet, this page should be ignored for the most part. OpGuides is free. Unfortunately all the tools and programs you&amp;rsquo;ll need to follow along aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily. While you probably could do everything in this guide without getting the things in this Bill OF Materials (BOM) it will massively help to have it.
I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to keep the cost as low as possible though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 23 - e-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-e- Electrons work for you # A simple guide to electronic components (YouTube)
The Tools of the Trade # Building, fixing, and analyzing circuitry requires the use of a some tools and appliances, so let&amp;rsquo;s look at the basics of working with electricity by looking at what purpose the tools serve. While there are many more than those listed here, these are the most important ones and should be all you need for most applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/circuits2/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 24 - Circuits &amp;amp; Semiconductors # When I was a kid I thought about circuits as being alive, like Cells at Work!, only little electrons going around busily keeping the heart of my toy working instead of anthropomorphic red blood cells working in the human body.
Now, as an adult - and a computer and electrical engineer at that - I still find this thought endearing. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve now come to see the physics and art of electronics to be even more beautiful when their true nature is really understood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/digitallogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/digitallogic/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 25 - Digital Logic # Digital logic is what it sounds like- it&amp;rsquo;s doing logical operations on digital data - 1&amp;rsquo;s and 0&amp;rsquo;s; True and False. Chain some of (er, a lot of) these logical operations together and you can do anything you want! Want to make your own CPU? Done. Want to make dedicated circuitry to do what your code does but hundreds of times faster? This is the way to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/embedded/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/embedded/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 26 - Embedded Systems # By Make It With Me What is an Embedded System? # [TODO] need source These little devices are Pocket Operators made by Teenage Engineering, they&amp;rsquo;re relatively inexpensive synths that can be chained together, and I think they&amp;rsquo;re a great example of what an embedded system is, but for the sake of clarity, here&amp;rsquo;s how Wikipedia defines it:
An embedded system is a computer system—a combination of a computer processor, computer memory, and input/output peripheral devices—that has a dedicated function within a larger mechanical or electronic system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/parts/</guid>
      <description>24½ - Parts # When thinking about electronics, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to focus on the bits that electricity actually flows though. This chapter is for everything else
Part Codes # Okay, sort of still electrically relevant, but as your peruse your options for parts you&amp;rsquo;ll see some patterns in how things are named, such as diodes starting with a 1N prefix. If you want to know more about that, these links are decent:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/pcb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/circuits/pcb/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 27 - Let&amp;rsquo;s make our own PCB # Printed Circuit Borads look like something reserved for only big business, but that is very much so not the case. It&amp;rsquo;s suprisingly cheap to get smaller boards made, espically if you&amp;rsquo;re okay with waiting a week or two on international shipping. But, let me back up- what even is a PCB?
Well, when anyone first starts with circuits, they go for the ever popular breadboard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/comparch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/comparch/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 37 - Let&amp;rsquo;s make our own CPU # How To Make A CPU - A Simple Picture Based Explanation (RobertElder)
This chapter will be split into three parts:Part 1, understanding the interval workings of a CPU. This is effectively just a computer architecture class, and will be by far the largest section.Part 2, making that CPU on an FPGA.Part 3, making that CPU do something. [TODO] http://www.lighterra.com/papers/modernmicroprocessors/
[TODO] A Density Metric for Semiconductor Technology - past nm for sizing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/compileassemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/compileassemble/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 34 - Compilers and Assemblers # https://lee.earth/til/compiling-c-code-a-step-by-step-guide/
[TODO] Better Firmware with LLVM/Clang
[TODO] Zig cc: a Powerful Drop-In Replacement for GCC/Clang
Common Flags and When to Use them # These flags are not universal, instead they&amp;rsquo;re from GCC. GCC and Clang are the big two compilers you&amp;rsquo;ll see a lot and these flags should be mostly the same between the two. Of course, there are many, many other compilers, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with the common stuff</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/fpga1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/fpga1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 36 - Let&amp;rsquo;s try out programmable logic # Before we get started, please be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve read Chapter 24 - Digital Logic Simulation of an Intel 4004 in TICS (The Integrated Circuit Simulator) a (abandoned?) WIP by Oni, Download the interpreter here, the repo has plenty of examples.
Some similar pixel art simulation tools are wired-logic, reso, wireworld,
[TODO]
Finite State Machines, VHDL, Verilog, FPGA &amp;amp; CPLD internals</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/nonsilicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/nonsilicon/</guid>
      <description>Unpublished - Non-Silicon Computing # Most computers today use integrated circuits which use silicon as a semiconductor. This, historically, was not the only option. In the past, there were some chips made with gallium arsenide (such as those in the Cray-3) though it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be confused with gallium nitride (GaN) which are getting common use not for logic, but for power electronics. Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not just Gallium. Germanium is also a semiconductor which used to be used for transistors and diodes, and there has been modern research into using a silicon–germanium alloy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/reverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/deeper/reverse/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 35 - Reverse Engineering # Software # Anyone know of good resources for learning binary reversing? Not particular tools necessarily, but like theory and how to think @XMPPwocky on Twitter An Opinionated Guide on How To Reverse Engineer Software is decent.
for me personally:
know some assembly, and in particular make sure you know the calling conventions for your platform.
when starting out, do it on binaries you can actually run in a debugger and see what&amp;rsquo;s actually happening at runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/howtolearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/intro/howtolearn/</guid>
      <description>Ⅱ - Learn how to learn # I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep this short and sweet: Nobody learns (effectively) by being shown what to do. You can watch hundreds of hours of people playing guitar, even explaining how they do it, but you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to randomly pick one up and play if you never have before. Furthermore, as much as you can learn from direct reading and instruction, it has its place and limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/arch/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 - Installing Arch Linux # I am working on a new install guide located at
archnew , though it is still a work in progress. The new guide is based on the offical install guide, among other pages from the wiki, and adds running commentry and advice in an attempt to help new users while still sticking to some of the Arch ethos. Some Background # Unlike Windows or Mac which are primarily differentiated by versions (Windows XP, Vista, 7, 10&amp;hellip;), Linux has two important things to look out for:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/archnew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/archnew/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 - Installing Arch Linux # Some Background # ⬤◯◯◯◯◯◯◯◯◯
Unlike Windows or Mac which are primarily differentiated by versions (Windows XP, Vista, 7, 10&amp;hellip;), Linux has two important things to look out for:
The distribution name (Arch, Ubuntu, Mint, Debian, etc.) Kernel version number (5.18 last time this page was updated) So, what do each of these mean?
Well, Linux is actually just the name of the underlying &amp;lsquo;core&amp;rsquo; of the system, known as the kernel, as such, there are literally thousands of Linux variations or &amp;lsquo;distributions&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/firstgoal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/firstgoal/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 - The first goal # Art by @monoxromatik Every journey needs a place to start, and while many may like to start slow, I think a head first approach is best. So that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we&amp;rsquo;re gonna do. The very first thing we&amp;rsquo;re going to do is install a new Operating System (OS)(1) on your computer. This is a pretty involved process. It will require you to Repartition(2) your drive, change settings in your BIOS or UEFI(3), and install a new Bootloader(4).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/git/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5½ - Git. # &amp;hellip; Despite the chapter name, git isn&amp;rsquo;t just a Linux thing - it&amp;rsquo;s actually more of a programming thing, but you&amp;rsquo;ll still probably want to use it for storing your configuration files for Linux, and it&amp;rsquo;s worth learning before you really get into programming, which is why it&amp;rsquo;s here. So, uh, what&amp;rsquo;s git?
The ELI5 of it is that it&amp;rsquo;s a Version Control System, which really just means it can give you the equivalent of save states on your files, like in a video game- and just like a video game, you can save (or go back to a previous save) and have two different branches where you make a different decision in each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3 - Into The Hardware # One of the nifty things about Linux is you don&amp;rsquo;t need to install extra software to check out the deeper parts of your hardware. While on Windows you might need a tool like CPU-Z to look at information about the CPU on Linux you can do it out of the box. Even better, Linux makes changing values and tweaking performance easier, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/architectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/architectures/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3½ - Architectures # Instruction Set Architectures # Today, there are two main computer architectures you&amp;rsquo;ll use x86_64 and ARM. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard this in passing, but you may not know what they are. These are Instruction Set Architectures (ISA), and they define the list of instructions your computer can understand and the basics about how those instructions are laid out.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say we have a fictional computer, really old, that&amp;rsquo;s only 8-bit (most modern systems are 32 or 64bit) this would mean we get eight 1&amp;rsquo;s and 0&amp;rsquo;s to define our instruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/biggerpicture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/biggerpicture/</guid>
      <description>The Bigger Picture # Something that&amp;rsquo;s most people get wrong about computers is thinking that the majority of what makes a computer go faster at something is being able to do math faster. After all, if you can add, divide, multiply, subtract, etc. numbers faster, that&amp;rsquo;s everything a computer does, right? So making math twice as fast means everything is twice as fast? No. Very much so no.
It turns out, the vast majority of what your computer does is not math and logic, but just moving data around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/buying/</guid>
      <description>10 - How to Know What to Buy # I&amp;rsquo;ve tried writing this like 5 times, trying to work around the fucked up GPU market, I just can&amp;rsquo;t even show the process of finding parts when things are this messed up. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend a pre-built system either, since DELL is awful, but so is everyone else. Fuck this. Unless you literally don&amp;rsquo;t have a computer, just don&amp;rsquo;t buy anything for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cooling/</guid>
      <description>8 - Cooling # Computers, who&amp;rsquo;d&amp;rsquo;ve guessed, use power. Shocker, right? Well, using power means making heat, and we need to get that away from the components as fast as we can - if they stay hot they&amp;rsquo;ll throttle down to a lower speed, and it degrades their quality over time. Not good.
So, what are our options?
Air Cooling # 3-pin and 4-pin fans # Air flow VS Static Pressure # Fan size # Noise # Smaller → Louder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/cpu/</guid>
      <description>1 - The CPU # Note, there&amp;rsquo;s more the a CPU on some of these boards. On the big one, only the square thing in the middle is the CPU, on the pi-0 (the board with the HDMI and USB Ports) the CPU is under the metal heatsink - and in truth the CPU is actually an SOC (System On a Chip) - more on that in a bit. Finally, on the blue board, the CPU is only the black chip in the middle, though in this case it is again the definition is blurred, as in truth this is a microcontroller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/gpu/</guid>
      <description>4 - Graphics &amp;amp; Acceleration # Photo by Thomas Foster, depicting an Nvidia RTX 3070 Hi Gamers!
This page will obviously appeal to you, those that drive the sales of these chonky, expensive cards; however, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that this page is about all graphics &amp;amp; acceleration- from the iGPU in low power systems to the compute cards used for AI research and wasteful crypto mining. Still, this more in depth knowledge will probably be helpful in helping you extract more FPS from your GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/legacy/</guid>
      <description># Legacy Hardware? # There&amp;rsquo;s some old hardware almost everyone is familiar with: Floppy disks and big ol&amp;rsquo; CRT monitors became a big part of what defined a computer, and became recognizable enough that the shape of a floppy disk is still the standard save icon today. But still, why care?
In history classes, the line “Those who don&amp;rsquo;t know history are destined to repeat it.&amp;quot; but I think there&amp;rsquo;s a bigger reason here: those who don&amp;rsquo;t understand the legacy hardware have no idea what the fuck is going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/motherboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/motherboard/</guid>
      <description>3 - The Motherboard # This is an older motherboard, but still new enough to have modern parts. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by looking at the the most obvious physical features and move to smaller things from there.
The most obvious thing to point out is the size of the motherboard. This is a mATX motherboard, which is considered the normal size for most systems. Most gaming or DIY computers will use full size ATX motherboards, which look very similar but are a bit longer vertically, allowing for more expansion slots - those horizontal black bars - among other features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/network/</guid>
      <description>6 - Network Interfaces # Pictured here are three Network Interface Cards (NICs). The three on the left are for Wi-Fi (though some of this form factor may include Bluetooth as well) while the one on the right has an Ethernet port for wired access. Most computer&amp;rsquo;s will not have a separate card for the wired interface, though, as most motherboard&amp;rsquo;s have a wired network interface built in.
NICs also include the wireless chipset used for connecting to a cell tower and really any radio communication device in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/peripherals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/peripherals/</guid>
      <description>9 - Peripherals # USB # The below two videos do a really good job of covering USB, but there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I want to add: Some cables lie! They don&amp;rsquo;t have data pins at all, and instead are only carry power. This can be a massive pain when you have a box of cables and need to know which ones are &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; cables.
While there are testers available on Amazon, almost all of them are USB2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/power/</guid>
      <description>7 - Power Supply # The Power Supply Unit or PSU does what you think. It takes power from the wall and turns it into power for the computer. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the chapter on voltage and current, so I&amp;rsquo;ll spare some of the details, but effectively you want a power supply that can deliver plenty of power and that has clean power. A given power supply usually has a rating like &amp;lsquo;500w&amp;rsquo; for 500 watts, but this is usually a bad indicator, as they could be referring to multiple things- you see a desktop power supply usually outputs multiple voltages (-12, +12, +5, +3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/ram/</guid>
      <description>2 - RAM # Note, that some RAM sticks, especially the full size ones, have metal heat spreaders on top of them. In gaming computer especially it&amp;rsquo;s common for these to have RGB lights as well. This is RAM or Random Access Memory. The above two sticks are the normal-sized used in desktop PCs, this form factor is called a DIMM (Dual In-Line Memory Module) while the bottom two are from laptops and are called SO-DIMMS, the placement of the notch is an indicator of the generation of RAM, with nearly all modern ram being a consecutive generation of the DDR standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/hardware/storage/</guid>
      <description>5 - Storage # Pictured here are 3 hard drives, 2 of which are &amp;lsquo;full size&amp;rsquo; at 3.5&amp;quot; and the other a &amp;rsquo;laptop drive&amp;rsquo; at 2.5&amp;quot;, the right most hard drive has been opened up, which has certainly ruined it as dust has gotten in. Below the smaller Hard drive is an NVMe SSD on a carrier card. Under the CD is a micro SD card and a flash drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/howwework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/howwework/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5 - Working on how we work # The Terminal | # In the world of programming, embedded development, and electrical debugging you will inevitably need to understand how to use a terminal/command line at some point. While the text only interface can look intimidating, it has some clear advantages. Namely it&amp;rsquo;s significantly faster to use the cli or &amp;lsquo;command line interface&amp;rsquo; version of many tools. Because of the nature of this guide you will be using the terminal frequently, so for convince sake information on using it effectively has been moved to Appendix A, I highly recommend you read though it after you finish this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxdirtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxdirtree/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4 - Getting Rooted In Linux # We&amp;rsquo;ve been using file in /proc and /dev throughout this, but we never really looked to see what else is in there. Let&amp;rsquo;s do that.
go ahead and open up a terminal and run
1 2 3 4 5 ╭─vega@lyrae ~ ╰─➤ cd /dev ╭─vega@lyrae /dev ╰─➤ ls [Very, Very Long Output here] Alright, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking.
What. The. Actual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/linuxshell/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 1 - Using the Linux Shell # ./missing-semester - The Shell
./missing-semester - Shell Tools and Scripting
./missing-semester - Data Wrangling
Linux Productivity Tools Presentation PDF (Ketan M.)
What The Shell? # Okay, first question you probably have after I&amp;rsquo;ve been using them interchangebly &amp;lsquo;What is a Shell and is it different from a terminal?&amp;rsquo;
Yes, they&amp;rsquo;re different, but before I talk about the shell it&amp;rsquo;s easier to talk about the Terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/otheross/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/otheross/</guid>
      <description>A3 - Other Operating Systems # BSD macOS Serenity Redox React TempleOS Haiku https://awesomekling.github.io/pledge-and-unveil-in-SerenityOS/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/linux/windows/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 2 - Ugh. Windows. # Windows? In a Linux Chapter?
Okay, so, I hate Windows for many, many reasons. Beyond the Candy Crush being bundled and privacy concerns, it&amp;rsquo;s generally just a pain in the ass- and as a Linux user, that&amp;rsquo;s saying something. That said, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably need to do some stuff with it from time to time regardless. So, in this page I want to do three things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/3dprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/3dprint/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 42 - 3D printing, CNC, and making things # 31.1 - Basic making # Wood working # Safety # Cool projects # Lichtenberg Figure Table (Imgur)
Epoxy Inlay and Rustic Compass Butcher Block Countertops (Imgur) (YouTube)
Wood Tables Embedded with Photoluminescent Resin (Mike Warren)
CAD Up Some Shoes But Don&amp;rsquo;t Start From Scratch (Hackaday, DaveMakesStuff) + 3D Printed Shoes Make Bigfoot tracks (Hackaday, Stephan Henrich)
3D Printing Diffraction Gratings (iridescent/rainbow surfaces)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/hamradio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/hamradio/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 43 - Ham Radio # &amp;lsquo;137Mhz&amp;rsquo; by u/CashewHut LORA
2.4Ghz patch antenna
electronically tunable filters
National Radio Quiet Zone (Wikipedia)
https://newhams.info/2017/02/17/rf-connector-types/
question of the day:
Analog TV is shut down in the US, right? so all the over-the-air TV is digital. And existing analog OTA frequencies are getting repurposed to other uses... so what am I seeing on UHF channel 60? it&amp;#39;s got way more structure than the noise everywhere else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/history/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 44 - History # BBS and Tildie Sites # tilde.town: A social network over SSH
Tilde.club
Other Tilde Services?
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mother_of_All_Demos
Adam Savage&amp;rsquo;s Computer History Collection! (YouTube)
Preserving data # https://media.ccc.de/v/31c3_-_6373_-_en_-_saal_6_-_201412291600_-_the_only_thing_we_know_about_cyberspace_is_that_its_640x480_-_olia_lialina#t=3641
Preserving hardware # https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Delay_line_memory
http://www.vcfed.org/forum/forum.php
https://skilldrick.github.io/easy6502/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/mechanical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/making/mechanical/</guid>
      <description>Unpublished - Mechanical Bits # Through all the Engineering pages I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on electrical and programming solutions, because those are what I know, but they are not always the right answer. For example, in this Reddit post the author asks &amp;ldquo;What kind of motor can I use for this? I need a lightweight pole to go from 0 to 90 degrees [as fast as possible]?&amp;rdquo; and the answer really stuck out to me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/algebra/</guid>
      <description>1 - Algebra # This section is a tad bit misnamed, as instead of covering just Algebra I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering most things you&amp;rsquo;d learn in a high school Algebra class along side it, plus probably a bit extra. Number Systems # To get started, let&amp;rsquo;s look at &amp;lsquo;Number Systems&amp;rsquo;. Essentially, there are a variety of &amp;rsquo;types&amp;rsquo; of numbers, rather than get all philosophical let&amp;rsquo;s just dive in and I think you&amp;rsquo;ll get the gist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/calc/</guid>
      <description>4 - Calculus # Introduction To Calculus With Derivatives (adit.io)
Calculus Made Easy by Silvanus P. Thompson
[TODO] limits before video
Below is a 12 video series that totals about 3.25 hours. [The Exponential Function is a Miracle (Mark Dominus)](</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/diffeq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/diffeq/</guid>
      <description> 5 - Differential Equations # Below is a 5 video series that totals about 1.5 hours. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/geometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/geometry/</guid>
      <description>3 - Geometry and Trigonometry # Geometry # Notation # ∥, ⊥,
Trigonometry # Learning Trig playlist on YouTube by &amp;lsquo;The Organic Chemistry Tutor&amp;rsquo;
Notation # 3½ - Topology # But, this is supposed to be about engineering, so why do we need it?
[TODO] topology optimization and generative design
3¾ - Non-Euclidian Spaces # Fractals # https://www.fractal.garden</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/linalg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/linalg/</guid>
      <description>6 - Matrix Theory / Linear Algebra # Below is a 15 video series that totals a bit under 3 hours. Interactive Linear Algebra, text book that actually uses the web Linear Algebra Done Wrong - Sergei Treil @ Brown University
Matrices, Diagrammatically
Linear Algebra - Jim Hefferson
Linear Algebra and Applications: An Inquiry-Based Approach</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/logic/</guid>
      <description> 2 - Discrete Math &amp;amp; Logic # http://discrete.openmathbooks.org/dmoi3/
Math For Programmers (PDF) Notation # https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mathematic_operators
Logic # Many Valued Logic # Fuzzy Logic # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/math/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6 - Math # This section of OpGuides is divided into subsections for easier reading! Just click the little arrow next to the heading to see the full list of chapters
As with all of OpGuides, please skip around as necessary. I suspect the start of this math chapter will be stuff many readers already know, especially those currently in college.
Math 6.1 Algebra 6.2 Logic 6.3 Geometry &amp; Trig 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/newmath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/newmath/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s NEW math! # Math, as I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to convey though these chapters, is more about problem-solving than actual mechanical operations. Part of solving really hard problems is having even weirder intuitions and tools.
/+ Hilbert curves (and the IP map)
/+ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a-767WnbaCQ
/+ Markov Chains
/+ EGG, https://egraphs-good.github.io &amp;amp; DAGs
/+ Annealing + related: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulated_annealing
/+ Marching squares
/+ Slime mold
/+ Chaos/attractors</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/numanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/numanalysis/</guid>
      <description>7 - Numerical Analysis # Bisection Method
Newton&amp;rsquo;s Method
Secant Method
Lagrange Polynomial
Divided Differences
Linear Interpolation, Bilinear Interpolation, Bicubic Interpolation, Spatial Interpolation
Cubic Spline
Numerical Differentiation
Trapezoidal Rule
Simpson&amp;rsquo;s Rule
Romberg Integration
Monte Carlo Method - Algorithm Archive
Condition Number
Least Squares
The Bernstein Basis (Mutual Information, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/probability/</guid>
      <description>10 - Probability/Stats # Seeing Theory: A visual Introduction to probability and statistics Why, where are these used, etc.
bring up music things, part failure rates, tolerances, etc.
Basics # For the following, I&amp;rsquo;ll be using a die roll example, where the events are the total of two die. The Sample Space of this is
\(S = \{2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12\}\) Note, that 1 isn&amp;rsquo;t possible as the lowest is both die being &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/settheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/settheory/</guid>
      <description>9 - Set Theory # The, uh, study of sets. It&amp;rsquo;s not as boring as it sounds, I swear. Set theory is pretty boring. Yes, it brings about ideas of infinity, Sets of numbers (integers, complex numbers, etc.) but frankly, unless you&amp;rsquo;re really into math&amp;rsquo;s nerdy bits and trying to understand the nature of mathematics and all that jazz, there&amp;rsquo;s really only a few bits you need to understand:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/units/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/math/units/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 6½ - Units # By 42CrMo4 and Christoph Päper English units of Length, CC BY-SA 4.0 Scaling, Logarithms and Scientific Notation # Before we get into units, we need to get into scale. That is, the idea of how big or how small something is, usually relative to something else.
In elementary school, you were taught to write the powers of 10 like this:
1 10 100 1000 That is good for regular numbers, but it works against us when we are dealing with numbers that are similar, and all of them are either very large or very small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 39½ - &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo; # Some people will tell you the cloud is the future, that someday everybody will rent computational power from a handful of services like AWS.
These people are nuts.
The cloud is just someone eles&amp;rsquo;s computer. Unless your business is going through a period of extreme growth, it makes no sense to use a cloud provider like AWS or Azure. It does make plenty of sense to buy a VPS (Virtual Private Server) for hosting a website or game server or a personal website like this one, but at scale?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/databases/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 40 - Databases # [TODO] Start with comparison to spreadsheet, explaining &amp;lsquo;NoSQL&amp;rsquo; Vs &amp;lsquo;SQL&amp;rsquo; and that this is Relational vs Non-Relational
[TODO] explain CRUD
CRUD # Create, Read, Update, Delete
SQL # This is Opinionated Guides, so let me be clear, I really, really hate SQL. I don&amp;rsquo;t like OOP in general, and SQL is sorta like object orientation taken further. Add onto this a mostly shit syntax, like, JOINs are objectively weird to read, write, and understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/howyougothere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/howyougothere/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 37.1 - How you got here # So that we have some context through this chapter, lets look at what happens when you visit https://opguides.info (assuming you have a normal network)
You&amp;rsquo;ve already connected to your home network. Let&amp;rsquo;s make some assumptions about your setup:
This is over twisted pair wire (Ethernet), just to keep things simple for now. (Not using Wi-Fi)
Let&amp;rsquo;s also assume IPv4, since IPv6 still isn&amp;rsquo;t used everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/networking/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 38 - Networking # Quick links
Blip - Check latency Speedtest.net - Speed test myexternalip.com - See your external IP portchecker.co - Check if a port is open crt.sh - Certificate search The Basics # To get started, let&amp;rsquo;s just get some basic terminology down and take a look at the bigger picture:
Nodes # These are all the points in the network. There are terminal nodes and intermediate nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/osi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/osi/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 37.2 - The OSI Model # The OSI model of networking is the model of networking most classes will cover. It is slightly different from the one used by the internet, which is the TCP/IP model, but it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more regularly used when talking about networking, so it&amp;rsquo;s the one I&amp;rsquo;ll cover here. Note, the big difference is really just that In the TCP/IP model, the Physical and Data Link Layers are viewed as a unified &amp;lsquo;Network Acces Layer&amp;rsquo;, the Network Layer is called the Internet Layer, The Transport Layer stays the same, and the and The Session, Presentation, and Application layer are all part of a larger Application Layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 41½ - Your Guide to Privacy # &#34; Arguing that you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the right to privacy because you have nothing to hide is no different from saying you don&amp;rsquo;t care about free speech because you have nothing to say. &#34; - Edward Snowden, in his Reddit AMA Privacy online is a joke. No matter what you do, you&amp;rsquo;re still going to be tracked so much that advertisers and the big tech companies (Facebook, Google, Microsoft, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/security/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 41 - Security &amp;amp; Exploitation # I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume at least some prior knowledge here, if you want a quick intro, I recommend going through ./missing-semester-Security so that we can all be on the same page. Often when we think about Exploitation, better known as hacking, we conjure images of a more-punk-than-cyber cyberpunk person clicking away wildly on a keyboard as code flies by, like the 1995 movie, Hackers, and to some extent this isn&amp;rsquo;t wrong, as one look around the floor at DefCon, will show you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/servers/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 39 - Servers! # First of all, let&amp;rsquo;s demystify the servers, they are not something to be afraid of &amp;hellip; they are just normal computers that execute processes, the main difference is that these computers do not have a direct interface, that is: there is no need for them to have peripherals (most of the time) since they only SERVE resources for other needs.
A good example of a server is this one, in which you are reading this, the only function of the server where this content is hosted is to provide it, nothing more and nothing less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/networking/tools/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 37.3 - Networking Tools # Etherape # Wireshark # https://wiki.wireshark.org/CaptureFilters
Enable Packet Diagram View
Nmap # Scapy / Kamene # Kamene
(G)NS # HTTPie # HTTPie (Github) - human-friendly CLI HTTP client for the API era
Tunnels &amp;amp; VPN # bore (Github) - a simple CLI tool for making tunnels to localhost
Further Reading # What happens when&amp;hellip; [Github] - An attempt to answer the age old interview question &amp;ldquo;What happens when you type google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/chem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/chem/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 8 - Chemistry # Super handy periodic table with visualization, atomic mass, melting/boiling points, specific heat, isotopes, etc. (ptable)
This chapter is more or less on hold while I prioritize adding the content I&amp;rsquo;m more familiar with, if you&amp;rsquo;d like, feel free to submit a PR to flesh this section out. Unfortunately, my chemistry education was pretty &amp;lsquo;meh&amp;rsquo;, and I never actually made it to Organic Chem. I have CrashCourse&amp;rsquo;s Chemistry and Organic Chemistry videos on YouTube on my &amp;lsquo;To Watch&amp;rsquo; list, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/othersubjects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/othersubjects/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 9 - &amp;lsquo;The Rest&amp;rsquo; # Finance # [TODO] because making and engineering are expensive, and you probably want to make money, and spend less money.
Music # Music? In a chapter on Engineering? Well, yeah. Hear me out, music is a combination of math and signals.
1 2 3 4 5 EUCLID(m, k): if k = 0: return m else: return EUCLID(k,m mod k) The Euclidean Algorithm Generates Traditional Musical Rhythms (Godfried Toussaint) (PDF) As another example, the Euclidean Algorithm can be used to distribute drum hits to algorithmically make drum beats</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/physics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/prereq/physics/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 7 - Physics # This is still a dumping ground for things I want to write about later, nothing of substance is here yet, sorry about that [TODO] speed vs Velocity vs Acceleration, classical vs relative
Radiocarbon dating (Wikipedia)
Cosmic Microwave Background (Wikipedia)
Natural nuclear fission reactor (Wikipedia)
How Kodak Exposed The Atomic Bomb (YouTube, Veritasium)
Seeing the invisible: Event displays in particle physics
Building a Vortex Tube (This Old Tony, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 15 - Discrete Math, Algorithms, Data Structures, and Not Sucking at Programming ™* # Brute Force Algorithms # Backtracking # [TODO] Directed Acyclic Graphs
[TODO] Finite State Machines
[TODO] e-graphs? https://egraphs-good.github.io
[TODO] http://courses.csail.mit.edu/6.851/
[TODO] &amp;lsquo;Tree Traversal&amp;rsquo; on Algorithm Archive
Divide and Conquer # Master Theorem # Decrease and Conquer # Branch and Bound # Kernelization # Caching # *With some complexity analysis too.
[TODO]
https://www.mattkeeter.com/blog/2021-03-01-happen/
[TODO] I also have discrete math in the chapter 11, math&amp;hellip; not sure what do about this&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/bestpractices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/bestpractices/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11 - Best Practices # Manifesto # Everything should be a tool. A tool transforms data without adding to its source limitations. It&amp;rsquo;s a function: returns an output for a given input. A great tool is ambient. It should disappear and flow through your actions. You should never need it because it&amp;rsquo;s always at your hands. You should never ignore it because it&amp;rsquo;s never in your way. Tools should be adaptable, changeable and personalisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codecont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codecont/</guid>
      <description>THIS PAGE IS BEING REMOVED # Part 3, more advanced high level # Modify the original python program to support a pretty CLI input in a pretty way to make entries and visualize the data collected, parallelize some things, finally add a config file using YAML
Part 4, getting our toes wet with embedded systems # Finally, let&amp;rsquo;s go back and add a com port to the C code and send data to an Arduino (can be simulated) and a TFT to display the currently active task and time elapsed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codeintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/codeintro/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10 - Let&amp;rsquo;s write some Code # Hello! If you&amp;rsquo;re here, you should know you&amp;rsquo;re on a deprecated page. All work has now been refocused on getting the new programming intro (Chapter 10 in the menu bar) to being much, much better than this page ever was. Starting Minimal # Code is mostly math # Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: Code is mostly math. If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you probably just went ugggggghhhhhhh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/commands/</guid>
      <description>Commands # [TODO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>Conclusion # [TODO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/conditionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/conditionals/</guid>
      <description>Conditionals # [TODO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/generation/</guid>
      <description>Code Generation # As I said earlier, there is no way that you can write a proper compiler on your own, due to the amount of work involved.
But new languages are invented by individual people all the time. How is this possible? The answer is, they use a backend framework or library for this part.
This is the part where the Intermediate Representation (IR) comes it. It is determined by the library being used, which means the language itself can be abstracted away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/intermezzo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/intermezzo/</guid>
      <description>Intermezzo # At this point, we have something that is ugly looking, but seems like a real compiler! After all, it does the four stages as promised:
Lexing: the splitting of whitespace and division of tokens Parsing: the creation of the syntax tree based on ordering of operations Translation: a no-op, because the syntax tree is good enough Code Generation: Python &amp;ldquo;machine code&amp;rdquo; as valid infix math, or a JIT library running routines But still, you can&amp;rsquo;t really call this a langauge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/intro/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 22 - Custom Languages # Some people like playing around with new programming languages, or concepts in Programming Language Theory (PLT). In order to do this outside of pure mathematics, anyone who does will have to learn how to write a compiler for their new language.
Unfortunately, compilers are some of the most complex pieces of software out there, along with operating system kernels. Especially when talking about a common compiler for well-established language, there is no way a single guide on the internet can teach you how to write one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/lexing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/lexing/</guid>
      <description>Lexical analysis # The transformation of source code text into a series of tokens is the first task. Much like words in a sentence, each token has a specific meaning that will be used by later phases. It is this meaning that is is being captured, while the exact formatting or other details of the text itself are stripped away.
In our calculator, lexing (as it is called for short) is just one operation: line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/parsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/parsing/</guid>
      <description>Syntax analysis # Our syntax analysis phase, or &amp;ldquo;parsing&amp;rdquo;, is basically a no-op in the current version. This is possible because, thanks to our stack having a &amp;ldquo;guard zero&amp;rdquo; at the bottom, there is really no such thing as a program with only valid tokens that is invalid syntax.
This makes it a very rare language indeed.
Since we are doing math in a specific order of operations, it would be easy to make this into a tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/prelude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/prelude/</guid>
      <description>Prelude: A Reverse Polish Notation Calculator # In order to get a footing, we&amp;rsquo;ll start with an example: a calculator that uses postfix operator notation, sometimes called &amp;ldquo;reverse polish notation.&amp;rdquo;
In this calculator, all arguments are placed onto a stack. Whenever an operator occurs, it pops values off the stack at that point, performs the operation, and pushes the answer back on.
All operations are binary, so they take two operands from the stack and replace it with one result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/subroutines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/subroutines/</guid>
      <description>Subroutines # [TODO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/translation/</guid>
      <description>Syntax-Directed Translation # This stage is where we get an opportunity to modify and restructure the tree from a syntax point of view, into a semantic point of view.
To avoid &amp;ldquo;How to Draw an Owl Step 2: Finish the Owl&amp;rdquo;, we will continue with the interpteter theme for the moment. Instead of figuring out all the analyses required, let&amp;rsquo;s ask: what intermediate representation can be interpreted by Python?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/compilers/variables/</guid>
      <description>Variables # [TODO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/data/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 15½ - Data, Encodings, Compression, etc. # When you write code, you&amp;rsquo;ll inevitably be working with input and output of some sort - even if it&amp;rsquo;s just text. This is always more complicated than it seems. For example, text processing is easy, right?
🚫, 🅘🄣&amp;rsquo;s 🇳ot.
Even text encoding is a massive pain, unless you can ensure you only need to (and do) process basic ASCII characters, that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/ethics/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 11½ - Ethics &amp;amp; Copyright # Ethics # Programming is awesome. If you get into creative coding, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use it to make art. You&amp;rsquo;ll likely use it to automate tasks you find boring. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you might use it to make your own website or start to make products you intend to sell. That&amp;rsquo;s great. But there are a few things you need to consider as what you make becomes more professional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fixxingissuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/fixxingissuses/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 13 - Fixing Issues &amp;amp; Debugging # Alright, so your code/electronics/computer/life was working fine just a second ago, and now it&amp;rsquo;s just not working at all. Take a deep breath, and relax. Let&amp;rsquo;s work though this.
🦆 Grab a rubber duck # This won&amp;rsquo;t always be applicable, but assuming it&amp;rsquo;s a system- code, or electronics, or a math problem, something that can be analyzed - explain it. Out loud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/funcprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/funcprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 20 - (((())(()((()(())))))) # What is Functional Programming? # Most of the programming languages in this section up until now have been imperative programming languages. Programs are a series of instructions: do this, then do that, then do the other thing.
Functional programming languages are another type of language. Like math, they simply define sets, relationships, and then have a process for doing things based on &amp;ldquo;answering questions&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;getting to a result&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/game/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 21 - Game Programming &amp;amp; Design # https://www.gameuidatabase.com/index.php
https://www.riotgames.com/en/urf-academy/curriculum-guide
COMP4300 - Game Programming (David Churchill, YouTube)
Engines &amp;amp; Frameworks # Both 2d and 3d # Godot
Luxe
Heaps
fine. I&amp;rsquo;ll mention Unity and Unreal, but, like, I hate that the two make up such a huge chunk of the market
Unreal Engine
Unity
2d # LEd engine - &amp;ldquo;LEd is a modern and open-source 2D level editor, specifically designed for indie devs&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/gitcicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/gitcicd/</guid>
      <description>16 - Git, Testing, CI, and CD # Testing # @jnesselr replying to @alicegoldfuss (Nov 13, 2018) +----------------------------------------------------+ |Me: *does major refactor* | |Tests: ✓ | |Me: I don&amp;#39;t believe you | +----------------------------------------------------+ [Suspended User] +----------------------------------------------------+ |Me: *deliberately breaks something, just to be sure*| |Tests: ✓ | |Me: oh no | +----------------------------------------------------+ @boo_radley +----------------------------------------------------+ |Me: *changes nothing* | |Tests: ✗ | |Me: oh no | +----------------------------------------------------+ [Suspended User] +----------------------------------------------------+ |Me: *runs tests again* | |Tests: ✔ | |Me: oh no no no | +----------------------------------------------------+ src: https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/guiprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/guiprog/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 18 - Graphical Programming # [TODO] Graphics Programming on badd10de.dev
Let&amp;rsquo;s start in a way that&amp;rsquo;s incredibly simple, and abstract away all the hard stuff at first by using a tool kit called &amp;lsquo;Processing&amp;rsquo;, which is available under that name from the community repo in arch. The default IDE that comes with it is awful to work in though, so go ahead and open up VSCode and grab the Processing Language add on, then in VSCode open up a new workspace folder and make a file called processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog0intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog0intro/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.0 - Let&amp;rsquo;s Write Some Code # Knowing how to program will give you deep control over the most advanced tool mankind has ever made: The computer. More over, because we use computers as extensions of our own minds (and as a collective, with the Internet) it will literally expand your ability to process information as you&amp;rsquo;re no longer limited to the inputs and computation systems that other programmers have built for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog10/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.10 - The rest of the Owl # Okay, so, we&amp;rsquo;ve gone over types and functions and operations and all of that jazz, but there are a few little pieces that have been left out, so, let&amp;rsquo;s do some of them rapid fire
Multiple files # In any language, once your code gets big enough, working in one really long file is going to become a clusterfuck.
Python # In python, this is stupidly easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog1math/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog1math/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.1 - It&amp;rsquo;s math? # Let&amp;rsquo;s talk math and look at some real code.
I think a lot of people over estimate how hard it is to handle even the more complex math. As an example, let&amp;rsquo;s estimate π. (You should never actually do this in code - just use a library which will provide a pre-computed value of pi anywhere you need it!) To do this, we need a formula.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog2turtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog2turtle/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.2 - Turtles All The Way Down # Low Level and High Level Programming # There are two types of programming, high level and low level.
High level programmers make things where the hardware doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. The code they write runs everywhere, and the users directly see it and interact with it.
Low level developers write code that runs directly on the hardware. The software inside the controller on your mouse to the driver on your computer for responding to that input, that&amp;rsquo;s all low level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog3tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog3tools/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.3 - Getting Tools # As mentioned before, you&amp;rsquo;ll be learning both Python and C. This means we need to get the tools necessary for working with each. If you&amp;rsquo;re following along with OpGuides as a whole and have Linux setup, this will be easy. If you&amp;rsquo;re on Windows it&amp;rsquo;s not hard but there are some annoying steps we&amp;rsquo;ll need to jump through.
Getting Code To Run # Arch Linux Run pacman -Syu gcc python, then you&amp;rsquo;ll want to grab visual-studio-code-bin from the AUR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog4comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog4comments/</guid>
      <description>10.4 - Getting to know our tools # Okay, we now have the ability to run and debug code but we still need set up and go over a few features in your text editor (VSCode) to make things easier. Plus, now&amp;rsquo;s a good time to introduce comments and indentation and why they matter in code.
This may seem a bit out of order, but at this stage there&amp;rsquo;s problems with prioritizing how much to learn about the tool versus the craft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog5two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog5two/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.5 - Leaning Two Languages At Once # Back in the Into The Hardware section we looked at some of the inner workings of the CPU, and briefly looked into how the CPU only understands machine code, 1&amp;rsquo;s and 0&amp;rsquo;s that make up individual instructions. Now, there&amp;rsquo;s absolutely no reason to ever think at that low of a level, the lowest you should ever care to look at, as mentioned there, is assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog6types/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog6types/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.6 - What&amp;rsquo;s a Type? &amp;amp; Going Down Rabbit Holes # Alright, I&amp;rsquo;ll cut to the chase. When programming, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to deal with types. On the last page, there was a mix of types, int, uint8_t, float, and char all make appearances. While the exact names of each type and what they&amp;rsquo;re capable of may vary a bit from language to language and platform to platform understanding the basics here will help you out a lot, so, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the C language and look at ints</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog7logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog7logic/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.7 - ＬＯＧＩＣ &amp;amp; Functions # For this page, If you see that lines are ending with a semicolon, ;, then that code is C. If they don&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s Python. Would you like to speak to an Operator? # The very first thing to understand before we can get to more intersting things is the list of operations available to us.
This includes the operations your used to - addition, subtraction, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog8oo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog8oo/</guid>
      <description>10.8 - Data Structures, Object Orientation, &amp;amp; Encodings # Why not just structs? # C is a very low level language and only lets you make structs. Structs are fine, but they have some annoying properties, particularly in separating data from how you interact with it, making it difficult to make complex abstractions where you can be sure that data that should only be internal to a structure isn&amp;rsquo;t exposed, or that the data can&amp;rsquo;t be changed in an invalid way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog9stdlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/prog9stdlib/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10.9 - The Standard Library # Yunno&amp;rsquo; how you&amp;rsquo;ve been using print() and printf() all over the place? Well, those are functions, but where are they from?!
Well, for C, in printf()&amp;rsquo;s case it&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious - you can&amp;rsquo;t use it unless you have #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; at the top of the file, so, clearly your computer has that file, and the associated .c file, somewhere. And frankly? That&amp;rsquo;s good enough for the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/progendreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/intro/progendreal/</guid>
      <description>10.11 - &amp;ldquo;Real&amp;rdquo; Programs # So, you now mostly know all the fundamental building blocks used to write basically everything out there.
But&amp;hellip; not really?
The thing is, almost any program of moderate complexity is going to rely on libraries to provide extra, (hopefully) well tested, performant, hard to write functionality. Plus, most programs don&amp;rsquo;t exist in a vacuum: you may need to hook into a database, send packets over the internet, check for malicious user input, write to files, encrypt data, use an API to interact with a game engine, or even write in a different language and call one language&amp;rsquo;s code from another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/languages/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 3 - Programming Languages # for (🥚 = 1; 🥚 &amp;lt; 🐔; 🥚++){ //whatever } Hello nerds,
Before you get on my case, I know this isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete list, so it&amp;rsquo;s possible your favorite language isn&amp;rsquo;t on it. Hell, a complete list can&amp;rsquo;t even really exist. Still, there are a lot of cool languages I didn&amp;rsquo;t put here, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for some weird but not incredibly weird languages see Awesome Programming Languages (GitHub), though note even it doesn&amp;rsquo;t include the obvious - like C and Java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lifeofcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lifeofcode/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 12 - Life Of Code # Building # The C Build Process # I&amp;rsquo;m going to jump right in here, so things are going to be a bit brutal to understand for a bit. I&amp;rsquo;ll break things down, but I need to give the high-level view first! As we saw way back Hardware→CPU , your computer doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand instructions like printf(), so ultimately the code you write has to get turned into something your computer understands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lowlvl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/lowlvl/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 14 - Low Level Programming # Ashlyn Black&amp;rsquo;s C Cheat Sheet
&amp;lsquo;C Programming&amp;rsquo; on badd10de.dev
Why C? # This chapter of OpGuides will be mostly C, but, why? Well, there&amp;rsquo;s only really a few options for learning low level programming that make sense to start with. C, C++, Rust are the &amp;lsquo;big three&amp;rsquo; that come to mind. C is what is most popular(1). Its spec is small, it&amp;rsquo;s been kept minimal, and it&amp;rsquo;s got a ton of tools to help you learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/multithread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/multithread/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 17 - We&amp;rsquo;ve got cores, let&amp;rsquo;s use em&#39; # [TDOO] Motivations from Moore&amp;rsquo;s law, Blocking I/O,
[TODO] start with process forking via syscall - show it
https://lemire.me/blog/2020/01/30/cost-of-a-thread-in-c-under-linux/
C++ coroutines
not really threading, but process children
SIMD, https://nullprogram.com/blog/2021/12/04/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/shaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/programming/shaders/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 19 - Shaders # The Book Of Shaders GLSL 2D Tutorials by Vug Here for VRChat Stuff? Cool! VR chat is a really neat platform to work with and it&amp;rsquo;s really fun to be able to hold or walk around your art. Unfortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s some added complexity that comes with handling VR, Unity, and even just 3D stuff outright that, all together, takes a hot minute to build up to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/aiml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/aiml/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 33 - Fine, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about AI # This chapter is very much a work in progress, and is really more of just a list of topics, despite how much content there appears to be. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to have code examples under each concept as well, as otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s like reading a fucking math textbook from hell.In the meantime, please see https://sebastianraschka.com/blog/2021/dl-course.html#l01-introduction-to-deep-learning for a good intro to Deep Learning [TODO] https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/commsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/commsys/</guid>
      <description>29 - Communication Systems # This chapter is currently just a stub. I&amp;rsquo;m currently taking a comm systems class at Uni and will be putting the results of my notes as well as external resources into here at some point. What is a communication system? # For the purposes of this page, we&amp;rsquo;re talking about systems that transmit signals over a medium- so that might be your voice over the air, a radio signal though the vacuum of space, or ultrasonic waves under the water as sonar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/compvision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/compvision/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 32 - Computer Vision # This page is still pretty empty, in the meantime, check out The Ancient Secrets of Computer Vision by Joseph Redmon and Ali Farhadi
As an aside, Joseph Redmon is an absolute genius, and the main brain behind You Only Look Once: Unified, Real-Time Object Detection which sort of revolutionized the computer vision with AI space, yet, his resume looks like this
This is to say the man is an absolute badass and I could not be more confident in my recommendation of his course</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/controlsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/controlsys/</guid>
      <description>31 - Control Systems # What are control systems? Well, the easiest way to answer that is to list the things control systems typically do:
What Can Control Systems do? # Amplify an input: # ex: Pluck a tiny string on a guitar, get an earth shaking output from the speaker Reduce the complexity of user input or change its location # ex: Floor button on an elevator- you don&amp;rsquo;t need to input a height off the ground for what floor you want to be on, nor do you need to enter values to compensate for how quickly it should get to its max speed or how fast it should slow down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/dsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/dsp/</guid>
      <description>30 - Digital Signal Processing # Spectral Audio Signal Processing by JULIUS O. SMITH III at the Center for Computer Research in Music and Acoustics (CCRMA) The Scientist and Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Digital Signal Processing By Steven W. Smith, Ph.D.
Awesome MusicDSP (Github)
Tom Erbe, Design the Erbe Verb (YouTube)
https://zserge.com/posts/etude-in-c/ &amp;amp; https://zserge.com/posts/beep/
Diospyros - Search-based compiler for high-performance DSP programming
Think DSP - DSP in Python, Free book</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/sigandsys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/signals/sigandsys/</guid>
      <description>28 - Signals &amp;amp; Systems # When I took ECEN 304 Signals &amp;amp; Systems Ⅰ with the fantastic Dr. Sayood at UNL I remember how in awe I was at how he concisely he managed to describe the core idea of this class. While I can not hope to convey the same level of brilliance or inspiration, I do hope that my poor attempt at mimicking his introduction to the course may be of value:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/cheat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/cheat/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 3 - Cheat Sheets and quick info # Electrical Part Tables # [TODO]
package types
reading specs
datasheets
Nice Libraries &amp;amp; Resources # Please don&amp;rsquo;t use Electron&amp;hellip; # Ultralight - &amp;ldquo;Next-generation HTML renderer for apps and games&amp;rdquo;
Muon - &amp;ldquo;GPU based Electron on a diet&amp;rdquo;
Multi-Lang # NotCurses (It&amp;rsquo;s not Ncurses) - &amp;ldquo;blingful character graphics/TUI library. definitely not curses.&amp;rdquo;
C # Awesome-C - &amp;ldquo;A curated list of awesome C frameworks, libraries, resources and other shiny things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/job/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 5 - Getting a Job in Engineering # &#34;Recently, I was asked if I was going to fire an employee who made a mistake that cost the company $600,000. No, I replied, I just spent $600,000 training him. Why would I want somebody to hire his experience?&#34; - Thomas John Watson Sr., IBM
[TODO] literally this entire page is TODO. I&amp;rsquo;m just making it as a place to dump links for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/latex/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 6 - \(\LaTeX\) &amp;amp; Markdown # Like the kink? # \(\LaTeX\) , pronounced Lay-Tech, is a document writing and formatting &amp;rsquo;language&amp;rsquo; that acts pretty different from MS Word. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily used for writing fancy math equations, academic, journal, or conference papers, as such, you might have to use it at some point to conform to one standard or another (like IEEE).
As an example of what \(\LaTeX\) formatting looks like, check this equation out:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/resources/</guid>
      <description>Appendix 4 - Other Great Resources # Conventions # https://www.emfcamp.org
https://media.ccc.de/
News Sites # Serializer.io (Aggregate of Hacker News, Ars, Reddit, Macrumors, and Lobste.rs )
Hacker News
Hackaday
Slashdot
Snopzu
https://n-o-d-e.news/
Forums # https://lobste.rs/
https://stackoverflow.com/
http://textfiles.com/
https://glitch.com/
Learning Linux # https://linuxjourney.com
Youtube # ElectroBoom
CNLohr
N-O-D-E
LiveOverflow
Tom Scott
bigclive
AdoredTV
3Blue1Brown
Bryan Lunduke
Level1Techs
Crash Course: Computer Science, from PBS
Podcasts # https://theamphour.com/
Hacker Public Radio
GitHub info pages # Hacker Laws</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/wrappingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/wrappingup/wrappingup/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 45 - Where To Go From Here? # Hey, so, you made it. I can&amp;rsquo;t give you a degree. But, I&amp;rsquo;m proud of you. Even if you skipped a chapter or two, you still put in work to improve yourself and learn something. That&amp;rsquo;s cool.
But, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re thinking &amp;ldquo;Okay, but now what?&amp;rdquo;
Integrating other interests # There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to life than computers and code and electronics and making and hacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/hidden/jaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/hidden/jaki/</guid>
      <description> 󱤐󱤾󱥍󱥠󱥔 # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Cadey Ratio # 3/10/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Cadey. Your blog at christine.website/blog shows that you really have a wide range of interests. So, to get started, what are you passionate about and why? I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about making computers understandable. We work with these impossibly complex mechanical creations like they are nothing. They dominate our culture. With the onset of COVID, the internet has gone from an essential part of our lives to a vital method of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/cendyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/cendyne/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Cendyne # 12/30/2022
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Cendyne. Your blog at Cendyne.dev has a mix of crytography and tips for leadership and planning. Other than those things, what are your interests? What are you passionate about and why? Within tech, security is an ever evolving source of new things to see. I listen to podcasts every other day that mention the new details on where Lockbit affiliates are targeting hospitals, patch this and that, an analysis of some NSO malware, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/kell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/kell/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Kell Bengal # 7/27/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Kell. I know you work on robots, and teach others to do so as well, and are from the continent where everything wants to kill you, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know much else: How would you describe yourself? What are you passionate about and why? I would describe myself as an engineer, first and foremost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Loial Otter # 9/23/2018
Introduction:
I&amp;rsquo;m Matthew or LoialOtter, a crazy person up in western Canada who likes to make stuff. I work at Kron Technology as an engineer mainly in FPGA, electronics design and hardware design.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have any credentials except a certificate in baking and pastry arts. I&amp;rsquo;m self-taught mostly due to not being ever able to afford going to school. I suggest others do when the have the opportunity but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolutely required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/paulshapera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/paulshapera/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Paul Shapera # 2/17/2023
Paul Shapera is a composer, musician, and storyteller known for his unique musical style, which incorporates elements of classical, rock, electronica, and more. His most well-known works include the New Albion and Post-Human series, which are both sprawling concept albums that blend together music and storytelling to create immersive musical worlds.
Shapera&amp;rsquo;s music is known for its intricate plotlines, complex characters, and exploration of themes such as transhumanism, love, loss, and redemption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Soatok Dreamseeker # 12/3/2020
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Soatok. Your blog at https://soatok.blog shows that you&amp;rsquo;re a furry crypto nerd, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to hear how you&amp;rsquo;d put it, so, to get started, can you describe yourself? Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m asked, I usually say something to the effect of, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a security engineer with a dhole fursona that sometimes writes about cryptography on my furry blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/spg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/spg/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Annie of Sex Positive Gaming # 01/07/2022
Annie is the creator behind the Sex Positive Gaming YouTube channel where she primarily reviews adult games and occasionally streams SFW game play. Her channel is still relatively new, having only started in February. In this time she has release over 120 videos ranging from game reviews to explainers of sexual topics all with the theme of &amp;ldquo;No Shaming, Just Gaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/taxbadger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/taxbadger/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Laguna of Tax Badger, LLC # 08/26/2021
﻿﻿
Laguna Crale is a bright pink Tax Badger that has made a name for himself with Tax Badger, LLC where he has made waves in the furry artist and NSFW content creator communities for being open and accepting of these professions. He&amp;rsquo;s freely given helpful pointers on his Twitter, @TaxBadgerLLC to help those questioning how to handle transitioning from making content as a hobby to making it a real, legal self-employment career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics # Distortion # How Distortion Works in Music (Ben Sheron&amp;rsquo;s Blog)
Dynamics &amp;amp; Transients # When thinking of effects, our lil&amp;rsquo; brains like to think about them as being volume and having a nice simple relationship with what comes out. Distortions are not that.
First, they do sound massively different depending on how much volume and the frequency content on the input. That&amp;rsquo;s why in the above video he mentions that putting an EQ before and after a distortion that would normally cancel each other out can still sound wildly different than no EQ at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</guid>
      <description>Filters (LP, HP, BP, Notch) # See the signal processing chapters. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do real time DSP and if you want to modulate the cutoff, you&amp;rsquo;re probably stuck with an IIR. FWIW, the delay of an FIR means the linear phase is often worse than not anyway. If licencing isn&amp;rsquo;t an issue, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to start with at least https://www.musicdsp.org/en/latest/Filters/index.html or really any DSP library. Implimenting a well performing filter isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/meta/</guid>
      <description>Meta # Mid-Side # https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dD6_Bajj2DI
Gain-Staging # Gain staging is the practice of setting the gain or level of each stage in a signal chain, such as in a mixer or a sound system, to an optimal level. This is important because it ensures that the signal remains at a consistent level as it passes through each stage of the signal chain, which can help to avoid distortion and other problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</guid>
      <description>Misc Effects # Auto-Tune # Doing autotune in code is well beyond the scope of a small comment. Outside of just throwing AI at the problem - witch is likely to sound god awful - there&amp;rsquo;s no magic bullet here. It&amp;rsquo;s spectral analysis hell. Given it&amp;rsquo;s basically a meme now, I assume you know what Auto-Tune is. What you may not realize is that not all auto-tune is, well, auto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</guid>
      <description>Time Based Effects # Delay # There are a million ways to make a delay that&amp;rsquo;s weird. Most basic? Make a ring buffer and add the signals, probably with a dry/wet mix. Less basic? IDK, add in multilpe taps on the ring buffer? Use random samples in the buffer? Change the sample rate of the buffer? Reverse the buffer occassionally? Go nuts. Delay is basically echo. Take a sound in, and repeat it it it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</guid>
      <description>Trivial Effects # Tremolo # This is probably the easiest to understand audio effect. Put simply, fade the volume in and out automatically. This can be done at different speeds (really fast for a &amp;lsquo;deep&amp;rsquo; effect or slow for something pad-like) and with a bias so that the volume never completely cuts. It can also refer to a playing style where the same note is struck rapidly, leading to a similar effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstarted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstarted/</guid>
      <description>Getting Our Hands Dirty # Music, like any creative endeavor, requires you keep your left and right brains equally talkative.
Logical Mixing parts together Studying music theory Getting core components of the song laid out Practicing tecnique on an instrument Writing lyrics with good timings and structure Creative Using weird sound sources Combining effects Finding inspiration outside of music Adding fun frills to the song Writing vivid, emotional lyrics If you know that you&amp;rsquo;re a creative type, try to focus on the science and math and technique of things more on these pages and as you practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstartedcont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstartedcont/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our Adventure # Picking up where we left off,
This lil&amp;rsquo; synth works, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give us much control, and unlike a real instrument, after we let go of the key it just immediately stops. Similarly, most real instruments have a either a bit of a pluck at the start or a more gentle fade in.
This leads us to the idea of envelopes. In music, you&amp;rsquo;ll often want to draw a shape that evelopes a signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</guid>
      <description>The Esoteric # feedback only, no input. i love this instrument. pic.twitter.com/IR6lmxZGHJ
&amp;mdash; 𝒆𝒎𝒎𝒂 (@HECKSCAPER) July 31, 2020 𝐡𝐨𝐰 𝐢𝐭 𝐰𝐨𝐫𝐤𝐬: pedal rig rundown &amp;amp; building a sound (Emma Essex)
A neat on-guitar effects board (Instagram, ian.costabile)
Why To Modular With Guitar (YouTube, Knobs)
Otamatone Metal - Rob Scallon
Theorbo - The enormous 14 string lute (YouTube)
Double-sided Guitar Jam (YouTube)
Octobasse: A really, really big upright bass (YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</guid>
      <description>Percussion # Theory # Before I even dive into Percussion, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out how generic the term is. Just looking at the Wikipedia page for drum kit, you&amp;rsquo;ll see this: Drum Kit page on Wikipedia and clearly that&amp;rsquo;s still not an exhaustive list. Just off the top of my head I can see it lacks the Cajon or Taiko as acoustic instruments, let alone anything more specific than electronic drum, which can make for a class all its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</guid>
      <description>Strings # Guitars # Picture of my character by Alex the Nerd Bird Acoustic, Electric, Acoustic-Electric? # Hollow Body, Solid Body? # Pickups? # Strings? # [TODO]
Nylon vs plain vs wound, metal types, coated. Gauges. https://blog.ernieball.com/strings/what-string-gauges-should-you-be-playing/ . This page does reference neck length, so keep that in mind too!
My recommendation, first and foremost, is try them. Strings are cheap, swap &amp;rsquo;em out, try each for a month, note your experiences before and after- how they felt, sounded, if they left your fingers sore, if pitch bending was fun, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</guid>
      <description>Synthesizers # I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about FM, additive, subtractive, etc. in Sound Sources. Here I want to go into how they fit into a song, the idea of pads, leads, bass. As well as how a lot of famous sounds have been done and what some of the most famous synths are. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to cover some of why some newer synths are exciting, like the Hydrasynth, Continumm, Norand Mono, Subharmonicon, Polygogo,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</guid>
      <description>Wind # What is a Wind Instrument? # A wind instrument is a musical instrument that contains some type of resonator (usually a tube) in which a column of air is set into vibration by the player blowing into (or over) a mouthpiece set at or near the end of the resonator. The pitch of the vibration is determined by the length of the tube and by manual modifications of the effective length of the vibrating column of air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/intro/</guid>
      <description>Bang!. Zwoop. Bada-dap-bap. # Here&amp;rsquo;s a sine wave.
I want you to try something. Put your foot back up on your heel and each time you see a new peak, tap the ground. Play a non existent kick drum to each new peak. (or just tap a finger on your desk)
To some people, keeping this beat is difficult. To some it will come naturally. Either is fine. This could be the tempo of a song, the metronome that everything is playing in time to, and it&amp;rsquo;s just a wave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/lies/</guid>
      <description>I lied # Well, sort of. I haven&amp;rsquo;t told you anything that&amp;rsquo;s wrong, but I have been omitting something.
The software we&amp;rsquo;re using, VCV Rack, is very weird. It lacks many features that most people expect in a DAW - Digital Audio Workstation. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk significantly more about DAWs in a coming page, but I need to bring them up now because there&amp;rsquo;s some things that VCV absolutely does not do well that will make creating full songs that sound like music you&amp;rsquo;re probably used to unnecessarily difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/lyrics/</guid>
      <description>Lyrics &amp;amp; Vocals # Lyrics and just sung poetry! - Some moron that has never made music Oh fuck directly off. This is poetry:
They thought there be seven and they&#39;re right. There is seven sins without I I come from a place that many do find Heroes and villains find me inside When they do what they do for family Regardless of who dies Blood is my name l o Many families have cried o r d i e n d once so dear tossed aside Blood is my name, the sin of o n d s undeserved I&#39;m a sin that lurks unheard Religious and Righteous often mistaken Use my name as if it is not forsaken Do not think that blood is a bond to never be broken I find my way to bring many to do things that should never be spoken How should that be sung, pray tell?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</guid>
      <description>MIDI in Detail # Musical Instrument Digital Interface, or MIDI is what it sounds like, the primary way to get data between devices digitally. Want to tell a hardware synth to play a sequence you arranged on your computer? MIDI. Want to play notes into your computer using a keyboard? MIDI. Want to sequence drums, with varying &amp;lsquo;velocity&amp;rsquo; on each hit? MIDI.
Sounds Great?
For the most part, yeah. Everything works together and you can make all your hardware speak the same language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</guid>
      <description>Piracy? # Plugins++ # Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not the police. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care what you do on your system. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to outright condone you to find pirated versions of music software, though- in part for liability, but mostly because you absolutely will get a virus. That said, some sites are more reputable than others, and if you&amp;rsquo;re careful, you can probably yoink at least a few things. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</guid>
      <description>Psychoacoustics and Cultural Associations # When we hear music, we don&amp;rsquo;t hear individual sine waves and sum them up. We don&amp;rsquo;t hear instruments devoid of context, either- a ukulele carries a different cultural meaning than a mandolin. We also don&amp;rsquo;t just hear what comes out the speakers as plainly as basic frequencies. Our ears process what we here. Our ears take in the reverb of the room, ignore sounds before and after drum hits, find speech in sounds that weren&amp;rsquo;t meant to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/seqandmidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/seqandmidi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing &amp;amp; Midi # MIDI In Detail covers the technical bits of MIDI in much more detail, but you&#39;ll still probably want to read this this first if you don&#39;t know what MIDI even is. Sequencing # The definition of a sequence is pretty obvious, but don&amp;rsquo;t be misled by the name- a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; is not always just a list of notes to be played one after the other. Sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s overlap, gaps (rests), bends from one note to another (legato) and almost always information about how hard a note is pressed and how long it should be held for are saved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</guid>
      <description>Digital Audio Workstations+ # A Digital Audio Workstations is software that allows you to record and edit audio, host and play digital instruments, arrange the parts in a timeline, and mix the audio together. The most common DAWs you&amp;rsquo;ll see are Ableton Live (Often called just &amp;ldquo;Ableton&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Live&amp;rdquo;) and FL Studio, but there are plenty of other options as well, many of which are listed below.
The definition of a DAW is a bit fuzzy, as tools like VCV Rack and Audacity- both of which we&amp;rsquo;ve seen previously- have features that make them very DAW like and can be used to make full tracks (assuming you have hardware instruments to record into Audacity)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</guid>
      <description>Programmable Music Tools # Before getting into this list, I also want to point out that there&amp;rsquo;s an endless number of programmable music sequencing tools which can be found built into VST plugins, larger audio software, and even video games. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly fond of the huge number of interesting sequencers for VCV Rack, such as Quad Algorithmic Rhythm Generator, Entropia, Fate, Marbles, and Orca&amp;rsquo;s Heart - just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</guid>
      <description>Plugins # This page is a massive work in progress. Even the things that look done may be wrong. [TODO] break list up more
Sound Sources Vintage Synths Modern Synths Bass Synths Sampled / Acoustic Modeling Percussive Effects Dynamics Filter Reverb Delay Trivial Weird as fuck Misc Tools Organization MIDI generation This is probably where the most bias of any of the lists on this page will show as I obviously can&amp;rsquo;t list every possible plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</guid>
      <description>VCV Rack Tips &amp;amp; Tricks # I am not affiliated with VCV or the Rack software in any way. Despite the mess in the VCV community, I&amp;rsquo;ve still put in a lot of time in the software and run a pretty large group chat on Telegram where it (alongside hardware Eurorack) is the main focus. In that chat, there&amp;rsquo;s been a few recurring questions, this page is just some of those questions and answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/coolhardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/coolhardware/</guid>
      <description>Cool Hardware # LTP-305G/HR 5x7 LED Matrix displays &amp;amp; Driver, article on (Hackaday)
also see the redot project for a modern clone
Core Memory Shield for Arduino by Jussi Kilpelainen on Tindie
A somewhat ridiculous precision voltage source
turns out placing 900 resistors does not get you banned from SMD assembly service after all 😇 pic.twitter.com/3iu3zL5TLi
&amp;mdash; Marco Reps (@MarcoReps) December 31, 2020 Backup of the above tweet on archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/fediverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/fediverse/</guid>
      <description>The Fediverse, ActivityPub, &amp;amp; The IndieWeb # If you&amp;rsquo;re as active in the same nerdy online circles I am, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard all three of these terms. There&amp;rsquo;s also a good chance you&amp;rsquo;re confused how they&amp;rsquo;re all related. Well, let&amp;rsquo;s fix that:
The Fediverse # The fediverse (a portmanteau of &amp;ldquo;federation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;universe&amp;rdquo;) is an ensemble of federated (i.e. interconnected) servers that are used for web publishing (i.e. social networking, microblogging, blogging, or websites) and file hosting, but which, while independently hosted, can communicate with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/funlinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/funlinks/</guid>
      <description>Other cool things that I want to promote but don&amp;rsquo;t fit elsewhere, so I&amp;rsquo;m making this list here: # Brimstone Valley Mall
The year is 1999. Lurking somewhere between Hot Topic and the food court, five misfit demons from Hell kill time inciting sin in a suburban shopping mall. When the lead singer of their band goes mysteriously missing, the demons only have two weeks to find him before they play the biggest gig of the millennium - or face the wrath of Satan herself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/contradictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/contradictions/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 4: What points contradict? # Having Low Level Access and High Level Usability. # Yeah, this is always a problem. It&amp;rsquo;s always been the dream to be able to describe in &amp;rsquo;natural language&amp;rsquo; what you want and to have the computer parse what you want, inferring intent, and do whatever you want for you, but naturally, this will never be totally possible. This point is only conflicting in the sense that it can be overwhelming- if a user has access to work in something as high as natural language and can manipulate those instructions all the way down at the assembly level, that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of open space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/digital/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2: The Digital # Alright, now onto the fun stuff, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve established that the physical side of how we use a computer is sub optimal, but what about how we actually do the things we do day to day? I think, for the most part, these things can be put into a few categories:
Finding and Accessing shit Looking at shit Storing Shit Transferring Shit Making Shit Finding and Accessing Information Sucks # Search sucks # If you&amp;rsquo;re like most people, you probably use Google Search, but also don&amp;rsquo;t like Google Search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/intro/</guid>
      <description>The Way We Interact With Computers Sucks. # ASCII art morphing by Tim Holman What do you see when you sit down to work?
Is your space actually comfortable?
Does your keyboard feel like it was actually designed for human hands?
How do you access information?
How do know that information is reliable?
How do you store information in a way you can retrieve it easily later?
Do you have good tools for making content?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/physical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/physical/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1: The Physical # Computers aren&amp;rsquo;t just about software, websites, and programs. As the most powerful tool that most people have access to and often one that we spend many hours a day looking at, it makes sense that we make working with that tool comfortable, straight forward, and healthy. In general, we&amp;rsquo;ve mostly sucked at this, and while some things are getting better (monitor resolution) some things have gotten significantly worse (keyboards).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/radicallychanging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/radicallychanging/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 5: What Might Radically Change Things? # Breaking Away from Silicon, Binary, and Traditional Architectures # Probably the biggest change in computers that we could see would be rethinking the entire idea of how a computer works. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean changing the way users interact with a system, but by having new, radically different hardware designs developers may be inspired to make things that are currently impractical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/whatelse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/whatelse/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 3: What&amp;rsquo;s Else Is Needed? # Script all the things! But Not Like That™ # Computers are, generally, really good at repetitive tasks. People are, generally, really bad at telling computers what they want.
This means that developers (which, I assume, is a large portion of those still reading this) need to make systems that let users automate tasks in a more user-friendly way than they would do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/wrappingup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/hci2/wrappingup/</guid>
      <description>Wrapping up # In all honesty, I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure what everything I just wrote is about. Mostly it&amp;rsquo;s just a lot of ranting, but hopefully it has been interesting. To round things off with a bit of a closing note though, I don&amp;rsquo;t actually foresee many of the things I mentioned becoming common place or many even being possible, if not simply because they&amp;rsquo;re requiring so many people to agree on standards, but there is one glimmer of hope, and it&amp;rsquo;s one of proof of uniformity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/tokipona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/tokipona/</guid>
      <description>toki pona! 󱥬󱦖󱥔 # This page will test your UTF-8 support and ability to load in weird fonts. It works on my computer ╮(─▽─)╭ toki a! toki pona is a constructed language created by Sonja Lang in 2001. First things first- what&amp;rsquo;s a constructed language? Think like Quenya (which is written in Tengwar) from JRR Tolkein&amp;rsquo;s Lord of the Rings:
            This font is Fairfax HD by KreativeKorp, which is licensed under the open font license It is used for all of the conlang displays on this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/characters/</guid>
      <description>Making Characters # Relationships # Including with the dead, missing, and absent</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/conflict/</guid>
      <description> Conflict # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/fantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/fantasy/</guid>
      <description> Thinking In Fantasy # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/language/</guid>
      <description>Language # Using accents, regional terms, slang, etc.
Tone, with respect of the narrator PoV and the intended audience from the narrator
Church of interruption</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/pacing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/pacing/</guid>
      <description> Pacing # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/plot/</guid>
      <description> Plot # If you can find a moment in the plot where nothing is changing, that is not a relevant moment to be including - ShaelinWrites </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/poetry/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/revision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/revision/</guid>
      <description> Revision # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/worldbuilding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/worldbuilding/</guid>
      <description> World Building # Cultures # Languages # Senses # Sounds # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/other/writing/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/other/writing/writing/</guid>
      <description>Improving Your Writing # [TODO] split this up for technical, fiction, and applicable to both.
And for some fun,
What if English were Phonetically Consistent? (YouTube - Aaron Alon) Finding Inspiration &amp;amp; Advice # Wonderbook has been by far the most useful thing I have read for improving my skills, and I can&amp;rsquo;t reccomend it enough.
Catastrotivity, a series of short audio episodes about being an artist, while not focused on writing, proved to be quite useful too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/personal/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/personal/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>Wishlist # $50 and Under # Socks++ are always welcome too.
Name &amp; Link Description Picture Category Price in USD (approx) Magic Eye Tube Music Display using a tube Music / Electronics ~$25 SA Keycaps Nicer caps for my keyboard. Note, these alone would only get me 90% of the way there. I&#39;d also need some 1.5U SA Keys, such as this one, but they&#39;re $20/key, and I&#39;d need at least 2, I could always grab them myself later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</guid>
      <description>Economic Systems # Cryptocurrency &amp;amp; NFTs # Why NFTs are bad: the long version (Antsstyle)
Hacker News comments on &amp;ldquo;PayPal raises fees for most domestic transaction types to 3.49% + $0.49&amp;rdquo;
https://basicappleguy.com/basicappleblog/999month
https://thehustle.co/americas-favorite-family-outings-are-increasingly-out-of-reach/
The &amp;ldquo;Pay For It&amp;rdquo; Scam (Carlos Maza, YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</guid>
      <description>Environmental Protection # u/SvenInFramse / @SvenInFrames (Twitter) / @sveninframes (Insta) u/neilrkaye (2021) Carbon Tax?
Geoengineering: A Horrible Idea We Might Have to Do (YouTube, Kurzgesagt)
A Strange New Blend of Rock and Plastic Is Forming on a Portuguese Island (Gizmodo)
A Plateful of Plastic - Visualising the amount of microplastic we eat (Reuters)
The poison found in everyone, even unborn babies – and who is responsible for it (The Guardian)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/armament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/armament/</guid>
      <description>Personal Armament # Before we talk about this at all, I want to get one thing out of the way:
The 2nd amendment does not make gun ownership right or wrong. Laws - including the constitution - do not dictate morality and ethics. We all know there are unjust laws and many choose to break them because of it. So, if you use the argument &amp;ldquo;But Muh Constitution!&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;ve already made a bad argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/body/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Body # What should you be able to do with your body? The immediate reaction may be &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s my body, so whatever I want!&amp;rdquo; but think about it really, should everyone have the right to do anything they want with their body? What about suicide and self harm? What about when information about you is shared- if you take a DNA test, that impacts everyone related to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/environmentalconcern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/environmentalconcern/</guid>
      <description> Freedom of environmental concern # Vaccination # Local Pollution # PFAS # Air Quality # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/fairtrial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/fairtrial/</guid>
      <description> Fair Trial # Jury of your peers - how do we define peers? # Court of Public Opinion # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/freedoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/freedoms/</guid>
      <description>Freedoms and Rights # Before we go into some actual philosophy and current issues, let&amp;rsquo;s establish a baseline by looking at some of how freedoms and rights are laid out around the world
UN Declaration of Human Rights # The Universal Declaration of Human Rights from the United Nations lays out quite a few protections that are mostly ignored and unenforceable, but fundamentally agreeable. The actual text isn&amp;rsquo;t very long, but here&amp;rsquo;s the quick version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/ownership/</guid>
      <description> Promise of Ownership # DRM, Right to Repair # See the DRM , Right To Repair , and Ads in content you&#39;ve already paid for sections from Chapter 9: Consumerism https://goel.io/drm-ownership
General Purpose Computation # https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HUEvRyemKSg
First Sale Doctrine # Trademark # https://www.ipwatchdog.com/2021/04/13/satan-shoes-trademark-blasphemy-free-speech/id=132184/
Reverse Engineering # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/press/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Press # Everyone is press, https://www.eff.org/bloggers
The Trump Administration Is Trying To Force BuzzFeed News To Divulge Its Sources With A Subpoena
anti-SLAPP laws
Whistle Blower Protections # https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_whistleblowers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/recording/</guid>
      <description> Right to record, Right to know # if it is public, there&amp;rsquo;s reason to expect you may be if it is private, person to person, (not b2b or p2b) there&amp;rsquo;s an exception for if it only for personal or judicial (to be used in trial) use. I.E, can&amp;rsquo;t post it online if it&amp;rsquo;s unreasonable to expect being recorded </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/search/</guid>
      <description> Search and Seizure # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/speech/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Speech # xkcd №1357 The freedom of speech is weird, because it&amp;rsquo;s one that most of us recognize is that it should have limits because speech is powerful. The problem comes in what those limits are, which is why there are so many topics under debate:
Government Secrets Whistleblowing Hate Speech Political/Religious Opinion Copyright Parody Public Health Advertising of Sugar/Drugs Public Safety Creating Panic Encryption Self Incrimination Flag Burning National Pride Gag Orders National Security Porn/Cursing Public Decency (and the FCC) Advertising Spam Satire Defamation There&amp;rsquo;s also a question of where things go too far- at what point is speech a legitimate threat, and where is the line for actions that constitute harassment vs just being an asshole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/travel/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Travel # Immigration, Citizenship testing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</guid>
      <description>History # Something to consider before going forward is that, assuming you&amp;rsquo;re from the US, the education you&amp;rsquo;ve received is likely very skewed both in what content is presented in the first place and how it&amp;rsquo;s presented. Unlike what most US education will tell you MLK did not magically end racism, not every US war has been just, and - no - our three branches of government are not working as intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/advice/</guid>
      <description>I will dispense this advice now # Over the last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve joined a few new communities online, made a few new friends in meat space, and had a repeated conversation with my SO all about the same thing: &amp;ldquo;How can I be more like you?&amp;rdquo; (or, in one case &amp;ldquo;How can I be you&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; yikes.) This is a really weird question to get. It is simultaneously asking for life advice, placing me on a pedestal as some sort of ideal, and sort of diminishes both my personal quirks and personality and the beauty in everyone&amp;rsquo;s uniqueness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/janolin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/janolin/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts on olin, Part 1 # Post by jan Usawi So. Can you olin a potato?
Tonight (1), myself and a few others in the ma pona server got talking about the usage of the word olin (󱥅) towards actions, and whether or not olin can refer to love for anything other than a person. And my brain, in its normal spiderweb-weaving fashion, went running.
As much as I love using the odd preverb here and there (sike (󱥜) especially), olin preverb is one I’ve never gotten on board with—I love writing, but “mi olin sitelen” is not how I’d express that passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/kids/</guid>
      <description> Ask HN: How can I make a “kid&amp;rsquo;s computer” today as good as an Apple II? The Bad Way To Teach Music to Babies </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</guid>
      <description>List of Ideas # Post about sympy in math chapter, espically with sum and product
increasingly online spaces that are custom-built are both spreading new ideas and preventing mono-cultures AND causing people to live in completely different realities and echo chambers
Fuck consumerism, fuck hoarding, fuck status symbols, fuck plastic wrapped single use internationally shiped good, fuck single use electronics, fuck shitty electronics that are instant-ewaste
Dangerous sounds - high voltage arc clicks, hard drive clicks, loud 60hz hum, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/mathtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/mathtest/</guid>
      <description>WEBGL &amp;amp; MATH TESTING # This is a testing ground for different options for rendering math, signals, etc. though the website. Given the music, DSP, and signals page I really care about sine waves and FFTs. It seems the best looking, lowest CPU sine I can get is using WEBGL (as immediately below) but writing the code for it is quite cumbersome. For math itself, https://github.com/airladon/figureone/ seems to be the best bet, and and should dramatically help with the math chapters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/myworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/myworld/</guid>
      <description>Making a VRChat World # Step 1: What Do I Want? What Do I 𝕟𝕠𝕥 want. # concept art, etc.
Want:
ALIVE. Things should feel alive - wind, movement, player-reactivity LIVED IN. Each area should feel like there have been people there. Papers around, things under study, etc. SOUND. Ambient environment should have original sounds from my modular, kalimba, talkbox, guitars, etc. SYTLIZED. The world should be big so poly counts need to be low and/or have LOD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/p5test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/p5test/</guid>
      <description> P5 test # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/reacttest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/reacttest/</guid>
      <description>React test # https://josem.co/how-to-render-a-react-component-in-hugo/ - I&amp;rsquo;d like to get https://mafs.dev/guides/get-started/installation working, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do so in a convenient way with Hugo. I&amp;rsquo;m really not a fan of adding react as a depedency and using that much JS anyway, but if this works it&amp;rsquo;d be worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/vr/</guid>
      <description>VR # FBT # https://www.crowdsupply.com/slimevr/slimevr-full-body-tracker
Vive trackers
April Tag
Kinect
Hand tracking &amp;amp; Haptics # Walking around # I created a Udon world to visualize infinite walking. The white lines are the limits of my play space.
The orange trail shows my movement in play space, and the blue trail shows my movement in world space.
(When I&amp;#39;m wireless I walk in circles, otherwise I walk in a ∞ shape) pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/whatelseexists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/whatelseexists/</guid>
      <description>What Else Exists? # I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer that an important part of problem solving and innovating development is connecting ideas from other, seemingly unrelated fields. Really just pick any two niche interests and try to combine them. To put my money where my mouth is, here&amp;rsquo;s three quick projects:
Cryptography and Fractals? Generative music and slime mold simulation? Domain specific JS Idea Generator # [TODO] I&amp;rsquo;d like this to have about 400 items minimum, then make each into a sentence start and end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/webdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/webdev/</guid>
      <description>How to make OpGuides Better # From 3b1b:
Restructure things to go from Concrete to Abstract, not the other way around; Show patterns &amp;amp; examples, before going to the symbolic and abstract Go really esoteric and specific - it builds a loyal audience Do not start with definitions - let people think they could have come to those definitions themselves Start with motivating problems source
Don&amp;rsquo;t force the user to remember things if you can help it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</guid>
      <description>Philosophical Arguments # [TODO]how to construct a phil argument
Not simply accepting &amp;ldquo;Because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is&amp;rdquo; # I&amp;rsquo;m writing this at @292.78 on Day 132 of 12,020. I&amp;rsquo;m typing on a Dvorak, split, ortholinear keyboard in a markdown document using Arch Linux instead of M$ Word on Windows. I find music off the 12 tone scale interesting, and while I know 432 vs 440hz, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to open my 3rd eye, listening to microtonal or music made with just intonation is still something interesting to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Phil</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</guid>
      <description>OPINION Before anything else, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out this is opinionated guides. Philosophy involves looking at the world around us and asking ourselves &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, then making arguments for how things should be different and what moral frameworks work best to come to conclusions that optimize for something like happiness or &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; in the world. Given that both morals and &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; are not absolutes, the best way for me to write this guide and actually be of service to you as a reader is to provide my opinion and talk about why I believe what believe both from a researched &amp;lsquo;here are the facts&amp;rsquo; sense and from a &amp;lsquo;here is the moral framework that, with these facts, brought me to this conclusion&amp;rsquo; sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Art and Design # When you&amp;rsquo;re first learning art, every art class will beat a few core ideas into your head:
Lines - The &amp;lsquo;structure&amp;rsquo; bits of the works, when you start making art, you&amp;rsquo;ll often start with the Line Art
Shape - Structures that form out of lines, might appear 3D. These might be mathy, like squares, or organic, like an eye
Form - Mostly applicable to 3D (or art interpreted as 3D) - Think of this as the shape you&amp;rsquo;d see if you could move around the object in real life</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</guid>
      <description>Community # Hopefully this isn&amp;rsquo;t a shock to anyone reading this, but I&amp;rsquo;m a furry.
owo uwu nuzzles rawr tehe So, I think I can share a little bit about why I joined the fandom, what being in a subculture community is like, and how some of those experiences have made me a better person and helped me be a part of or run successful online communities.
I hope that though this I can talk about what makes a community good or bad, what brings division, and what good rules for a healthy community look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>Consumerism # Vega&amp;rsquo;s Maw, made for me by @NewtWolfdeer Look, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of falling for the tricks used to get people to consume. To buy and buy more. A good sale, even on something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I previously wanted, still has a way of making my dumb lil&amp;rsquo; human brain go &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;
The problem is that consumers can easily fall into traps that lead them to buy things for a stupid reasons, these include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/cooking/cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/cooking/cooking/</guid>
      <description>Hey there.
My name is Vega, and I can&amp;rsquo;t cook, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be letting my friends take this one over.
Why you should take the time to be a functional adult: # !&amp;gt; I had a few friends interested in fleshing this page out, but they got busy, lmk if you want to take it over or just sumbit a pull request ^-^</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Letting Society Advance Though Art and Innovation # This video from Tom Scott on YouTube is a very good intro to everything I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about on this page, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you&amp;rsquo;ve watched it so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat everything that he says here.
What is Copyright? # [TODO]
What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong With that? # Watch a police officer admit to playing Taylor Swift to keep a video off YouTube (The Verge)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources # Wonderbook I very rarely promote resources you have to pay to access on OpGuides. I am not paid to say this. I bought my own copy on a whim. This book is pure gold. It&amp;rsquo;s about the written word, but will help any artist just as much. It is probably the most beautiful, lovingly hand crafted book I have ever read. It&amp;rsquo;s full of character and art and beauty and words of wisdom that will make you think about what it means to be an Artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duties</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</guid>
      <description> Personal Duties # Maintaining health # Physical # Working out # Air quality # Mental # Socialized healthcare # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</guid>
      <description>Education # Freedom of Information # Curriculum Changes # Basic Aid # Sex Education # Individualized, shared, and student led # [TODO] Faster, lower standards # Better testing # Fuck Respondus And Proctorio # The following is a (slightly edited) excerpt from an email I felt necessary to send to my professors at the start of the spring semester, 2021
First and foremost, they&amp;rsquo;re just creepy. Taking tests digitally but in person is fine with me because I know those computers are secure and dedicated to the single use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects # This chapter is broken up into subsections, check the menu and it should have expanded! Please Read This, for real # Automation Lanes Are Your Friend # A lot of audio effects boil down to automating some simple parameter. Sometimes you may not actually need a dedicated effect and can instead get by with using Automation Lanes (YouTube, once upon a synth) in your Digital Audio Workstation (DAW)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/engineering/engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/engineering/engineering/</guid>
      <description>Hey There! My name is Vega, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad you&amp;rsquo;re here! I know there are plenty of tutorials and ways to learn online, be it on YouTube, SkillShare, or online classes provided for free by various universities. The difference here is I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to cut out the boring parts, make things a bit more entertaining than a textbook, and drenched the content in my own personal opinion that has been built up by my experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</guid>
      <description>Logical Fallacies (and a bit more) # If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet for more than about a quarter of a second, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely been accused of a whole host of logical fallacies. Unfortunately, most people really don&amp;rsquo;t understand what they&amp;rsquo;re saying and often use a lot of these incorrectly. On the other hand, you also likely encounter politicians people using these fallacies on a regular basis as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to call them out on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foriegn</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</guid>
      <description>Foreign Involvement # &#34; The Ministry of Peace concerns itself with war, the Ministry of Truth with lies, the Ministry of Love with torture and the Ministry of Plenty with starvation &#34; - George Orwell, 1984 In the US, we have the Department of Defense - the DOD. Whenever I think about that name, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about that quote from 1984. The Department of Defense is primarily concerned with war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Labs</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</guid>
      <description>Idea Labs # This page is heavily inspired by Idea Labs and Echo Chambers, which is Part 8 of The Story Of Us. It&amp;rsquo;s a long read, but worth the time- you could read just the one part; however, I think it will be harder to understand without the previous 7 parts as context. Rather than try to repeat here what is put so well there, I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend you read at least that section and come back here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure # Power # Gravity-based batteries try to beat their chemical cousins with winches, weights, and mine shafts
Light Pollution # International Dark Sky Association
Air Quality # A paradigm shift to combat indoor respiratory infection
Networking (Mesh) # Housing and Land # Car-Free Neighborhoods in the US
The People the Suburbs Were Built for Are Gone (Vice)
Land Value Tax? # Birth Lottery # Where you&amp;rsquo;re born determines if you have access to even basic needs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspirational Artists</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</guid>
      <description>Inspirational Artists # Unfortunately, this page is nearly entirely Twitter embeds. If you have something in your browser blocking these from working, this page won&amp;rsquo;t be all that useful. Sorry! Added a lot of minor improvements, like camera limits, subtle lighting, dust particles and more #gamedev #pixelart #screenshotsaturday pic.twitter.com/KmSYW3iHml
&amp;mdash; Luis Moreno Jimenez (@more8bit) September 2, 2017 Teenage Engineering&amp;#39;s OP-1 Synthesizer modules: pic.twitter.com/Jx5FEkiGK9
&amp;mdash; Shadow Drop - R&amp;amp;D (@ShadowDropDev) August 18, 2017 Some really cool pixel art gifs by Mark Ferrari https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Instruments # If you&amp;rsquo;re going to be playing an instrument though a computer - and I mean either an instrument which makes its own noise like a guitar or a controller like a MIDI keyboard - you&amp;rsquo;ll want to adjust your audio buffer size as best you can. See Optimizing The Latency Of Your PC Audio Interface from Sound on Sound for more info about this, but generally just set your buffer size as low as you can until it starts to sound like it&amp;rsquo;s horribly broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</guid>
      <description>Published Interviews: # Loial Otter Soatok Dreamseeker Cadey Ratio Kell Bengal Tax Badger Sex Positive Gaming Cendyne Wolfgun Paul Shapera If you would like to be interviewed # Well, first of all I&amp;rsquo;d like to know what makes you interesting - so shoot me a message or open an issue on GitHub, twitter, or where ever you can find me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</guid>
      <description>Labor and Compensation # The Case For Banning Non-Competes (slowboring.com)
EU pushes for &amp;lsquo;right to disconnect&amp;rsquo; from work at home (dw.com)
Please Consider My Application to Give You Labor So I Can Stay Alive
Workplace Wellbeing Is a Scam (Tribune)
Economic Inequality # Source code (GPL v3), by Matt Korostoff Wage Theft is a Much Bigger Problem Than Other Forms of Theft—But Workers Remain Mostly Unprotected
Ex-Google Employee Exposes Unequal Pay With Spreadsheet (Wall Street Journal)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law And Order</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</guid>
      <description> Law Enforcement and Judgment # Trial of educated peers
Criminal Rehabilitation # end mandatory sentencing end bail no debtors prison
Divorce, Child Support # Jury Duty # Prosecutors &amp;amp; Public Defenders # Police # Illinois, First State to Tell Police They Can&amp;rsquo;t Lie to Minors in Interrogations (NPR)
Prisons # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare Costs # Why is life expectancy in the US lower than in other rich countries?
White House wins ruling on disclosing health care prices (AP)
Drugs # Most drugs and prostitution should be legal at the age of 18. However, trafficking obviously not, and drugs must be sold by an individual with a license to deal and said license may be revoked if the product is sold with a false label or is tainted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixing &amp;amp; Mastering # Mixers # mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring # https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and Spotify
Mixing # eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Mastering # Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)
Studio Monitors, Headphones, and Amps # @Tirrelous on Twitter Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of all the specs you might want to understand if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to buy headphones or studio monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware # While you could make all of your music with just a computer, you’ll probably want some tools that make your life as a musician easier and let you explore ideas faster. Like I said back in the Audio Effects Chapter , in my experience, making music depends on a really quick brain to input device feedback loop. Being able to turn a physical knob and mash physical keys will often lead to better results if only because you’re able to try things both faster and by physically interacting with something that you may not have thought of otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software # Audio Sources # Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot Various from SugarBytes I really like Consequence - Chord GroveboxFactory - Mod Matrix PolysynthGuitarist - Guitar Emulation, easy to programDrum Computer - Drum SynthObscurium - I don&amp;rsquo;t even know, but it&amp;rsquo;s cool.Cyclop - Neat Synth, good for bassEgoist - Weird audio stem re-groover?Thesys - MIDI Sequencer Websites # Google Drum Machine (Like XO)
Audio backends # [TODO]
Windows # ASIO # Direct Sound # WSAPI # Linux # Seriously, check out Making Sense of The Linux Audio Stack on Venam&amp;rsquo;s Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpPhil Old</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</guid>
      <description>Old Version, needs migrated: # Because you&amp;rsquo;re now somebody in the know about topics relating to technology and have a deeper understanding about issues that may effect the public, such as The FBI V Apple encryption case, Issues regrading internet speed and infrastructure, or The Government/NSA spying on people. There are plenty of issues that weather you like it or not you&amp;rsquo;re one of the few with enough information to truly understand and inform your peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources # PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (Github) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses
Sample Packs &amp;amp; Wavetables # Echo Sound Works Coda (~$30) - Wavetables &amp;amp; Serum presets. These wavetables are truly amazing.
Cool People # https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/thePatchBay - some shameless self promo, as this is my chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil and The Internet</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>The fight for the Internet is never ending. At the time of writing, Senators want to mandate anti-piracy technology across the web (ArsTechnica).
Please call and write your congress critters, and let them know this is some stupid bullshit. Then ask your friends to do so as well.
You can use Find My Representative (house.gov) if you need to look up who represents you.
Even if you&amp;rsquo;re outside the US, this will still very likely affect you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</guid>
      <description>Thank you # If you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far, I just want to say thank you. We need more people to really consider how ethics, politics, and copyright shape the world around us with technology and art as we design it and proceed with it. DeepFakes, Automated driving, and even more mass online censorship are issues we&amp;rsquo;re only going to face more with time, and it&amp;rsquo;s people like you who are going to help make sure we take the best path we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil, Misc</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</guid>
      <description> Animal Rights (Industrial Scale Slaughter) # Organ donation # Tech can&amp;rsquo;t solve all your problems # Human problems need human solutions
Guns # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion # Religion is, shocker, a deeply personal thing.
Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re of the opinion that you&amp;rsquo;re following the One True Good™. Maybe you think that everyone is crazy with their belief in imaginary friends. Maybe you think all of humanity is just a sort of womb for a new god.Maybe you think all the gods are real, and made from the belief of their followers. Maybe you just don&amp;rsquo;t give a 💩 Maybe you give a 💩 some days, think it&amp;rsquo;s all a bunch of 🐂💩 others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</guid>
      <description>Sex # In an ideal world, humankind would be driven forward by more than the initiate desire to reproduce and bone. But, we don&amp;rsquo;t live in an ideal world, and people like to have fun and feel good. (consensual) Sex is fun and feels good- so it should not be looked down on. Flirting, hooking up, being horny: They&amp;rsquo;re all natural and good. Unfortunately, today it seems Everyone is Beautiful and No One is Horny Consent # Look, I don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise* # * Excluding traditional instruments. We&amp;rsquo;ll get there soon.
Samples # A snippet of a .wav file open in audacity A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. Still, for the generic term what is usually meant is a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: # Don&amp;rsquo;t undervalue just sitting down and listening to music, trying to figure out what parts you enjoy and thinking about how it compares to what you&amp;rsquo;ve made, what you think you should change to sound better. Along with that, it helps to look at breakdowns of music done on YouTube. I particularly recommend all of the videos from 12tone&amp;rsquo;s channel.
Theory # I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</guid>
      <description>UI and UX # Principals of UI, A Thread (zensaiyuki@mastodon.social)
Gallery of Fantasy UI design from Movies and TV shows
Responsiveness # Source Power Users # User power, not power users: htop and its design philosophy
Typography # Practical Typography Textbook
Datalegeya Font
Almost Monospace Fonts (blakewatson.com)
Data Visualization # https://bids.github.io/colormap/
Website Design # Learn CSS by Google Developers
Butalist Web Design, by David Copeland
motherfuckingwebsite.com, bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com, thebestmotherfuckingwebsite.website
Scrollbar Blindness (Sven Kadak&amp;rsquo;s Blog)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/video/</guid>
      <description>Video &amp;amp; Streaming # &amp;hellip;Psst, if you&amp;rsquo;re on this page, you may be interested in My blog post on Video Synthesis Before anything else, I need to crush some hopes and dreams:
You absolutely should not expect your YouTube or Twitch channel to make it big. Even if you put in the work, invest in good equipment, and make cool content regularly, and promote the shit out of yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s still a game of luck on if you can go viral and if you can retain any viewership whatsoever after doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</guid>
      <description>Elections &amp;amp; Voting # I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;lsquo;murican, so this will be US centric, that said, the arguments here could likely be applied universally Issue 1: FPTP Voting Sucks # lower standards of removal, ranked, transparency Budget voting
Issue 2: Voters are really, really stupid # voting based on if they like the person, how he/she looks, single issue voting
Issue 3: Two is the unfriendliest number # Issue 4: Gerrymandering, Fraud, and Astroturfing # [TODO] Comment on Citizen&amp;rsquo;s United</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolfgun</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/wolfgun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/wolfgun/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Wolfgun # 2/17/2023
Play Wolfgun is a space obsessed master of synthesizers with 50 albums out on Bandcamp. He primarily makes his music in Renoise, a Digital Audio Workstation (DAW) which combines an old-school tracker workflow - think the equivalent of combining spreadsheets and music software with the sequence of notes and effects entered vertically, like the example on the left - with modern production capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
