<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHIL on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/phil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PHIL on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/phil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</guid>
      <description>Environmental Protection #  Legacy [OC] from r/funny  Carbon Tax?
Percentage of all fossil fuel emissions that have occurred in my lifetime [OC] from r/dataisbeautiful 
Geoengineering: A Horrible Idea We Might Have to Do (YouTube, Kurzgesagt)
A Strange New Blend of Rock and Plastic Is Forming on a Portuguese Island (Gizmodo)
A Plateful of Plastic - Visualising the amount of microplastic we eat (Reuters)
The poison found in everyone, even unborn babies – and who is responsible for it (The Guardian)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</guid>
      <description>Philosophical Arguments #  [TODO]how to construct a phil argument
Not simply accepting &amp;ldquo;Because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is&amp;rdquo; #  I&amp;rsquo;m writing this at @292.78 on Day 132 of 12,020. I&amp;rsquo;m typing on a Dvorak, split, ortholinear keyboard in a markdown document using Arch Linux instead of M$ Word on Windows, and if you&amp;rsquo;d like you could view this document using DAT or IPFS or LBRY. I find music off the 12 tone scale interesting, and while I know 432 vs 440hz, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to open my 3rd eye, listening to microtonal or music made with just intonation is still something interesting to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Phil</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</guid>
      <description>OPINION          Before anything else, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out this is opinionated guides. Philosophy involves looking at the world around us and asking ourselves &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, then making arguments for how things should be different and what moral frameworks work best to come to conclusions that optimize for something like happiness or &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; in the world. Given that both morals and &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; are not absolutes, the best way for me to write this guide and actually be of service to you as a reader is to provide my opinion and talk about why I believe what believe both from a researched &amp;lsquo;here are the facts&amp;rsquo; sense and from a &amp;lsquo;here is the moral framework that, with these facts, brought me to this conclusion&amp;rsquo; sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</guid>
      <description>Community #  Hopefully this isn&amp;rsquo;t a shock to anyone reading this, but I&amp;rsquo;m a furry.
owo uwu nuzzles rawr tehe So, I think I can share a little bit about why I joined the fandom, what being in a subculture community is like, and how some of those experiences have made me a better person and helped me be a part of or run successful online communities.
I hope that though this I can talk about what makes a community good or bad, what brings division, and what good rules for a healthy community look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>Consumerism #  Vega&amp;rsquo;s Maw, made for me by @NewtWolfdeer  Look, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of falling for the tricks used to get people to consume. To buy and buy more. A good sale, even on something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I previously wanted, still has a way of making my dumb lil&#39; human brain go &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;
The problem is that consumers can easily fall into traps that lead them to buy things for a stupid reasons, these include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Letting Society Advance Though Art and Innovation #  This video from Tom Scott on YouTube is a very good intro to everything I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about on this page, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you&amp;rsquo;ve watched it so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat everything that he says here.
 What is Copyright? #  [TODO]
What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong With that? #   How do we fix it? #  I think to further address any issues we first need to look into how these issues have come to exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duties</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</guid>
      <description>Personal Duties #  Maintaining health #  Physical #  Working out #  Air quality #  Mental #  Socialized healthcare #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</guid>
      <description>Education #  Freedom of Information #  Curriculum Changes #  Basic Aid #  Sex Education #  Individualized, shared, and student led #  [TODO] Faster, lower standards #  Better testing #   Fuck Respondus And Proctorio #   The following is a (slightly edited) excerpt from an email I felt necessary to send to my professors at the start of the spring semester, 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</guid>
      <description>Logical Fallacies (and a bit more) #  If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet for more than about a quarter of a second, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely been accused of a whole host of logical fallacies. Unfortunately, most people really don&amp;rsquo;t understand what they&amp;rsquo;re saying and often use a lot of these incorrectly. On the other hand, you also likely encounter politicians people using these fallacies on a regular basis as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to call them out on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foriegn</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</guid>
      <description>War and Foreign Involvement #  Denuclearization #  Localization #   Falsehoods Programmers Believe About Name The Problem with Time &amp;amp; Timezones (YouTube) Google Maps is Different in Other Countries (YouTube)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedoms</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/</guid>
      <description>Freedoms and Rights #  Freedom of Speech #  xkcd №1357 Freedom of Press #  Everyone is press, https://www.eff.org/bloggers
The Trump Administration Is Trying To Force BuzzFeed News To Divulge Its Sources With A Subpoena
anti-SLAPP laws
Whistle Blower Protections #  Search and Seizure #  Fair Trial #  Court of Public Opinion #  Freedom of Body #  Marital Rape, Euthanasia, Abortion, AI recognition and usage, gene ownership</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Labs</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</guid>
      <description>Communal Efforts #  [TODO] Shared Spaces #  Hacker Spaces Community Garden
Open Source hardware and software #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure #  College Campuses Are Designed at Human-Scale. Our Cities Can Be Too. (StrongTowns.org)
Power #  Gravity-based batteries try to beat their chemical cousins with winches, weights, and mine shafts
Light Pollution #  International Dark Sky Association
Air Quality #  A paradigm shift to combat indoor respiratory infection
Networking (Mesh) #  Housing and Land #  The People the Suburbs Were Built for Are Gone (Vice)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</guid>
      <description>Labor and Compensation #  EU pushes for &amp;lsquo;right to disconnect&amp;rsquo; from work at home (dw.com)
Please Consider My Application to Give You Labor So I Can Stay Alive
Workplace Wellbeing Is a Scam (Tribune)
 Economic Inequality #   Source code (GPL v3), by Matt Korostoff Wage Theft is a Much Bigger Problem Than Other Forms of Theft—But Workers Remain Mostly Unprotected
Ex-Google Employee Exposes Unequal Pay With Spreadsheet (Wall Street Journal)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law And Order</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</guid>
      <description>Law Enforcment and Judgment #  Trial of educated peers
Criminal Rehabilitation #  end mandatory sentencing end bail no debters prision
 Divorce, Child Support #  Jury Duty #   Prosecutors &amp;amp; Public Defenders #    Police #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare Costs #  Why is life expectancy in the US lower than in other rich countries?
White House wins ruling on disclosing health care prices (AP)
Drugs #  Most drugs and prostitution should be legal at the age of 18. However, trafficking obviously not, and drugs must be sold by an individual with a licence to deal and said licence may be revoked if the product is sold with a false label or is tainted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpPhil Old</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</guid>
      <description>Old Version, needs migrated: #  Because you&amp;rsquo;re now somebody in the know about topics relating to technology and have a deeper understanding about issues that may effect the public, such as The FBI V Apple encryption case, Issues regrading internet speed and infrastructure, or The Government/NSA spying on people. There are plenty of issues that weather you like it or not you&amp;rsquo;re one of the few with enough information to truly understand and inform your peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil and The Internet</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>The fight for the Internet is never ending. At the time of writing, Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell tried to tie anti §230 legislation to the $2000 stimulus checks, and my own Congress Critter, Ben Sasse (R,Nebraska), along with Jeff Merkley (D,Oregon) are trying to push though SISEA - the Stop Internet Sexual Exploitation Act, which on paper sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s doing good to stop the possibility of revenge porn. Unfortunately, they want to do this by requiring that all people in porn expressly give the site written consent with identity verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</guid>
      <description>Thank you #  If you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far I just want to say thank you. We need more people to really consider how ethics, politics, and copyright shape the world around us with technology and art as we design it and proceed with it. DeepFakes, Automated driving, and even more mass online censorship are issues we&amp;rsquo;re only going to face more with time and it&amp;rsquo;s people like you who are going to help make sure we take the best path we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil, Misc</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</guid>
      <description>Animal Rights (Industrial Scale Slaughter) #  Organ donation #  Tech can&amp;rsquo;t solve all your problems #  Human problems need human solutions
Guns #                  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion #  [TODO] The engineering community is strangely divided, the &amp;lsquo;old guard&amp;rsquo; is actually relatively conservative and professional, but as time has moved forward it&amp;rsquo;s quite the opposite. Unsurprisingly, this correlates with religion as well. The main way this plays into politics is a general hard stance for the separation of church and state. This is in part due to a past of religiously motivated legislation negatively impacting copyright law, but also just generally an understood ideal that is beneficial to democracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</guid>
      <description>Sex #  In an ideal world human kind would be driven forward by more than the initiate desire to reproduce and bone. Then again, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have evolved to this point where we&amp;rsquo;re capable of reflecting on that irony, in the first place.
Consent #  Look, I don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot. I assume you know &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t rαpe people&amp;rdquo;. I also assume you&amp;rsquo;ve had the normal no-is-no, not-a-yes-is-still-a-no and probably already seen Tea and Consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</guid>
      <description>Elections &amp;amp; Voting #  I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;lsquo;murican, so this will be US centric, that said, the arguments here could likely be applied universally Issue 1: FPTP Voting Sucks #  lower standards of removal, ranked, transparency Budget voting
  Issue 2: Voters are really, really stupid #  voting based on if they like the person, how he/she looks, single issue voting
Issue 3: Two is the unfriendliest number #  Issue 4: Gerrymandering and Fraud and Astroturfing #     [TODO] Comment on Citizen&amp;rsquo;s United</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
