<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PHIL on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/phil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PHIL on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/phil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/economics/</guid>
      <description>Economic Systems # Cryptocurrency &amp;amp; NFTs # Why NFTs are bad: the long version (Antsstyle)
Hacker News comments on &amp;ldquo;PayPal raises fees for most domestic transaction types to 3.49% + $0.49&amp;rdquo;
https://basicappleguy.com/basicappleblog/999month
https://thehustle.co/americas-favorite-family-outings-are-increasingly-out-of-reach/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/environment/</guid>
      <description>Environmental Protection # u/SvenInFramse / @SvenInFrames (Twitter) / @sveninframes (Insta) u/neilrkaye (2021) Carbon Tax?
Geoengineering: A Horrible Idea We Might Have to Do (YouTube, Kurzgesagt)
A Strange New Blend of Rock and Plastic Is Forming on a Portuguese Island (Gizmodo)
A Plateful of Plastic - Visualising the amount of microplastic we eat (Reuters)
The poison found in everyone, even unborn babies – and who is responsible for it (The Guardian)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/armament/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/armament/</guid>
      <description>Personal Armament # Before we talk about this at all, I want to get one thing out of the way:
The 2nd amendment does not make gun ownership right or wrong. Laws - including the constitution - do not dictate morality and ethics. We all know there are unjust laws and many choose to break them because of it. So, if you use the argument &amp;ldquo;But Muh Constitution!&amp;rdquo; you&amp;rsquo;ve already made a bad argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/body/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Body # What should you be able to do with your body? The immediate reaction may be &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s my body, so whatever I want!&amp;rdquo; but think about it really, should everyone have the right to do anything they want with their body? What about suicide and self harm? What about when information about you is shared- if you take a DNA test, that impacts everyone related to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/environmentalconcern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/environmentalconcern/</guid>
      <description> Freedom of environmental concern # Vaccination # Local Pollution # PFAS # Air Quality # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/fairtrial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/fairtrial/</guid>
      <description> Fair Trial # Jury of your peers - how do we define peers? # Court of Public Opinion # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/freedoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/freedoms/</guid>
      <description>Freedoms and Rights # Before we go into some actual philosophy and current issues, let&amp;rsquo;s establish a baseline by looking at some of how freedoms and rights are laid out around the world
UN Declaration of Human Rights # The Universal Declaration of Human Rights from the United Nations lays out quite a few protections that are mostly ignored and unenforceable, but fundamentally agreeable. The actual text isn&amp;rsquo;t very long, but here&amp;rsquo;s the quick version</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/ownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/ownership/</guid>
      <description> Promise of Ownership # DRM, Right to Repair # See the DRM , Right To Repair , and Ads in content you&#39;ve already paid for sections from Chapter 9: Consumerism https://goel.io/drm-ownership
General Purpose Computation # https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HUEvRyemKSg
First Sale Doctrine # Trademark # https://www.ipwatchdog.com/2021/04/13/satan-shoes-trademark-blasphemy-free-speech/id=132184/
Reverse Engineering # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/press/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/press/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Press # Everyone is press, https://www.eff.org/bloggers
The Trump Administration Is Trying To Force BuzzFeed News To Divulge Its Sources With A Subpoena
anti-SLAPP laws
Whistle Blower Protections # https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_whistleblowers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/recording/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/recording/</guid>
      <description> Right to record, Right to know # if it is public, there&amp;rsquo;s reason to expect you may be if it is private, person to person, (not b2b or p2b) there&amp;rsquo;s an exception for if it only for personal or judicial (to be used in trial) use. I.E, can&amp;rsquo;t post it online if it&amp;rsquo;s unreasonable to expect being recorded </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/search/</guid>
      <description> Search and Seizure # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/speech/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Speech # xkcd №1357 The freedom of speech is weird, because it&amp;rsquo;s one that most of us recognize is that it should have limits because speech is powerful. The problem comes in what those limits are, which is why there are so many topics under debate:
Government Secrets Whistleblowing Hate Speech Political/Religious Opinion Copyright Parody Public Health Advertising of Sugar/Drugs Public Safety Creating Panic Encryption Self Incrimination Flag Burning National Pride Gag Orders National Security Porn/Cursing Public Decency (and the FCC) Advertising Spam Satire Defamation There&amp;rsquo;s also a question of where things go too far- at what point is speech a legitimate threat, and where is the line for actions that constitute harassment vs just being an asshole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/freedoms/travel/</guid>
      <description>Freedom of Travel # Immigration, Citizenship testing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/history/</guid>
      <description>History # Something to consider before going forward is that, assuming you&amp;rsquo;re from the US, the education you&amp;rsquo;ve received is likely very skewed both in what content is presented in the first place and how it&amp;rsquo;s presented. Unlike what most US education will tell you MLK did not magically end racism, not every US war has been just, and - no - our three branches of government are not working as intended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/arguments/</guid>
      <description>Philosophical Arguments # [TODO]how to construct a phil argument
Not simply accepting &amp;ldquo;Because that&amp;rsquo;s how it is&amp;rdquo; # I&amp;rsquo;m writing this at @292.78 on Day 132 of 12,020. I&amp;rsquo;m typing on a Dvorak, split, ortholinear keyboard in a markdown document using Arch Linux instead of M$ Word on Windows. I find music off the 12 tone scale interesting, and while I know 432 vs 440hz, isn&amp;rsquo;t going to open my 3rd eye, listening to microtonal or music made with just intonation is still something interesting to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Phil</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/basic-phil/</guid>
      <description>OPINION Before anything else, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out this is opinionated guides. Philosophy involves looking at the world around us and asking ourselves &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;, then making arguments for how things should be different and what moral frameworks work best to come to conclusions that optimize for something like happiness or &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; in the world. Given that both morals and &amp;lsquo;goodness&amp;rsquo; are not absolutes, the best way for me to write this guide and actually be of service to you as a reader is to provide my opinion and talk about why I believe what believe both from a researched &amp;lsquo;here are the facts&amp;rsquo; sense and from a &amp;lsquo;here is the moral framework that, with these facts, brought me to this conclusion&amp;rsquo; sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/community/</guid>
      <description>Community # Hopefully this isn&amp;rsquo;t a shock to anyone reading this, but I&amp;rsquo;m a furry.
owo uwu nuzzles rawr tehe So, I think I can share a little bit about why I joined the fandom, what being in a subculture community is like, and how some of those experiences have made me a better person and helped me be a part of or run successful online communities.
I hope that though this I can talk about what makes a community good or bad, what brings division, and what good rules for a healthy community look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumerism</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/consumerism/</guid>
      <description>Consumerism # Vega&amp;rsquo;s Maw, made for me by @NewtWolfdeer Look, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of falling for the tricks used to get people to consume. To buy and buy more. A good sale, even on something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know I previously wanted, still has a way of making my dumb lil&amp;rsquo; human brain go &amp;ldquo;OH!&amp;rdquo;
The problem is that consumers can easily fall into traps that lead them to buy things for a stupid reasons, these include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Letting Society Advance Though Art and Innovation # This video from Tom Scott on YouTube is a very good intro to everything I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about on this page, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you&amp;rsquo;ve watched it so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat everything that he says here.
What is Copyright? # [TODO]
What&amp;rsquo;s Wrong With that? # Watch a police officer admit to playing Taylor Swift to keep a video off YouTube (The Verge)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duties</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/duties/</guid>
      <description> Personal Duties # Maintaining health # Physical # Working out # Air quality # Mental # Socialized healthcare # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/education/</guid>
      <description>Education # Freedom of Information # Curriculum Changes # Basic Aid # Sex Education # Individualized, shared, and student led # [TODO] Faster, lower standards # Better testing # Fuck Respondus And Proctorio # The following is a (slightly edited) excerpt from an email I felt necessary to send to my professors at the start of the spring semester, 2021
First and foremost, they&amp;rsquo;re just creepy. Taking tests digitally but in person is fine with me because I know those computers are secure and dedicated to the single use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/fallacies/</guid>
      <description>Logical Fallacies (and a bit more) # If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet for more than about a quarter of a second, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely been accused of a whole host of logical fallacies. Unfortunately, most people really don&amp;rsquo;t understand what they&amp;rsquo;re saying and often use a lot of these incorrectly. On the other hand, you also likely encounter politicians people using these fallacies on a regular basis as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to call them out on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foriegn</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/foriegn/</guid>
      <description>Foreign Involvement # &#34; The Ministry of Peace concerns itself with war, the Ministry of Truth with lies, the Ministry of Love with torture and the Ministry of Plenty with starvation &#34; - George Orwell, 1984 In the US, we have the Department of Defense - the DOD. Whenever I think about that name, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think about that quote from 1984. The Department of Defense is primarily concerned with war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea Labs</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/idea-labs/</guid>
      <description>Idea Labs # This page is heavily inspired by Idea Labs and Echo Chambers, which is Part 8 of The Story Of Us. It&amp;rsquo;s a long read, but worth the time- you could read just the one part; however, I think it will be harder to understand without the previous 7 parts as context. Rather than try to repeat here what is put so well there, I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend you read at least that section and come back here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure # Power # Gravity-based batteries try to beat their chemical cousins with winches, weights, and mine shafts
Light Pollution # International Dark Sky Association
Air Quality # A paradigm shift to combat indoor respiratory infection
Networking (Mesh) # Housing and Land # Car-Free Neighborhoods in the US
The People the Suburbs Were Built for Are Gone (Vice)
Land Value Tax? # Birth Lottery # Where you&amp;rsquo;re born determines if you have access to even basic needs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/labor/</guid>
      <description>Labor and Compensation # The Case For Banning Non-Competes (slowboring.com)
EU pushes for &amp;lsquo;right to disconnect&amp;rsquo; from work at home (dw.com)
Please Consider My Application to Give You Labor So I Can Stay Alive
Workplace Wellbeing Is a Scam (Tribune)
Economic Inequality # Source code (GPL v3), by Matt Korostoff Wage Theft is a Much Bigger Problem Than Other Forms of Theft—But Workers Remain Mostly Unprotected
Ex-Google Employee Exposes Unequal Pay With Spreadsheet (Wall Street Journal)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law And Order</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/law-and-order/</guid>
      <description> Law Enforcement and Judgment # Trial of educated peers
Criminal Rehabilitation # end mandatory sentencing end bail no debtors prison
Divorce, Child Support # Jury Duty # Prosecutors &amp;amp; Public Defenders # Police # Illinois, First State to Tell Police They Can&amp;rsquo;t Lie to Minors in Interrogations (NPR)
Prisons # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/medical/</guid>
      <description>Healthcare Costs # Why is life expectancy in the US lower than in other rich countries?
White House wins ruling on disclosing health care prices (AP)
Drugs # Most drugs and prostitution should be legal at the age of 18. However, trafficking obviously not, and drugs must be sold by an individual with a license to deal and said license may be revoked if the product is sold with a false label or is tainted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpPhil Old</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/opphil-old/</guid>
      <description>Old Version, needs migrated: # Because you&amp;rsquo;re now somebody in the know about topics relating to technology and have a deeper understanding about issues that may effect the public, such as The FBI V Apple encryption case, Issues regrading internet speed and infrastructure, or The Government/NSA spying on people. There are plenty of issues that weather you like it or not you&amp;rsquo;re one of the few with enough information to truly understand and inform your peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil and The Internet</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-and-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>The fight for the Internet is never ending. At the time of writing, Senators want to mandate anti-piracy technology across the web (ArsTechnica).
Please call and write your congress critters, and let them know this is some stupid bullshit. Then ask your friends to do so as well.
You can use Find My Representative (house.gov) if you need to look up who represents you.
Even if you&amp;rsquo;re outside the US, this will still very likely affect you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-other/</guid>
      <description>Thank you # If you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far, I just want to say thank you. We need more people to really consider how ethics, politics, and copyright shape the world around us with technology and art as we design it and proceed with it. DeepFakes, Automated driving, and even more mass online censorship are issues we&amp;rsquo;re only going to face more with time, and it&amp;rsquo;s people like you who are going to help make sure we take the best path we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil, Misc</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/phil-misc/</guid>
      <description> Animal Rights (Industrial Scale Slaughter) # Organ donation # Tech can&amp;rsquo;t solve all your problems # Human problems need human solutions
Guns # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/religion/</guid>
      <description>Religion # Religion is, shocker, a deeply personal thing.
Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re of the opinion that you&amp;rsquo;re following the One True Good™. Maybe you think that everyone is crazy with their belief in imaginary friends. Maybe you think all of humanity is just a sort of womb for a new god.Maybe you think all the gods are real, and made from the belief of their followers. Maybe you just don&amp;rsquo;t give a 💩 Maybe you give a 💩 some days, think it&amp;rsquo;s all a bunch of 🐂💩 others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sex</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/sex/</guid>
      <description>Sex # In an ideal world, humankind would be driven forward by more than the initiate desire to reproduce and bone. But, we don&amp;rsquo;t live in an ideal world, and people like to have fun and feel good. (consensual) Sex is fun and feels good- so it should not be looked down on. Flirting, hooking up, being horny: They&amp;rsquo;re all natural and good. Unfortunately, today it seems Everyone is Beautiful and No One is Horny Consent # Look, I don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/phil/voting/</guid>
      <description>Elections &amp;amp; Voting # I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;lsquo;murican, so this will be US centric, that said, the arguments here could likely be applied universally Issue 1: FPTP Voting Sucks # lower standards of removal, ranked, transparency Budget voting
Issue 2: Voters are really, really stupid # voting based on if they like the person, how he/she looks, single issue voting
Issue 3: Two is the unfriendliest number # Issue 4: Gerrymandering, Fraud, and Astroturfing # [TODO] Comment on Citizen&amp;rsquo;s United</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
