<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>art on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in art on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Art Panic</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/aiartpanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/aiartpanic/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been on the internet at all lately, you&amp;rsquo;ve seen AI generated art and discussion of the impact of the tools. You&amp;rsquo;ve also probably seen a lot of hate for AI generated art. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of drama going on, as art focused communities across the internet decide how to handle this. Does AI generated/assisted art need tagged as such? Should it be allowed at all? There&amp;rsquo;s the whole Deviant Art situation (ArsTechnica).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Video Synthesis Journey</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/video-synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/video-synth/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not being paid to say any of this, I haven&amp;rsquo;t spoken to any of the companies listed here except for
Noisedeck, which while is made by two really awesome people, also gets a pretty nasty review here because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for this use case. Sleepy Circuits, which I&amp;rsquo;ve only talked to. I don&amp;rsquo;t even own their hardware. Furthermore, I have paid my own money for Visual Synthesizer, Cathodemer, and KodeLife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Bandwidth Images</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lowbandwidthimages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lowbandwidthimages/</guid>
      <description>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a website that you want to make use less bandwidth. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re paying by the byte for content delivery, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re worried about the environment, either way, let&amp;rsquo;s assume you want to make your images as small as possible. The obvious place to start is just shrinking your images. Here, this is a 4032x2268 .jpg shrunk down to a 1008x567 .jpg - 25% of the original quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
