<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://opguides.info/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quantization, Polarization, &amp; Indoctrination</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/quantized/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/quantized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;quote [wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantization)&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;strong&gt;Quantization&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of constraining an input from a continuous or otherwise large set of values (such as the real numbers) to a discrete set (such as the integers).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div style=&#34;display: block; text-align: right; width: 100%; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; line-height: 0px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;p style=&#34;font-size:.85em;color:var(--text-color);&#34; class=&#34;qsource&#34;&gt; &#xA;        - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantization&#34;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m less than two months from graduating with degrees in both Electrical Engineering and Computer Engineering. One subject that comes up a lot in both fields is &lt;em&gt;Quantization&lt;/em&gt;. Reading audio in to a micocontroller from a DAC? That continuous signal, represented physically by infinite values, now may only have 12 bits of resolution. Turning a knob on MIDI controller? There you get 7 bits. 128 possible values.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nebraksa LR107 - Stupdity Abound</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/lr107/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;book-hint gray&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;NOW, THEREFORE, BE IT RESOLVED BY THE MEMBERS OF THE ONE HUNDRED SEVENTH LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA, FIRST SESSION:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That we hereby reaffirm our solemn oaths of office by expressing a firm resolution to maintain and defend the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of Nebraska against every act of aggression whether foreign or domestic, including every act of unconstitutional abuse of power arising from the state or federal government.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That sounds fantastic, unfortunately, it seems that you also use this document to then break those oaths, so it may have been advisable to put this at the end of the document. Regardless, this point exists solely as a &amp;lsquo;war cry&amp;rsquo; of sorts to simultaneously stir up feelings of national pride in readers as well as stoke the flames of the exact crowd that believed there was an abuse of power so strongly that they choose to break into the U.S. Capitol or supported those that did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
