<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MUSIC on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MUSIC on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects #  Tremolo #  This is probably the easiest to understand audio effect. Put simply, fade the volume in and out automatically, usually pretty fast and with a bias so that the volume never completely cuts. It can also refer to a playing style where the same note is struck rapidly, leading to a similar effect. In VCV this can be done as simply as hooking up an LFO to a VCA&amp;rsquo;s CV input like we did here, but turning up the frequency of the LFO-2 module (note, that here there is no bias so the volume does actually cut out):    Vibrato #  Vibrato as an effect requires pitch shifting, which I suppose actually makes it akin to FM synthesis as described above, regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as applying a, typically subtle, pitch &amp;lsquo;wobble&amp;rsquo; into the sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Drums #  TR808, syth, short ADSR, noise, snare, tom, kick, hat, clap, bell,
Guitar Pedals For Drums (YouTube, JHS Pedals)
Strings #  guitar, lute, dulcimer, dual/single string, acoustic, electric, electroacoustic
guitar pickups, slides, kapo, tuning (equal v just), wound, physical modeling (Kurplus Strong)
The History Of Guitar (Youtube, Rob Scallon)
Tuning a Floyd Rose Guitar (YouTube)
Synths #  Modular, semi-modular, software
  The Esoteric #  feedback only, no input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixers #  mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring #  https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and spotify
Mixing and Mastering #  eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/music-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/music-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the part where I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to explain how to read music or something boring like that. Really though, that&amp;rsquo;s not why you&amp;rsquo;re here. So let me start by giving you a bit of motivation. In a bit I&amp;rsquo;ll be going though how to use VCV Rack, a free (with paid addons, but those aren&amp;rsquo;t necessary) program for making music. But as we go though each bit is going to look so -basic- that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see the bigger picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware #  MIDI #  MPE, aftertouch, vel, virtual midi, midi cc v pb v mod v note on/off v sysmsg v OSC v midi2.0
Note, there&amp;rsquo;s a pretty limited number of MPE capable instruments, thankfully there&amp;rsquo;s stil a decent price range between them. This list is not exhaustive, but I think gives a good sampling:
Small:
Artiphon Orba
Roli Lightpad Blocks
Haken Audio ContinuuMini
 Big:
Expressive e - Osmose (Demo)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software #  Live Coding Tools #     Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot / Demo     SonicPi     ORCΑ Learn Orca Extra Tools for ORCA:  Cassetter for ORCA Aioi - UDP to complex OSC for ORCA  Pilot - 16 voice synth for ORCA    Noton A minimal logic gates playground, written in ANSI C. Made by the same developers as ORCΑ    Chuck &amp;ldquo;Chuck is a programming language for real-time sound synthesis and music creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpMusic Intro</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/opmusic-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/opmusic-intro/</guid>
      <description>Opinionated Music #  Hey there.
My name is Vega. I know there are plenty of tutorials and ways to learn online be it on YouTube, SkillShare, or online classes provided for free by various universities. The difference here is there is no bullshit, no babysitting, and lots of bias as a result of personal experience. My views of things like what music software is bad or what equipment you should buy to learn with will be expressed directly and bluntly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Cool People #  https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/vcvrackchat
Neurotypique https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4oBI5piGMznFMZdtEC0FhA
Omri Cohen, a Rack Master&amp;rsquo;s YouTube Channel
Loopop RedMeansRecording AdamNeely AndrewHuang Rob Scallon Pipe Organ Video (YouTube), Theorbo Video (YouTube),
Reddit: https://www.reddit.com/r/vcvrack/ , https://www.reddit.com/r/synthesizers/ , https://www.reddit.com/r/synthdiy/ , https://www.reddit.com/r/modular/
Other Resources #  PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (Github) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequencing and MIDI</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/sequencing-and-midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/sequencing-and-midi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing #  random, sample/hold, probability, piano rolls, trackers, AI based, euclidian, trigger/gate/len, humanization
Creating Melodies [Music Guides from Ableton]
Melody Guide [edmprod.com]
MIDI effects #  Arp, velocity, pitch bend, mod, sustain, generative, legatto</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise #  Samples #   a snippet of a .wav file open in audacity
 A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. The easiest to explain is what is usually meant by sample: a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opinionatedguide.github.io/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: #   Theory #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest. I can&amp;rsquo;t read music and I don&amp;rsquo;t know scales. Why, then, would I in any way think I&amp;rsquo;m qualified to write anything about music? Well, let me stop you right there, I&amp;rsquo;m not. I make music for fun. However, I like to think that people enjoy my music and I enjoy listening to it myself as I make it, and though my experience I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a little here and there to make sure things don&amp;rsquo;t sound awful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
