<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musics on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musics on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://opguides.info/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics # Distortion # How Distortion Works in Music (Ben Sheron&amp;rsquo;s Blog)
Dynamics &amp;amp; Transients # When thinking of effects we have some nice mental models for what things sound like. Delay is just echos, reverb adds space, etc. Distortions sound simple enough, they just make it more aggressive - the problem is, they sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t. We have to think like an audio engineer here.
First, they sound massively different depending on the volume and frequency content of the input.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</guid>
      <description>Filters (LP, HP, BP, Notch) # See the signal processing chapters. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do real time DSP and if you want to modulate the cutoff, you&amp;rsquo;re probably stuck with an IIR. FWIW, the delay of an FIR means the linear phase is often worse than not anyway. If licensing isn&amp;rsquo;t an issue, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to start with at least https://www.musicdsp.org/en/latest/Filters/index.html or really any DSP library. Implementing a well performing filter isn&amp;rsquo;t that hard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/meta/</guid>
      <description>Meta # Mid-Side # Want to apply a different effect to the center of your sound than the more hard-panned left or right sounds - that is, does applying a different effect tho &amp;ldquo;middle&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sides&amp;rdquo; of your audio sound interesting to you?
Gain-Staging # Gain staging is the practice of setting the gain or level of each stage in a signal chain, such as in a mixer or a sound system, to an optimal level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</guid>
      <description>Misc Effects # Auto-Tune # Doing autotune in code is well beyond the scope of a small comment. Outside of just throwing AI at the problem - witch is likely to sound god awful - there&amp;rsquo;s no magic bullet here. It&amp;rsquo;s spectral analysis hell. Given it&amp;rsquo;s basically a meme now, I assume you know what Auto-Tune is. What you may not realize is that not all auto-tune is, well, auto.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</guid>
      <description>Time Based Effects # Delay # There are a million ways to make a delay that&amp;rsquo;s weird. Most basic? Make a ring buffer and add the signals, probably with a dry/wet mix. Less basic? IDK, add in multiple taps on the ring buffer? Use random samples in the buffer? Change the sample rate of the buffer? Reverse the buffer occasionally? Go nuts. Delay is basically echo. Take a sound in, and repeat it it it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</guid>
      <description>Trivial Effects # Tremolo # This is probably the easiest to understand audio effect. Put simply, fade the volume in and out automatically. This can be done at different speeds (really fast for a &amp;lsquo;deep&amp;rsquo; effect or slow for something pad-like) and with a bias so that the volume never completely cuts. It can also refer to a playing style where the same note is struck rapidly, leading to a similar effect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstarted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstarted/</guid>
      <description>Getting Our Hands Dirty # Music, like any creative endeavor, requires you keep your left and right brains equally talkative.
Logical Mixing parts together Studying music theory Getting core components of the song laid out Practicing tecnique on an instrument Writing lyrics with good timings and structure Creative Using weird sound sources Combining effects Finding inspiration outside of music Adding fun frills to the song Writing vivid, emotional lyrics If you know that you&amp;rsquo;re a creative type, try to focus on the science and math and technique of things more on these pages and as you practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstartedcont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/gettingstartedcont/</guid>
      <description>Continuing our Adventure # Picking up where we left off,
This lil&amp;rsquo; synth works, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give us much control, and unlike a real instrument, after we let go of the key it just immediately stops. Similarly, most real instruments have a either a bit of a pluck at the start or a more gentle fade in.
This leads us to the idea of envelopes. In music, you&amp;rsquo;ll often want to draw a shape that evelopes a signal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/electro-mechanical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/electro-mechanical/</guid>
      <description>Electro-Mechanical Instruments # I have a particular love of instruments that sit in that acoustic sweet spot where i feels as though there&amp;rsquo;s a physical resonating body merged with a synthesizer, where you can hear key clicks and a physical body but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t respond like we&amp;rsquo;re used to yet it&amp;rsquo;s not so avant-garde as not not be useful or just a gimmick.
Think a hurdy gurdy, but with an inbuilt tube amp and the drones are actually tube based oscillators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</guid>
      <description>The Esoteric # feedback only, no input. i love this instrument. pic.twitter.com/IR6lmxZGHJ
&amp;mdash; 𝒆𝒎𝒎𝒂 (@HECKSCAPER) July 31, 2020 𝐡𝐨𝐰 𝐢𝐭 𝐰𝐨𝐫𝐤𝐬: pedal rig rundown &amp;amp; building a sound (Emma Essex)
A neat on-guitar effects board (Instagram, ian.costabile)
Why To Modular With Guitar (YouTube, Knobs)
Otamatone Metal - Rob Scallon
Theorbo - The enormous 14 string lute (YouTube)
Double-sided Guitar Jam (YouTube)
Octobasse: A really, really big upright bass (YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</guid>
      <description>Percussion # Theory # Before I even dive into Percussion, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out how generic the term is. Just looking at the Wikipedia page for drum kit, you&amp;rsquo;ll see this: Drum Kit page on Wikipedia and clearly that&amp;rsquo;s still not an exhaustive list. Just off the top of my head I can see it lacks the Cajon or Taiko as acoustic instruments, let alone anything more specific than electronic drum, which can make for a class all its own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</guid>
      <description>Strings # Guitars # Picture of my character by Alex the Nerd Bird Acoustic, Electric, Acoustic-Electric? # Hollow Body, Solid Body? # Pickups? # Frets? # Some guitars used &amp;ldquo;fanned&amp;rdquo; or multi-scale frets. This is most common on extended range (7+ string) guitars. The intent is that the scale length can be longer for the thick string and shorter for the thin so that the tension on all of them is reasonable (it avoids the low string being floppy).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</guid>
      <description>Synthesizers # I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about FM, additive, subtractive, etc. in Sound Sources. Here I want to go into how they fit into a song, the idea of pads, leads, bass. As well as how a lot of famous sounds have been done and what some of the most famous synths are. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to cover some of why some newer synths are exciting, like the Hydrasynth, Continumm, Norand Mono, Subharmonicon, Polygogo,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</guid>
      <description>Wind # What is a Wind Instrument? # A wind instrument is a musical instrument that contains some type of resonator (usually a tube) in which a column of air is set into vibration by the player blowing into (or over) a mouthpiece set at or near the end of the resonator. The pitch of the vibration is determined by the length of the tube and by manual modifications of the effective length of the vibrating column of air.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/intro/</guid>
      <description>Bang!. Zwoop. Bada-dap-bap. # Here&amp;rsquo;s a sine wave.
I want you to try something. Put your foot back up on your heel and each time you see a new peak, tap the ground. Play a non existent kick drum to each new peak. (or just tap a finger on your desk)
To some people, keeping this beat is difficult. To some it will come naturally. Either is fine. This could be the tempo of a song, the metronome that everything is playing in time to, and it&amp;rsquo;s just a wave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/lies/</guid>
      <description>I lied # Well, sort of. I haven&amp;rsquo;t told you anything that&amp;rsquo;s wrong, but I have been omitting something.
The software we&amp;rsquo;re using, VCV Rack, is very weird. It lacks many features that most people expect in a DAW - Digital Audio Workstation. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk significantly more about DAWs in a coming page, but I need to bring them up now because there&amp;rsquo;s some things that VCV absolutely does not do well that will make creating full songs that sound like music you&amp;rsquo;re probably used to unnecessarily difficult.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/lyrics/</guid>
      <description>12 - Lyrics &amp;amp; Vocals # Lyrics and just sung poetry! - Some moron that has never made music Oh fuck directly off. This is poetry:
They thought there be seven and they&#39;re right. There is seven sins without I I come from a place that many do find Heroes and villains find me inside When they do what they do for family Regardless of who dies Blood is my name l o Many families have cried o r d i e n d once so dear tossed aside Blood is my name, the sin of o n d s undeserved I&#39;m a sin that lurks unheard Religious and Righteous often mistaken Use my name as if it is not forsaken Do not think that blood is a bond to never be broken I find my way to bring many to do things that should never be spoken How should that be sung, pray tell?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</guid>
      <description>MIDI in Detail # Musical Instrument Digital Interface, or MIDI is what it sounds like, the primary way to get data between devices digitally. Want to tell a hardware synth to play a sequence you arranged on your computer? MIDI. Want to play notes into your computer using a keyboard? MIDI. Want to sequence drums, with varying &amp;lsquo;velocity&amp;rsquo; on each hit? MIDI.
Sounds Great?
For the most part, yeah. Everything works together and you can make all your hardware speak the same language.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</guid>
      <description>Piracy? # Plugins++ # Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not the police. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care what you do on your system. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to outright condone you to find pirated versions of music software, though- in part for liability, but mostly because you absolutely will get a virus. Some sites are more reputable than others, and if you&amp;rsquo;re careful, you can probably yoink at least a few things. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you should.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</guid>
      <description>Psychoacoustics and Cultural Associations # When we hear music, we don&amp;rsquo;t hear individual sine waves and sum them up. We don&amp;rsquo;t hear instruments devoid of context, either- a ukulele carries a different cultural meaning than a mandolin. We also don&amp;rsquo;t just hear what comes out the speakers as plainly as basic frequencies. Our ears process what we here. Our ears take in the reverb of the room, ignore sounds before and after drum hits, find speech in sounds that weren&amp;rsquo;t meant to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/seqandmidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/seqandmidi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing &amp;amp; Midi # MIDI In Detail covers the technical bits of MIDI in much more detail, but you&#39;ll still probably want to read this first if you don&#39;t know what MIDI even is. Sequencing # The definition of a sequence is pretty obvious, but don&amp;rsquo;t be misled by the name- a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; is not always just a list of notes to be played one after the other. Sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s overlap, gaps (rests), bends from one note to another (legato) and almost always information about how hard a note is pressed and how long it should be held for are saved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</guid>
      <description>Digital Audio Workstations+ # A Digital Audio Workstations is software that allows you to record and edit audio, host and play digital instruments, arrange the parts in a timeline, and mix the audio together. The most common DAWs you&amp;rsquo;ll see are Ableton Live (Often called just &amp;ldquo;Ableton&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Live&amp;rdquo;) and FL Studio, but there are plenty of other options as well, many of which are listed below.
The definition of a DAW is a bit fuzzy, as tools like VCV Rack and Audacity- both of which we&amp;rsquo;ve seen previously- have features that make them very DAW like and can be used to make full tracks (assuming you have hardware instruments to record into Audacity)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</guid>
      <description>Programmable Music Tools # Before getting into this list, I also want to point out that there&amp;rsquo;s an endless number of programmable music sequencing tools which can be found built into VST plugins, larger audio software, and even video games. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly fond of the huge number of interesting sequencers for VCV Rack, such as Quad Algorithmic Rhythm Generator, Entropia, Fate, Marbles, and Orca&amp;rsquo;s Heart - just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</guid>
      <description>Plugins # This page is a massive work in progress. Even the things that look done may be wrong. [TODO] break list up more
Sound Sources Vintage Synths Modern Synths Bass Synths Sampled / Acoustic Modeling Percussive Effects Dynamics Filter Reverb Delay Trivial Weird as fuck Misc Tools Organization MIDI generation This is probably where the most bias of any of the lists on this page will show as I obviously can&amp;rsquo;t list every possible plugin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</guid>
      <description>VCV Rack Tips &amp;amp; Tricks # I am not affiliated with VCV or the Rack software in any way. Despite the mess in the VCV community, I&amp;rsquo;ve still put in a lot of time in the software and run a pretty large group chat on Telegram where it (alongside hardware Eurorack) is the main focus. In that chat, there&amp;rsquo;s been a few recurring questions, this page is just some of those questions and answers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects # This chapter is broken up into subsections, check the menu and it should have expanded! Please Read This, for real # Automation Lanes Are Your Friend # A lot of audio effects boil down to automating some simple parameter. Sometimes you may not actually need a dedicated effect and can instead get by with using Automation Lanes (YouTube, once upon a synth) in your Digital Audio Workstation (DAW)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Instruments # If you&amp;rsquo;re going to be playing an instrument though a computer - and I mean either an instrument which makes its own noise like a guitar or a controller like a MIDI keyboard - you&amp;rsquo;ll want to adjust your audio buffer size as best you can. See Optimizing The Latency Of Your PC Audio Interface from Sound on Sound for more info about this, but generally just set your buffer size as low as you can until it starts to sound like it&amp;rsquo;s horribly broken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixing &amp;amp; Mastering # Mixers # mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring # https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and Spotify
Mixing # eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Mastering # Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)
Studio Monitors, Headphones, and Amps # @Tirrelous on Twitter Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of all the specs you might want to understand if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to buy headphones or studio monitors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware # While you could make all of your music with just a computer, you’ll probably want some tools that make your life as a musician easier and let you explore ideas faster. Like I said back in the Audio Effects Chapter , in my experience, making music depends on a really quick brain to input device feedback loop. Being able to turn a physical knob and mash physical keys will often lead to better results if only because you’re able to try things both faster and by physically interacting with something that you may not have thought of otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software # Audio Sources # Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot Various from SugarBytes I really like Consequence - Chord GroveboxFactory - Mod Matrix PolysynthGuitarist - Guitar Emulation, easy to programDrum Computer - Drum SynthObscurium - I don&amp;rsquo;t even know, but it&amp;rsquo;s cool.Cyclop - Neat Synth, good for bassEgoist - Weird audio stem re-groover?Thesys - MIDI Sequencer Websites # Google Drum Machine (Like XO)
Audio backends # [TODO]
Windows # ASIO # Direct Sound # WSAPI # Linux # Seriously, check out Making Sense of The Linux Audio Stack on Venam&amp;rsquo;s Blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources # PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (GitHub) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses
Sample Packs &amp;amp; Wavetables # Echo Sound Works Coda (~$30) - Wavetables &amp;amp; Serum presets. These wavetables are truly amazing.
Cool People # https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/thePatchBay - some shameless self promo, as this is my chat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise* # * Excluding traditional instruments. We&amp;rsquo;ll get there soon.
Samples # A snippet of a .wav file open in audacity A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. Still, for the generic term what is usually meant is a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: # Don&amp;rsquo;t undervalue just sitting down and listening to music, trying to figure out what parts you enjoy and thinking about how it compares to what you&amp;rsquo;ve made, what you think you should change to sound better. Along with that, it helps to look at breakdowns of music done on YouTube. I particularly recommend all of the videos from 12tone&amp;rsquo;s channel.
Theory # I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/video/</guid>
      <description>Video &amp;amp; Streaming # &amp;hellip;Psst, if you&amp;rsquo;re on this page, you may be interested in My blog post on Video Synthesis Before anything else, I need to crush some hopes and dreams:
You absolutely should not expect your YouTube or Twitch channel to make it big. Even if you put in the work, invest in good equipment, and make cool content regularly, and promote the shit out of yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s still a game of luck on if you can go viral and if you can retain any viewership whatsoever after doing so.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
