<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MUSIC on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MUSIC on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Distortion #   How Distortion Works in Music (Ben Sheron&amp;rsquo;s Blog)
Clipping (Soft &amp;amp; Hard) #  Clipping does exactly what it sounds like, it just chops off the wave. Usually on both the top and bottom.
Hard Clipping
 Soft Clipping
  The key take away from the two different kinds of clipping is that while both add harmonics, hard clipping adds significantly more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</guid>
      <description>Filters (LP, HP, BP, Notch) #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  https://www.perfectcircuit.com/signal/learning-synthesis-filters
Low Pass Filters #  Low Pass filters do what you think, they let the low frequencies pass and cut out the high frequencies. As with most filters, this will typically not be a sharp cutoff but instead be a gradual fading of the higher frequencies. Despite this, there is still a point called the cut off frequency, which is defined as the point where the signal is cut by 3db (what this means is discussed below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</guid>
      <description>Misc Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Auto-Tune #  Given it&amp;rsquo;s basically a meme now, I assume you know what Auto-Tune is. What you may not realize is that not all auto-tune is, well, auto. A lot of the time it&amp;rsquo;s done manually, painstakingly correcting the tuning. If the original sound is close enough, it&amp;rsquo;s usually pretty easy to get it to sound natural too.
Also keep in mind pitch correction isn&amp;rsquo;t just for vocals, you might want to pitch correct your guitar playing, change a note in an already recorded sequence when you change keys, or even just use it as a glitchy effect on pitch bends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</guid>
      <description>Time Based Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Delay #  Delay is basically echo. Take a sound in, and repeat it it it. Normally the main controls on a delay are &amp;lsquo;Time&amp;rsquo;, which controls how long of a delay there is before each repeat, &amp;lsquo;Feedback&amp;rsquo; which controls how much the level is reduced each time the delay repeats (and in turn, how many audible repetitions there are), and &amp;lsquo;Dry/Wet&amp;rsquo; which controls how the signal is blended, entirely dry will have no delay, entirely wet may even miss the initial sound adding a weird latency before you hear what you&amp;rsquo;re playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</guid>
      <description>Trivial Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Tremolo #  This is probably the easiest to understand audio effect. Put simply, fade the volume in and out automatically. This can be done at different speeds (really fast for a &amp;lsquo;deep&amp;rsquo; effect or slow for something pad-like) and with a bias so that the volume never completely cuts. It can also refer to a playing style where the same note is struck rapidly, leading to a similar effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</guid>
      <description>The Esoteric #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  feedback only, no input. i love this instrument. pic.twitter.com/IR6lmxZGHJ
&amp;mdash; 𝒆𝒎𝒎𝒂 (@HECKSCAPER) July 31, 2020  𝐡𝐨𝐰 𝐢𝐭 𝐰𝐨𝐫𝐤𝐬: pedal rig rundown &amp;amp; building a sound (Emma Essex)
     A neat on-guitar effects board (Instagram, ian.costabile)
Why To Modular With Guitar (YouTube, Knobs)
Otamatone Metal - Rob Scallon
Theorbo - The enormous 14 string lute (YouTube)
Double-sided Guitar Jam (YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</guid>
      <description>Percussion #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  Theory #  Before I even dive into Percussion, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out how generic the term is. Just looking at the Wikipedia page for drum kit you&amp;rsquo;ll see this:
Drum Kit page on Wikipedia and clearly that&amp;rsquo;s still not an exhaustive list. Just off the top of my head I can see it lacks the Cajon or Taiko as acoustic instruments, let alone anything more specific than electronic drum, which can make for a class all its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</guid>
      <description>Strings #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  Picture of my character by Alex the Nerd Bird Guitars #  Acoustic, Electric, Acoustic-Electric? #  Hollow Body, Solid Body? #  Pickups? #  Picks, Slides, fingers, or&amp;hellip; chopsticks? #       Classical Guitars? #     6-String #  Bass #  12-String #  Extended Range #  Fretless #  Baritone #  Lap Steel &amp;amp; Pedal Steel #  Pianos #  Clavinet #  Dulcimers #  Hammered #      Harp #  [TODO] + Pedals on harp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</guid>
      <description>Synths #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  [TODO] I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about FM, additive, subtractive, etc. in Sound Sources. Here I want to go into how they fit into a song, the idea of pads, leads, bass. As well as how a lot of famous sounds have been done and what some of the most famous synths are. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to cover some of why some newer synths are exciting, like the Hydrasynth, Continumm, Norand Mono, Subharmonicon, Polygogo,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</guid>
      <description>Wind #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  What is a Wind Instrument? #   A wind instrument is a musical instrument that contains some type of resonator (usually a tube) in which a column of air is set into vibration by the player blowing into (or over) a mouthpiece set at or near the end of the resonator. The pitch of the vibration is determined by the length of the tube and by manual modifications of the effective length of the vibrating column of air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</guid>
      <description>MIDI in Detail #  Musical Instrument Digital Interface, or MIDI is what it sounds like, the primary way to get data between devices digitally. Want to tell a hardware synth to play a sequence you arranged on your computer? MIDI. Want to play notes into your computer using a keyboard? MIDI. Want to sequence drums, with varying &amp;lsquo;velocity&amp;rsquo; on each hit? MIDI.
Sounds Great?
For the most part, yeah. Everything works together and you can make all your hardware speak the same language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/musicpiracy/</guid>
      <description>Piracy? #  Plugins++ #  Look, I&amp;rsquo;m not the police. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care what you do on your system. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to outright condone you find pirated versions of music software though- in part for liability, but mostly because you absolutely will get a virus. That said, some sites are more reputable than others, and if you&amp;rsquo;re careful, you can probably yoink at least a few things. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/psychoacoustic/</guid>
      <description>Psychoacoustics and Cultural Associations #   When we here music, we don&amp;rsquo;t hear individual sine waves and sum them up. We don&amp;rsquo;t hear instruments devoid of context either- a ukulele carries a different cultral meaning than a mandolin. We also don&amp;rsquo;t just hear what comes out the speakers as planly as basic frequencies. Our ears process what we here. Our ears take in the reverb of the room, ignore sounds before and after drum hits, find speech in sounds that weren&amp;rsquo;t meant to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/daw/</guid>
      <description>Digital Audio Workstations+ #   document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true; A Digital Audio Workstations is software that allows you to record and edit audio, host and play digital instruments, arrange the parts in a time line, and mix the audio together. The most common DAWs you&amp;rsquo;ll see are Ableton Live (Often called just &amp;ldquo;Ableton&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Live&amp;rdquo;) and FL Studio, but there are plenty of other options as well, many of which are listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/livecoding/</guid>
      <description>Live Coding Tools #   document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true;    Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot / Demo     SonicPi     ORCΑ  Learn Orca Extra Tools for ORCA:  Cassetter for ORCA Aioi - UDP to complex OSC for ORCA  Pilot - 16 voice synth for ORCA    Noton A minimal logic gates playground, written in ANSI C. Made by the same developers as ORCΑ    Chuck &amp;ldquo;Chuck is a programming language for real-time sound synthesis and music creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/plugin/</guid>
      <description>Plugins #  This page is a massive work in progress  document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true; This is probably where the most bias of any of the lists on this page will show as I obviously can&amp;rsquo;t list every possible plugin. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll list those that I think are particularly good both in terms of value and function. While the list below does have ranking (copper, silver, gold) everything I&amp;rsquo;m listing I think is good, even the &amp;lsquo;copper&amp;rsquo; ones!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/vcv/</guid>
      <description>VCV Rack Tips &amp;amp; Tricks #  I am not affiliated with VCV or the Rack software in any way. Despite the mess in the VCV community, I&amp;rsquo;ve still put in a lot of time in the software and run a pretty large group chat on Telegram where it (along side hardware Eurorack) is the main focus. In that chat, there&amp;rsquo;s been a feel recurring questions, this page is just some of those questions and answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  This chapter is broken up into sub sections, check the menu and it should have expanded!  Please Read This, for real   Automation Lanes Are Your Friend #  A lot of audio effects boil down to automating some simple parameter. Some times you may not actually need a dedicated effect and can instead get by with using Automation Lanes (YouTube, once upon a synth) in you Digital Audio Workstation (DAW)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Instruments #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  If you&amp;rsquo;re going to be playing an instrument though a computer - and I mean either an instrument which makes it&amp;rsquo;s own noise like a guitar or a controller like a MIDI keyboard - you&amp;rsquo;ll want to adjust your audio buffer size as best you can. See Optimizing The Latency Of Your PC Audio Interface from Sound on Sound for more info about this, but generally just set your buffer size as low as you can until it starts to sound like it&amp;rsquo;s horribly broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixing &amp;amp; Mastering #  Mixers #  mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring #  https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and spotify
Mixing #  eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Mastering #  Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)
 Studio Monitors, Headphones, and Amps #  @Tirrelous on Twitter  Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of all the specs you might want to understad if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to buy headphones or studio monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the part where I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to explain how to read music or something boring like that. Really though, that&amp;rsquo;s not why you&amp;rsquo;re here. So let me start by giving you a bit of motivation. In a bit I&amp;rsquo;ll be going though how to use VCV Rack, a free (with paid addons, but those aren&amp;rsquo;t necessary) program for making music. But as we go though each bit is going to look so -basic- that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see the bigger picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware #  While you could make all of your music with just computer, you’ll probably want some tools that make your life as a musician easier and let you explore ideas faster. Like I said back in the Audio Effects Chapter  , in my experience, making music depends on a really quick brain to input device feedback loop. Being able to turn a physical knob and mash physical keys will often lead to better results if only because you’re able to try things both faster and by physically interacting with something that you may not have thought of otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/software/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software #   document.getElementById(&#34;softMenu&#34;).open = true; Audio Sources #     Name &amp;amp; Link Description Screenshot          Various from SugarBytes I really like Consequence - Chord GroveboxFactory - Mod Matrix PolysynthGuitarist - Guitar Emulation, easy to programDrum Computer - Drum SynthObscurium - I don&amp;rsquo;t even know, but it&amp;rsquo;s cool.Cyclop - Neat Synth, good for bassEgoist - Weird audio stem re-groover?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources #  PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (Github) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses
Sample Packs &amp;amp; Wavetables #  Echo Sound Works Coda (~$30) - Wavetables &amp;amp; Serum presets. These wavetables are truly amazing.
Cool People #  https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/thePatchBay  - some shameless self promo, as this is my chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequencing and MIDI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing &amp;amp; Midi #  This chapter only goes over the basics of MIDI. Because MIDI is so important to music production I&amp;rsquo;ll dive much deeper into the details of MIDI in Chapter 6½ - MIDI in Detail Sequencing #  The definition of a sequence is pretty obvious, but don&amp;rsquo;t be misled by the name- a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; is not always just a list of notes to be played one after the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise #  Samples #  A snippet of a .wav file open in audacity  A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. The easiest to explain is what is usually meant by sample: a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: #   Don&amp;rsquo;t undervalue just sitting down and listening to music, trying to figure out what parts you enjoy and thinking about how it compares to what you&amp;rsquo;ve made, what you think you should change to sound better.
Theory #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest. I can&amp;rsquo;t read music and I don&amp;rsquo;t know scales. Why, then, would I in any way think I&amp;rsquo;m qualified to write anything about music?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/video/</guid>
      <description>Video &amp;amp; Streaming #   Before anythinge else, I need to crush some hopes and dreams:
You absolutely should not expect your YouTube or Twitch channel to make it big. Even if you put in the work, invest in good eqipment, and make cool content regularly, and promote the shit out of yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s still a game of luck on if you can go viral and if you can retain any viewership whatsoever after doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
