<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MUSIC on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MUSIC on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/dynamics/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Distortion #   How Distortion Works in Music (Ben Sheron&amp;rsquo;s Blog)
Clipping (Soft &amp;amp; Hard) #  Waveshaping #  Wavefolding #  This is one of those things where while the name is pretty self descriptive, you sorta just have to see the signal on a scope and hear it to see what it does.
Like any distortion, it ultimately adds in more harmonics, so it will make it sound higher pitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/filter/</guid>
      <description>Filters (LP, HP, BP, Notch) #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  https://www.perfectcircuit.com/signal/learning-synthesis-filters
Low Pass Filters #  Low Pass filters do what you think, they let the low frequencies pass and cut out the high frequencies. As with most filters, this will typically not be a sharp cutoff but instead be a gradual fading of the higher frequencies. Despite this, there is still a point called the cut off frequency, which is defined as the point where the signal is cut by 3db (what this means is discussed below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/misc/</guid>
      <description>Misc Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Auto-Tune #  Vocoders #  Ableton Live VOCODER Tutorial (YouTube, Once Upon A Synth)
[TODO] all of it&amp;hellip; but also mention how a lot of vocie effects use a combo of autotune, vocode, and pitch shifting
Glitch, Granular, and Pitch #  Talk-boxes #  Spectral Editing #  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/time/</guid>
      <description>Time Based Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Delay #  Delay is basically echo. Take a sound in, and repeat it it it. Normally the main controls on a delay are &amp;lsquo;Time&amp;rsquo;, which controls how long of a delay there is before each repeat, &amp;lsquo;Feedback&amp;rsquo; which controls how much the level is reduced each time the delay repeats (and in turn, how many audible repetitions there are), and &amp;lsquo;Dry/Wet&amp;rsquo; which controls how the signal is blended, entirely dry will have no delay, entirely wet may even miss the initial sound adding a weird latency before you hear what you&amp;rsquo;re playing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/trivial/</guid>
      <description>Trivial Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  Tremolo #  This is probably the easiest to understand audio effect. Put simply, fade the volume in and out automatically. This can be done at different speeds (really fast for a &amp;lsquo;deep&amp;rsquo; effect or slow for something pad-like) and with a bias so that the volume never completely cuts. It can also refer to a playing style where the same note is struck rapidly, leading to a similar effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/esoteric/</guid>
      <description>The Esoteric #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  feedback only, no input. i love this instrument. pic.twitter.com/IR6lmxZGHJ
&amp;mdash; 𝒆𝒎𝒎𝒂 (@HECKSCAPER) July 31, 2020  𝐡𝐨𝐰 𝐢𝐭 𝐰𝐨𝐫𝐤𝐬: pedal rig rundown &amp;amp; building a sound (Emma Essex)
     A neat on-guitar effects board (Instagram, ian.costabile)
Why To Modular With Guitar (YouTube, Knobs)
Otamatone Metal - Rob Scallon
Theorbo - The enormous 14 string lute (YouTube)
Double-sided Guitar Jam (YouTube)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/perc/</guid>
      <description>Percussion #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  Theory #  Before I even dive into Percussion, I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to point out how generic the term is. Just looking at the Wikipedia page for drum kit you&amp;rsquo;ll see this:
Drum Kit page on Wikipedia and clearly that&amp;rsquo;s still not an exhaustive list. Just off the top of my head I can see it lacks the Cajon or Taiko as acoustic instruments, let alone anything more specific than electronic drum, which can make for a class all its own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/strings/</guid>
      <description>Strings #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  guitar, lute, dulcimer, dual/single string, acoustic, electric, electroacoustic
guitar pickups, slides, kapo, tuning (equal v just), wound, physical modeling (Kurplus Strong)
https://grunfy.com/scaler.html
The History Of Guitar (Youtube, Rob Scallon)
Tuning a Floyd Rose Guitar (YouTube)
My New 18-String Hurdy-Gurdy (YouTube, Patty Gurdy) (also see 5 System of a Down riffs on hurdy gurdy)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/synth/</guid>
      <description>Synths #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  Modular, semi-modular, software
The Design of the Roland Juno oscillators (Stargirl Flowers&#39; Blog)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/wind/</guid>
      <description>Wind #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/midi/</guid>
      <description>MIDI in Detail #  Musical Instrument Digital Interface, or MIDI is what it sounds like, the primary way to get data between devices digitally. Want to tell a hardware synth to play a sequence you arranged on your computer? MIDI. Want to play notes into your computer using a keyboard? MIDI. Want to sequence drums, with varying &amp;lsquo;velocity&amp;rsquo; on each hit? MIDI.
Sounds Great?
For the most part, yeah. Everything works together and you can make all your hardware speak the same language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/effects/</guid>
      <description>Audio Effects #   document.getElementById(&#34;effectMenu&#34;).open = true;  A lot of audio effects boil down to automating some simple parameter. Some times you may not actually need a dedicated effect and can instead get by with using Automation Lanes (YouTube, once upon a synth) in you Digital Audio Workstation (DAW) Also don&amp;rsquo;t get to deep into gear envy. Effects are awesome and it&amp;rsquo;s tempting to either want to collect them and hoard them like a happy dragon on a pile of gold or feel like you can&amp;rsquo;t make music without that one perfect effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/instruments/</guid>
      <description>Instruments #   document.getElementById(&#34;instMenu&#34;).open = true;  What is an Instrument? #  Okay, yeah, that sounds like a stupid question, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to think about. Wikipedia has it defined like this:
 A musical instrument is a device created or adapted to make musical sounds. In principle, any object that produces sound can be considered a musical instrument—it is through purpose that the object becomes a musical instrument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix and Master</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/mix-and-master/</guid>
      <description>Mixing &amp;amp; Mastering #  Mixers #  mixer front ends, preamps, etc. Software mixing, etc.
Loundness Monitoring #  https://youlean.co/youlean-loudness-meter/
talk about loudness and spotify
Mixing #  eq, pan, quadraphonic+
Mastering #  Delay Always Means Phase Shift But Phase Shift Does Not Always Mean Delay (YouTube, Dan Worrall)
 Studio Monitors, Headphones, and Amps #  @Tirrelous on Twitter  Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of all the specs you might want to understad if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to buy headphones or studio monitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started #  Here&amp;rsquo;s the part where I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to explain how to read music or something boring like that. Really though, that&amp;rsquo;s not why you&amp;rsquo;re here. So let me start by giving you a bit of motivation. In a bit I&amp;rsquo;ll be going though how to use VCV Rack, a free (with paid addons, but those aren&amp;rsquo;t necessary) program for making music. But as we go though each bit is going to look so -basic- that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see the bigger picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Hardware</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Music Hardware #  While you could make all of your music with just computer, you’ll probably want some tools that make your life as a musician easier and let you explore ideas faster. Like I said back in the Audio Effects Chapter, in my experience, making music depends on a really quick brain to input device feedback loop. Being able to turn a physical knob and mash physical keys will often lead to better results if only because you’re able to try things both faster and by physically interacting with something that you may not have thought of otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Software</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/music-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/music-software/</guid>
      <description>Music Software #  Some tools on this page are not-free. As such, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to list prices as best I can. Music software usually goes on sale pretty significantly around Black Friday or Christmas, so when I can, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to list &amp;lsquo;street&amp;rsquo; prices. Regardless, I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with any of these projects in any way and I don&amp;rsquo;t make any money from these links- so don&amp;rsquo;t complain to me if the prices are wrong ╮(─▽─)╭ NOTE: this list is far from exhaustive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Resources, Music</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/other-resources-music/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources #  PatchStorage - A community of many active audio &amp;amp; visual programming enthusiasts who share and discuss their projects!
https://learningmusic.ableton.com/
https://codepen.io/teropa/full/bRqYVj/
Synchronized Swept-Sine: Theory, Application, and Implementation
AutoEq (Github) - Automatic headphone equalization from frequency responses
Cool People #  https://twitter.com/RichardDevine https://twitter.com/LOOKMUMNOCMPUTR
https://twitter.com/electricdahliia
https://t.me/thePatchBay - some shameless self promo, as this is my chat.  Neurotypique https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4oBI5piGMznFMZdtEC0FhA
Omri Cohen, a Rack Master&amp;rsquo;s YouTube Channel
Loopop RedMeansRecording AdamNeely AndrewHuang Rob Scallon Pipe Organ Video (YouTube), Theorbo Video (YouTube),</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequencing and MIDI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sequencing-and-midi/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing &amp;amp; Midi #  This chapter only goes over the basics of MIDI. Because MIDI is so important to music production I&amp;rsquo;ll dive much deeper into the details of MIDI in Chapter 6½ - MIDI in Detail Sequencing #  The definition of a sequence is pretty obvious, but don&amp;rsquo;t be misled by the name- a &amp;ldquo;sequence&amp;rdquo; is not always just a list of notes to be played one after the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound Sources</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/sound-sources/</guid>
      <description>Methods of making noise #  Samples #   a snippet of a .wav file open in audacity
 A sample is exactly as the name implies- a &amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo; of audio. Sample is a pretty broad term though, so usually some more terms are applied to help categorize them. The easiest to explain is what is usually meant by sample: a small audio file that contains one sound, like one drum hit or one piano key press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/theory/</guid>
      <description>First, this: #   Theory #  I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest. I can&amp;rsquo;t read music and I don&amp;rsquo;t know scales. Why, then, would I in any way think I&amp;rsquo;m qualified to write anything about music? Well, let me stop you right there, I&amp;rsquo;m not. I make music for fun. However, I like to think that people enjoy my music and I enjoy listening to it myself as I make it, and though my experience I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a little here and there to make sure things don&amp;rsquo;t sound awful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/music/video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/music/video/</guid>
      <description>Video &amp;amp; Streaming #  [TODO, basically the entire page]
Cameras #  If you&amp;rsquo;re like most people, the best camera you own is probably you&amp;rsquo;re phone camera.
Lighting #  I found hanging up some of those string light LED edison bulbs (like you&amp;rsquo;d see at a wedding) on the ceiling works well as an alternative to a softbox. It&amp;rsquo;s so many point lights that it adds up to a similar effect- albeit with the downside that you can&amp;rsquo;t move them around.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
