<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DESIGN on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DESIGN on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/3d/</guid>
      <description>3D Modeling, Sculpting, Painting, Shading, and Rendering # Art by TalonCreations This chapter will be using various programs, not all of which are free. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to recommend things that are open source if I can, otherwise I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep the cost down as much as possible. You definitely can do everything in this chapter for free, just be aware that without some of the paid tools it may be substantially harder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/analog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/analog/</guid>
      <description>Analog Art # What makes it &amp;lsquo;analog&amp;rsquo; # So, for OpGuides I&amp;rsquo;m going to refer to any non-digital art as analog. Traditionally, this art is called, well, traditional. I don&amp;rsquo;t like this term as it implies that there&amp;rsquo;s a right &amp;rsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; way to do things, and that&amp;rsquo;s a load of shit. So, whenever I say analog, don&amp;rsquo;t think about it too much. I just mean not using software and a computer, or, if a computer is used, it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary for the end product, like 3D printing and the like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/animation/</guid>
      <description>Animation # Why is &amp;ldquo;Choppy&amp;rdquo; Animation Better? (YouTube, Doodley)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/dacadc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/dacadc/</guid>
      <description>Analog Art to Digital Art # Scanning in your Analog Art # [TODO] Scanner DPI, etc.
Background Removal # Via vector art tools # Before doing this, you should really know what vector art is and how it differs from the raster art you&amp;rsquo;re probably used to. I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about this a bit in the previous chapter, Digital Art . This process requires combining the two, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit odd if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used vector art tools before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/digital/</guid>
      <description>Digital Art # Photo by cece kun The primary tool of the digital artist… The pen? # I want to give you a heads-up that making digital art without a pen tablet or pen display of some sort is pretty awful. You can get a cheap pen tablet - they&amp;rsquo;re basically like a mouse pad that you use a pen on - for ~$30. Or you can get a fancy pen display, where you draw directly on the screen, for about ~$300 (similar to the one in the picture above; however, one that large is probably much more expensive)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/gen/</guid>
      <description>Generative Art # This page is almost completely devoid of actual educational content. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to make the most complete list of generative art tools and libraries on the internet. Of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t actually make an exhaustive list and may be missing some of the newest tools and ideals, so please check out these other communities for more: r/proceduralgeneration
r/generative
r/PlotterArt
You may notice this page lacks AI generative art tools such as DALL·E 2, Midjourney, &amp;amp; Stable Diffusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/photo/</guid>
      <description>Photography # [TODO]
This Guy Flipped an Element in an Old Lens and Got ‘Magic’ Bokeh (PetaPixel)
https://hackaday.com/2022/10/12/enjoy-the-beauty-of-corona-discharge-with-this-kirlian-photography-setup/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/vbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/vbasics/</guid>
      <description>Vega&amp;rsquo;s Not-As-Basics of Art and Design # So, we have the basics that any art program will focus on - Lines, Shape, Form, Color, Space, Texture, Value - and these are the standard starting topics for good reason. They&amp;rsquo;re tried and tested to make people better at art, and they apply to any piece. This is great, but I think there are a few things left out of this for the purpose of making it broadly applicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/access/</guid>
      <description>Accessibility # Contrast. # ░▒▓ Accessability doesn&#39;t mean ugly. ▓▒░ ♚ High contrast colors can look good. ♛ 🙟Like this, nice nature-y theme.🙝 → Or this in-your-face purple ← 🗹🗹🗹 All of these boxes are high contrast. !!! And it&#39;s not like this is hard to do. &amp;nbsp&amp;nbsp Hell, it&#39;s easier! All of these palettes were made with https://randoma11y.com Though it&#39;s not hard to make your own. You just have to give a shit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/content/</guid>
      <description>Content is King # At the end of the day, you can make a cool looking fancy website, but you still have to have something to say, a story to tell, a tutorial, videos, something to play. something. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a print book, you can come back and edit it later. The important thing is to just make something.
It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be good at first, it just has to exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/cost/</guid>
      <description>Cost # So, a pretty big question you should ask right away is &amp;ldquo;How much does this cost?&amp;rdquo;, and you probably already know the answer.
It depends.
First thing you should worry about is the cost of hosting, but, uhh, what is hosting?
Hosting? # So, if you really want to, you can run a web server off of your home internet connection. This has a few problems though:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/garden/</guid>
      <description>Your Own Garden # So, I just said you&amp;rsquo;d need to learn a bunch to do this, so, why bother?
Platforms like Facebook, Tumblr, etc. - Social Media - don&amp;rsquo;t let you really customize the look of your page
… and they track you
… and they make the experience bad for those without accounts
… and they can limit your speech, ban your account, etc.
Site builders (Squarespace, Wix, WordPress, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/jack/</guid>
      <description>Jack of All Trades # You probably noticed the mildly ugly gradient heading this section, that was my warning to you that you&amp;rsquo;re about to walk into something that requires an interesting mixture of design and engineering skills. Making a good website requires a fair understanding of computers, some basic programming skills, and a willingness to dive into some technical topics. There&amp;rsquo;s a good reason most blogging now happens on Medium or Tumblr and that social media has boomed: The barrier to entry is significantly lower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/</guid>
      <description> HTML, (S)CSS, JS… WUT? # The rise of WASM # PHP needs to die. # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css/</guid>
      <description>CSS # Let me start by saying that Cascading Style Sheets - CSS - is not a hard language to write. The problem is not the language(1), but with how humans don&amp;rsquo;t think about style and art in a linear way and dealing with the complexities of different devices.
How we think about style # Look around this website, there are things that have been made stylistically cohesive - the color theme, the way I indicate that something is a local link by putting it in a button with a color that matches where it goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css_new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/css_new/</guid>
      <description>Draft: CSS Features That Aren&amp;rsquo;t Widely Supported But Should Be # element() - https://www.stefanjudis.com/a-firefox-only-minimap/
It&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely chrome will ever support these has() - should be supported soon
@scope - will probably exist eventually, still quite new
text-wrap: balance - seems to be polyfill-able, https://github.com/adobe/balance-text and will likely be supported eventually
This page will also check if the polyfill works. It seems to just fine. I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to condone using it yet though, as the polyfill sholudn&amp;rsquo;t be necessary for long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/html/</guid>
      <description>HTML # Alright, so HyperText Markup Language is the one thing on this list I suspect everyone reading this page has at least a smidgen of familiarity with, and it&amp;rsquo;s really very easy to work with, so let&amp;rsquo;s just dive in.
In general, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a bunch of HTML tags, tags are these point-bracketed enclosed words that mean something special to the browser, let&amp;rsquo;s actually make a HTML file right now to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/langs/js/</guid>
      <description>JS # Javascript is hard to talk about. Fundamentally, it&amp;rsquo;s a language for adding interactive content to the web.
Want to make a button that increments a counter?
Click me
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 // Set the initial value of the counter to 0 let counter = 0; // Get a reference to the button element const button = document.getElementById(&amp;#39;countButton&amp;#39;); // Add a click event listener to the button button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/resources/</guid>
      <description> Other Resources # Blog Posts # Only 90s Web Developers Remember This
https://www.learnui.design/tools/gradient-generator.html
Fonts # https://velvetyne.fr https://www.design-research.be/by-womxn/ https://usemodify.com </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/setup/</guid>
      <description>Setting up everything you need to make a website # [TODO] - include instructions for GitHub pages, a VPS, and self-hosted but assume a Hugo site for all three. There&amp;rsquo;s gotta be limits in the complexity somewhere, and I draw the line at setting up everything for decent JS web app dev / PHP shit, cloud/AWS, etc. though I still want to link to external resources for those things. Also, this probably needs to be written for win/mac/lin, which means there will have to be a ton of permutations of getting things setup depending on hosting solution and OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/static/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/static/</guid>
      <description> Static or Dynamic? # The &amp;lsquo;Weight&amp;rsquo; of your website # </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/thinkingweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/thinkingweb/</guid>
      <description> Thinking Web # [TODO] Content can be presented in novel ways. Text as a last resort
[TODO] Because of browser differences, screen size, Fonts, JS support, etc. you should check in other resolutions and browsers periodically
FAQs: why we don’t have them (gds.blog.gov.uk)
Every pricing page should have GIFs (Tony Dinh)
NoScript fallback
Some Beautiful Websites For Inspiration: # https://oxide.computer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/web/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/web/tools/</guid>
      <description>Web Development Tools # Code generation, libraries, etc.
HTML Helpers # HTML Table Generator</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/basics/</guid>
      <description>The Basics of Art and Design # When you&amp;rsquo;re first learning art, every art class will beat a few core ideas into your head:
Lines - The &amp;lsquo;structure&amp;rsquo; bits of the works, when you start making art, you&amp;rsquo;ll often start with the Line Art
Shape - Structures that form out of lines, might appear 3D. These might be mathy, like squares, or organic, like an eye
Form - Mostly applicable to 3D (or art interpreted as 3D) - Think of this as the shape you&amp;rsquo;d see if you could move around the object in real life</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, Other</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/design-other/</guid>
      <description>Other Resources # Wonderbook I very rarely promote resources you have to pay to access on OpGuides. I am not paid to say this. I bought my own copy on a whim. This book is pure gold. It&amp;rsquo;s about the written word, but will help any artist just as much. It is probably the most beautiful, lovingly hand crafted book I have ever read. It&amp;rsquo;s full of character and art and beauty and words of wisdom that will make you think about what it means to be an Artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspirational Artists</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ia/</guid>
      <description>Inspirational Artists # Unfortunately, this page is nearly entirely Twitter embeds. If you have something in your browser blocking these from working, this page won&amp;rsquo;t be all that useful. Sorry! Added a lot of minor improvements, like camera limits, subtle lighting, dust particles and more #gamedev #pixelart #screenshotsaturday pic.twitter.com/KmSYW3iHml
&amp;mdash; Luis Moreno Jimenez (@more8bit) September 2, 2017 Teenage Engineering&amp;#39;s OP-1 Synthesizer modules: pic.twitter.com/Jx5FEkiGK9
&amp;mdash; Shadow Drop - R&amp;amp;D (@ShadowDropDev) August 18, 2017 Some really cool pixel art gifs by Mark Ferrari https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UI</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/design/ui/</guid>
      <description>UI and UX # Principals of UI, A Thread (zensaiyuki@mastodon.social)
Gallery of Fantasy UI design from Movies and TV shows
Responsiveness # Source Power Users # User power, not power users: htop and its design philosophy
Typography # Practical Typography Textbook
Datalegeya Font
Almost Monospace Fonts (blakewatson.com)
Data Visualization # https://bids.github.io/colormap/
Website Design # Learn CSS by Google Developers
Butalist Web Design, by David Copeland
motherfuckingwebsite.com, bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com, thebestmotherfuckingwebsite.website
Scrollbar Blindness (Sven Kadak&amp;rsquo;s Blog)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
