<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technical on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/tags/technical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technical on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/tags/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ternary Logic</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/ternarylogic/</guid>
      <description>This paper was written for CSCE-430, Computer Architecture at University Of Nebraska - Lincoln in Spring of 2021.
This in-page view isn&amp;rsquo;t all that great, so feel free to download the pdf directly.
  #the-canvas { border: 1px solid black; direction: ltr; width: 100%; height: auto; } #paginator{ text-align: center; margin-bottom: 10px; }  Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page:  /     window.onload = function() { var url = &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Products I Wish Existed</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/productsiwishexisted/</guid>
      <description>Most of these things probably exist. For many, it&amp;rsquo;s just that they don&amp;rsquo;t exist at a practical price point.  Without further ado, In no particular order
  A not garbage, not phone based, IR camera that doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost a bajillion dollars
Yes. I know the FLIR and SEEK Thermal cameras are a thing, but both have their share of software problems or hardware incompatibilities. Most of all, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to hope that their app keeps working with my phone at risk of a $250 paper weight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time lapse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/time-lapse/</guid>
      <description>Super brief post about one of the more fun projects I setup recently: a lil&#39; time lapse script
#!/bin/bash CAM=$(v4l2-ctl --list-devices | grep C920 -A 1 | grep /dev | awk &#39;{$1=$1};1&#39;) #Uncomment the next line to verify it&#39;s using the correct device #echo $CAM ffmpeg -f video4linux2 -s 1920x1080 -i $CAM -ss 0:0:2 -frames 1 &amp;quot;/mnt/data/lapse/tl$(date +&amp;quot;%Y-%m-%d_%H-%M-%S&amp;quot;).jpg&amp;quot; I have multiple cameras on my system, but only wanted output from the better one, the C920.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Way We Interact With Computers Sucks.</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/thewayweinteractwithcomputerssucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/thewayweinteractwithcomputerssucks/</guid>
      <description>You are on a page that is a heavy work in progress. I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily stand by anything I&amp;rsquo;ve written here and this page should effectively be considered not yet published. I have decided to put it up while it is in development to encourage contributions What do you see when you sit down to work? My guess is a desk pressed against a wall, maybe a few shelves, one, maybe two monitors in front of you, and a keyboard and mouse dominating the work area of your desk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Down!</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/slowdown/</guid>
      <description>I use VCV Rack a lot. I normally use it on Windows as running VSTs in Linux is still a bit of a PITA and If I&amp;rsquo;m going to make music I want to have access to all of my tools. However, I still want to be able to use VCV on Linux for processing guitar when taking breaks from working on other things without having to reboot over to Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
