<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Way We Interact With Computers Sucks.</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/thewayweinteractwithcomputerssucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/thewayweinteractwithcomputerssucks/</guid>
      <description>You are on a page that is a heavy work in progress. I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily stand by anything I&amp;rsquo;ve written here and this page should effectively be considered not yet published. I have decided to put it up while it is in development to encourage contributions What do you see when you sit down to work? My guess is a desk pressed against a wall, maybe a few shelves, one, maybe two monitors in front of you, and a keyboard and mouse dominating the work area of your desk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xx80</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/xx80/</guid>
      <description>The year is 198x. #  I stare at my amber terminal. Hexadecimal fills my screen and my mind has become lost in the flow of 6502 assembly, as I hand optimize the code flow.
I&amp;rsquo;m interupted when I recieve a message from my friend, _Maverik, he&amp;rsquo;s excited about the ground breaking CGI in Tron.
 Nostalgia is a weird feeling. We can forget when things happened, and misttribute things to entirely different decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti Consumer</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/posts/anti-consumer/</guid>
      <description>As I walked to my car after class I could smell the ashes of a cigarette and hear the echos of a train scraping on its tracks. The cool foggy air held still beams of light. It looked like a scene from Blade runner, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but feel like the Android&amp;rsquo;s of it&amp;rsquo;s inspiration, lusting after something to make me feel alive.
The drive home was mentally taxing. The fog so dense that cars ahead seemed to be balls of light floating in the distance and keeping sight of the lines to stay in my lane took a constant effort.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
