<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unpublisheds on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unpublisheds on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://opguides.info/unpublished/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/ainotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/ainotes/</guid>
      <description>AI Tools # This page does is not a guide on how to use or setup any of the tools listed. Instead it&amp;rsquo;s a sort of reference for what&amp;rsquo;s possible. Large Language Models # Obviously, ChatGPT is well ahead of everyone else. Unfortunately, it keeps getting lobotomized. At the time of writing, it&amp;rsquo;s very insistent on outputting overly long, bulleted lists. For this reason alone, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth looking into options for self hosting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/board2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/board2023/</guid>
      <description>Last year, 2023, I started the year with a lot of goals. Some of them I accomplished, others not so much. One, from the start, was to motivate my creative mind a bit more. To that end, I made a board with some of my favorite ideas and creative guidance I could. A mix of motivation, advice, ideas, and inspiration. This is that board, with some modifications, digitized.&#xA;While the contents of this board come from a variety of sources, the biggest two influences were the Catastrotivity series on YouTube and Wonderbook: The Illustrated Guide to Creating Imaginative Fiction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/kids/</guid>
      <description> Ask HN: How can I make a “kid&amp;rsquo;s computer” today as good as an Apple II? The Bad Way To Teach Music to Babies </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</guid>
      <description>List of Ideas # Post about sympy in math chapter, espically with sum and product&#xA;increasingly online spaces that are custom-built are both spreading new ideas and preventing mono-cultures AND causing people to live in completely different realities and echo chambers&#xA;Fuck consumerism, fuck hoarding, fuck status symbols, fuck plastic wrapped single use internationally shiped good, fuck single use electronics, fuck shitty electronics that are instant-ewaste&#xA;Dangerous sounds - high voltage arc clicks, hard drive clicks, loud 60hz hum, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/mathtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/mathtest/</guid>
      <description>WEBGL &amp;amp; MATH TESTING # This is a testing ground for different options for rendering math, signals, etc. though the website. Given the music, DSP, and signals page I really care about sine waves and FFTs. It seems the best looking, lowest CPU sine I can get is using WEBGL (as immediately below) but writing the code for it is quite cumbersome. For math itself, https://github.com/airladon/figureone/ seems to be the best bet, and should dramatically help with the math chapters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/myworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/myworld/</guid>
      <description>Making a VRChat World # Step 1: What Do I Want? What Do I 𝕟𝕠𝕥 want. # concept art, etc.&#xA;Want:&#xA;ALIVE. Things should feel alive - wind, movement, player-reactivity LIVED IN. Each area should feel like there have been people there. Papers around, things under study, etc. SOUND. Ambient environment should have original sounds from my modular, kalimba, talkbox, guitars, etc. SYTLIZED. The world should be big so poly counts need to be low and/or have LOD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/p5test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/p5test/</guid>
      <description> P5 test # </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/reacttest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/reacttest/</guid>
      <description>React test # https://josem.co/how-to-render-a-react-component-in-hugo/ - I&amp;rsquo;d like to get https://mafs.dev/guides/get-started/installation working, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do so in a convenient way with Hugo. I&amp;rsquo;m really not a fan of adding react as a depedency and using that much JS anyway, but if this works it&amp;rsquo;d be worth it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/vr/</guid>
      <description>VR # FBT # https://www.crowdsupply.com/slimevr/slimevr-full-body-tracker&#xA;Vive trackers&#xA;April Tag&#xA;Kinect&#xA;Hand tracking &amp;amp; Haptics # Walking around # I created a Udon world to visualize infinite walking. The white lines are the limits of my play space.&#xA;The orange trail shows my movement in play space, and the blue trail shows my movement in world space.&#xA;(When I&amp;#39;m wireless I walk in circles, otherwise I walk in a ∞ shape) pic.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
