<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unpublisheds on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unpublisheds on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opguides.info/unpublished/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Meta-er-verse</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/metaverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/metaverse/</guid>
      <description>.me{background-color: #333!important; }Plots of land &amp;amp; Euclidean space #  One of the bigger points of the metaverse is the idea of owning a slice of digital property. This is a weird mix of the scarcity and value from real life property and the domain name (like myfancyname.com) market. It also makes no god damn sense in this context, and is really just artificially putting limitations into a system for the sake of making yet another crypto currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/interview/</guid>
      <description>bookToC = false
+++
An Interview with Annie of Sex Positive Gaming #  08/26/2021
Annie is the creator behind the Sex Positive Gaming YouTube channel where she primarily reviews adult games and ocassionaly streams SFW game play. Her channel is still relatively new, having only started in Feburary. In this time she has release over 120 videos ranging from game reviews to explainers of sexual topics all with the theme of &amp;ldquo;No Shaming, Just Gaming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/listofideasw/</guid>
      <description>List of Ideas #   Post about sympy in math chapter, espically with sum and product increasingly online spaces that are custom-built are both spreading new ideas and preventing mono-cultures AND causing people to live in completely different realities and echo chambers Fuck consumerism, fuck hoarding, fuck status symbols, fuck plastic wrapped single use internationally shiped good, fuck single use electronics, fuck shitty electronics that are instant-ewaste Dangerous sounds - high voltage arc clicks, hard drive clicks, loud 60hz hum, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/unpublished/tokipona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opguides.info/unpublished/tokipona/</guid>
      <description>Toki Pona? #  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
