<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>INTERVIEWS on Opinionated Guides</title>
    <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in INTERVIEWS on Opinionated Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://opguides.info/interviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/cadeyratio/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Cadey Ratio # 3/10/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Cadey. Your blog at christine.website/blog shows that you really have a wide range of interests. So, to get started, what are you passionate about and why? I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about making computers understandable. We work with these impossibly complex mechanical creations like they are nothing. They dominate our culture. With the onset of COVID, the internet has gone from an essential part of our lives to a vital method of communication.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/cendyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/cendyne/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Cendyne # 12/30/2022
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Cendyne. Your blog at Cendyne.dev has a mix of crytography and tips for leadership and planning. Other than those things, what are your interests? What are you passionate about and why? Within tech, security is an ever evolving source of new things to see. I listen to podcasts every other day that mention the new details on where Lockbit affiliates are targeting hospitals, patch this and that, an analysis of some NSO malware, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/kell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/kell/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Kell Bengal # 7/27/2021
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Kell. I know you work on robots, and teach others to do so as well, and are from the continent where everything wants to kill you, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know much else: How would you describe yourself? What are you passionate about and why? I would describe myself as an engineer, first and foremost.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/loial/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Loial Otter # 9/23/2018
Introduction:
I&amp;rsquo;m Matthew or LoialOtter, a crazy person up in western Canada who likes to make stuff. I work at Kron Technology as an engineer mainly in FPGA, electronics design and hardware design.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have any credentials except a certificate in baking and pastry arts. I&amp;rsquo;m self-taught mostly due to not being ever able to afford going to school. I suggest others do when the have the opportunity but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolutely required.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/paulshapera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/paulshapera/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Paul Shapera # 2/17/2023
Paul Shapera is a composer, musician, and storyteller known for his unique musical style, which incorporates elements of classical, rock, electronica, and more. His most well-known works include the New Albion and Post-Human series, which are both sprawling concept albums that blend together music and storytelling to create immersive musical worlds.
Shapera&amp;rsquo;s music is known for its intricate plotlines, complex characters, and exploration of themes such as transhumanism, love, loss, and redemption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/soatok/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Soatok Dreamseeker # 12/3/2020
Thank you for taking the time for this interview Soatok. Your blog at https://soatok.blog shows that you&amp;rsquo;re a furry crypto nerd, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to hear how you&amp;rsquo;d put it, so, to get started, can you describe yourself? Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m asked, I usually say something to the effect of, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a security engineer with a dhole fursona that sometimes writes about cryptography on my furry blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/spg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/spg/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Annie of Sex Positive Gaming # 01/07/2022
Annie is the creator behind the Sex Positive Gaming YouTube channel where she primarily reviews adult games and occasionally streams SFW game play. Her channel is still relatively new, having only started in February. In this time she has release over 120 videos ranging from game reviews to explainers of sexual topics all with the theme of &amp;ldquo;No Shaming, Just Gaming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/taxbadger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/taxbadger/</guid>
      <description>An Interview with Laguna of Tax Badger, LLC # 08/26/2021
﻿﻿
Laguna Crale is a bright pink Tax Badger that has made a name for himself with Tax Badger, LLC where he has made waves in the furry artist and NSFW content creator communities for being open and accepting of these professions. He&amp;rsquo;s freely given helpful pointers on his Twitter, @TaxBadgerLLC to help those questioning how to handle transitioning from making content as a hobby to making it a real, legal self-employment career.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/interviews/</guid>
      <description>Published Interviews: # Loial Otter Soatok Dreamseeker Cadey Ratio Kell Bengal Tax Badger Sex Positive Gaming Cendyne Wolfgun Paul Shapera If you would like to be interviewed # Well, first of all I&amp;rsquo;d like to know what makes you interesting - so shoot me a message or open an issue on GitHub, twitter, or where ever you can find me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wolfgun</title>
      <link>https://opguides.info/interviews/wolfgun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://opguides.info/interviews/wolfgun/</guid>
      <description>An Interview With Wolfgun # 2/17/2023
Play Wolfgun is a space obsessed master of synthesizers with 50 albums out on Bandcamp. He primarily makes his music in Renoise, a Digital Audio Workstation (DAW) which combines an old-school tracker workflow - think the equivalent of combining spreadsheets and music software with the sequence of notes and effects entered vertically, like the example on the left - with modern production capabilities.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
